<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384362</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554110</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 08:00:34</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor’s tariff burden in U.S. higher than U.S., Japanese peers]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 08:00:34</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.8d24be1df12f456489f4df9771a0b808_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Hyundai Motor Group faced steeper tariff costs than its U.S. and Japanese rivals in the second quarter of 2025 when trade tensions led to a 25 percent tariff on various automotive goods.
With a unified 15 percent tariff rate for South Korea, Japan, and the European Union taking effect from the third quarter, automakers’ localization strategies are expected to play a key role in shaping future performance.
According to a Maeil Business Newspaper analysis of second-quarter earnings of automakers from Korea, Japan, the U.S., and Europe competing in the U.S. market on Sunday, Hyundai Motor Group’s per-vehicle tariff burden was higher than that of the U.S. and Japanese companies but lower than European companies.
During its earnings call on July 24 and 25, Hyundai Motor Group reported that tariff-related losses in operating profit amounted to 1.6 trillion won ($1.15 billion). With about 470,000 vehicles sold in the U.S. in the second quarter, this means each car incurred around 3.41 million won in tariffs.
Volkswagen Group, based in Germany, also reported tariff costs of 1.61 trillion won. However, with total sales of only 113,600 units, the per-vehicle cost came to 14.16 million won.
On the other hand, American automakers with numerous local factories incurred much lower tariff costs per vehicle.
Ford Motor Co. reported 1.12 trillion won in total tariff expenses, General Motors posted 1.54 trillion won, and Stellantis N.V. reported 480 billion won.
Among Japanese automakers, Nissan Motor Corp.’s tariffs reduced its operating profit by 640 billion won, or 2.89 million won per vehicle.
Industry analysts say the key factor is local production.
Hyundai Motor Group’s U.S. localization rate remains around 40 percent, significantly lower than Ford and GM.
Hyundai Motor Group operates three plants in the U.S., including Hyundai Motor Manufacturing Alabama (HMMA), Kia Manufacturing Georgia (KMMG), and Hyundai Motor Group Metaplant America.
To cushion the tariff impact, most automakers are ramping up U.S. production rather than raising prices.
General Motors, for instance, plans to shift Blazer and Equinox production from Mexico—where tariffs now reach 25 percent—to its plants in Tennessee and Michigan.
Hyundai Motor Group is also pursuing a long-term expansion strategy.
If HMGMA scales up as planned, the automaker’s U.S. capacity could hit 1.2 million units annually—on par with Honda Motor Co. and trailing only Toyota Motor Corp.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Group faced steeper tariff costs than its U.S. and Japanese rivals in the second quarter of 2025 when trade tensions led to a 25 percent tariff on various automotive goods. With a unifie]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.8d24be1df12f456489f4df9771a0b808_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384362]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
