<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11386191</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>559807</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-06 08:27:41</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Kakao Pay posts profit in Q2]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-06 08:27:41</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.b8161190b9be41448d34df723cd65175_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
South Korea’s Kakao Pay Corp., which operates a mobile payment system, continued to post profits in the second quarter of 2025 thanks to increased payment volume and resulting revenue growth.
Kakao Pay announced on Tuesday that its consolidated operating profit for the second quarter totaled 9.3 billion won ($6.7 million), up more than twice from 4.4 billion won in the previous quarter. Revenue for the April to June period totaled 238.3 billion won, up 28.5 percent year-on-year, while net profit stood at 14.1 billion won.
The company said that it remained in the black for two straight quarters following a return to profitability in the first quarter. Total transaction volume for the second quarter stood at 45 trillion won, a 10 percent increase year-on-year, while transaction volume contributing to revenue rose 9 percent to 13.2 trillion won.
Transaction volumes grew evenly across services such as payments, financial products, and remittances. Payment transaction volume rose by 35 percent offline and 20 percent overseas compared to the same period in 2024. Remittance volume also increased by 10 percent, with Kakao Pay Money monthly active users reaching 20 million.
Financial service revenue surged 82 percent year-on-year to 100.3 billion won, accounting for over 40 percent of total revenue. In the platform business, advertising revenue grew 66 percent year-on-year, driven by data-based customer analysis, the company said.
Its subsidiary Kakao Pay Securities Corp. recorded an operating profit of 5.2 billion won during the cited period, maintaining profitability for the third consecutive quarter. Its stock balance more than doubled, up 131 percent from a year earlier.
Kakao Pay plans to further expand its offline payment ecosystem through services such as “QR Table Order” and the business solution “Boss Plus.”
“We are currently pursuing three key strategies: expanding the value chain, commercializing data, and developing new business areas using our traffic,” Kakao Pay CEO Shin Won-keun said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s Kakao Pay Corp., which operates a mobile payment system, continued to post profits in the second quarter of 2025 thanks to increased payment volume and resulting revenue growth. Kakao Pa]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.b8161190b9be41448d34df723cd65175_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11386191]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
