<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11396896</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>590342</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-19 11:13:59</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[S&SYS soars over 80% in Kosdaq debut]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-19 11:13:59</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-20 09:20:20</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250819.d0f6c00a82784edcbc3be12035909284_P1.png' alt=' (KRX)'>
Shipbuilding equipment solution provider S&SYS saw its shares surge more than 80 percent on their Kosdaq debut Tuesday. The stock price was almost twice that of the initial public offering (IPO).
The shares were trading at 55,200 won ($40.60) as of 9:32 a.m., up 84 percent from its IPO price of 30,000 won. The stock climbed as high as 56,800 won during the session, nearing the “double” mark at nearly 1.9 times the IPO price.
Founded in June 2017 after being spun off from Samsung Heavy Industries’ electric and electronics division, S&SYS develops and manufactures key ship and offshore plant components, including switchboards, ballast water treatment systems, and navigation control solutions.
The company drew strong investor interest during its book-building process for institutional investors, recording a competition rate of 739.2 to 1. The IPO price was set at the top of the desired range, 30,000 won. Retail investors also showed strong demand, with a competition rate of 1,472 to 1 and total deposits of 10.49 trillion won.
Meanwhile, major Korean game developers saw their shares gain in early trading on Tuesday ahead of the opening ceremony for Gamescom 2025, the world’s largest video game trade fair.
Krafton shares were up 3.19 percent at 323,000 won by 9:23 a.m., while those for Pearl Abyss gained 3.56 percent, Netmarble 1.7 percent, NCSoft 1.21 percent, and Kakao Games 0.42 percent. These companies plan to showcase new games at Gamescom, which kicks off on Wednesday in Cologne, Germany.
Separately, stocks related to Korean content production rose Tuesday morning following reports that Chinese authorities could ease restrictions on imported TV dramas.
Studio Dragon shares were trading 6.51 percent higher at 48,250 won as of 9:09 a.m. CJ ENM (+2.79%), Samhwa Networks (+2.28%), ASTORY (+1.34%), KidariStudio (+1.22%), and ContentreeJoongAng (+0.39%) also saw their stock advanced.
The rally was fueled by expectations that China may relax regulations on overseas drama content. Bloomberg reported that China’s National Radio and Television Administration held a meeting on August 15th, 2025, to discuss measures to support drama production and innovation, citing local platform IMTW.com.
S&SYS shares closed at 45,000 won, Krafton shares closed at 328,000 won, and Studio Dragon shares closed at 49,350 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Shipbuilding equipment solution provider S&SYS saw its shares surge more than 80 percent on their Kosdaq debut Tuesday. The stock price was almost twice that of the initial public offering (IPO). The ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250819.d0f6c00a82784edcbc3be12035909284_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (KRX)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11396896]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
