<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11396857</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>590195</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-19 10:42:50</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor, Kia accelerate U.S. localization to cushion tariff blow]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-19 10:42:50</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.16c53d071eaa42d191c7481861d9a80c_P1.png' alt=' (Hyundai Motor Group)'>
Hyundai Motor Co. and Kia Corp. are ramping up local production and procurement in the United States to blunt the impact of U.S. tariffs, with both automakers reporting sharp increases in output and sourcing during the first six months of 2025.
Hyundai Motor produced 217,214 vehicles at its U.S. plants in the January–June period, up 22 percent from 178,100 a year earlier, according to reports released on Monday.
The share of U.S. production in the automaker’s global output rose to 11 percent from 9.2 percent a year ago.
The increase came as Hyundai Motor Group Metaplant America (HMGMA), which started operations earlier this year, rapidly ramped up capacity. The facility’s utilization rate climbed from 54.7 percent in the first quarter to 72.6 percent in the first half.
HMGMA produced 31,598 IONIQ5 vehicles from January to July, surpassing the company’s domestic output of 24,887 units over the same period.
Kia lifted production at its only U.S. plant in Georgia to 180,500 units in the first half, up from 177,500 a year earlier.
Both automakers are also stepping up local sourcing. Hyundai Motor’s U.S. plants procured 8.38 trillion won ($6.04 billion) in parts in the first half, a 39 percent jump from a year earlier. Kia’s procurement rose 19 percent to 6.57 trillion won.
The push is expected to intensify as Japan and the European Union face a 15 percent tariff on their automotive exports, further pressuring Korean automakers to increase localization.
Hyundai Motor told investors in July it has set up a task force to shift more of its supply chain to the U.S. and is reviewing quotes from local suppliers for more than 200 auto parts.
Kia is also adopting a “produce where you sell” strategy.
“We will establish the principle that all vehicles produced at the Georgia plant will be prioritized for the U.S. market,” the automaker said in July.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Co. and Kia Corp. are ramping up local production and procurement in the United States to blunt the impact of U.S. tariffs, with both automakers reporting sharp increases in output and s]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.16c53d071eaa42d191c7481861d9a80c_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hyundai Motor Group)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11396857]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
