<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387400</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>563264</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 10:37:38</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor, GM to jointly develop five vehicles for release in 2028]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 10:37:38</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.5b3acf045c9a4a73868dcf4310d7f64e_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korea’s Hyundai Motor Co. will jointly develop five vehicles with U.S. automaker General Motors Co. (GM) under a strategic partnership announced on Thursday.
The two companies plan to jointly develop a total of five next-generation vehicles, including four models for the Latin American market – a mid-size pickup, compact pickup, compact passenger car, and compact SUV, all of which will support both internal combustion and hybrid powertrain – and an electric commercial van for the North American market.
The joint development plan stems from the memorandum of understanding signed by Hyundai Motor and GM in September 2024 to pursue comprehensive cooperation.
The companies initially planned to announce detailed collaboration plans earlier this year. However, the announcement was delayed due to extended discussions aimed at enabling the faster and more efficient development of a broader range of vehicle types.
The two companies expect to produce and sell over 800,000 units annually once mass production of the jointly developed vehicles begins.
During the joint development process, GM will take the lead in developing the mid-size truck platform, while Hyundai Motor will lead the development of platforms for compact vehicles and the electric commercial van.
While financial terms and conditions are not disclosed, the companies expect the partnership to cut platform costs by more than half, citing anticipated savings from shared development, supply chain efficiencies, and logistics streamlining.
“Hyundai’s strategic collaboration with GM will help us continue to deliver value and choice to our customers across multiple vehicle segments and markets,” said Jose Munoz, president and CEO of Hyundai Motor. “Our combined scale in North and South America helps us to more efficiently provide our customers more of what they want – beautifully designed, high-quality, safety focused vehicles with technology they appreciate.”
Design and engineering for the Central and South American models are already underway, while production of the electric vans in the U.S. could begin as early as 2028.
Both companies said the partnership could be expanded to additional vehicle programs and powertrain systems, and they are exploring collaborations in other global regions, leveraging their respective competitive advantages.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s Hyundai Motor Co. will jointly develop five vehicles with U.S. automaker General Motors Co. (GM) under a strategic partnership announced on Thursday. The two companies plan to jointly de]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.5b3acf045c9a4a73868dcf4310d7f64e_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387400]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
