<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11386211</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>559844</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-06 08:43:27</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Japanese brands rebound in Korea amid easing anti sentiment]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-06 08:43:27</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.540801f7a7184019a0555e572eab09cf_P1.png' alt=' (Canmake)'>
Once sidelined by the anti-Japan boycott movement, Japanese brands are making a comeback in South Korea as public sentiment softens and travel to Japan surges.
Japanese beauty brand Canmake, once pulled from health and beauty stores in Korea due to the 2019 “No Japan” campaign, is set to return to Olive Young on August 21. Known for its eye shadows and blush products, Canmake is often on Korean travelers’ must-buy lists when visiting Japan.
In the fashion sector, Uniqlo—which took a heavy hit during the boycott and even closed its flagship Myeong-dong store in 2021—is now rebounding. The brand’s revenue in Korea fell to 582.4 billion won ($420.0 million) in 2021 but climbed back to 1.06 trillion won last year. Operating profit also increased by 5.3 percent to 148.1 billion won.
Japanese discount retailer Don Quijote also drew large crowds last month when it opened a pop-up store at The Hyundai Seoul. Shoppers formed early morning lines, highlighting renewed enthusiasm for Japanese brands.
Industry insiders attribute the rebound to the weakening of anti-Japan sentiment and the resurgence of travel to Japan, boosted in part by the weak yen. According to data from the Ministry of Land, Infrastructure and Transport and Korea Airports Corporation, more than 13.43 million passengers flew to Japan during the first half of the year.
New Japanese entrants are also tapping into this momentum. Beauty brand Shiro, which gained traction on social media, opened its first Korean store in Seoul’s Seongsu district in April. The store reportedly earned 100 million won in sales within two days of launch.
“Anti-Japan sentiment is fading, and the rising number of travelers to Japan is creating demand for local experiences, which is translating into consumption,” one industry official said. “These shifts are encouraging more Japanese brands to re-enter the Korean market.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Once sidelined by the anti-Japan boycott movement, Japanese brands are making a comeback in South Korea as public sentiment softens and travel to Japan surges. Japanese beauty brand Canmake, once pull]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.540801f7a7184019a0555e572eab09cf_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Canmake)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11386211]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
