<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11392848</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>578578</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-13 14:55:38</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KT, Viettel partner up for Vietnam’s national AI language model]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-13 14:55:38</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.4f54e94b93734707b546723c2555c183_P1.png' alt=' (KT)'>
KT said on Tuesday that it signed a “Partnership 2.0” agreement with Vietnam’s state-owned ICT company Viettel Group to help develop the country’s national artificial intelligence (AI) strategy and accelerate AI transformation (AX) across industries.
The deal, which was signed ahead of the Korea-Vietnam Business Forum that was attended by some 500 participants, builds on an initial agreement reached in May 2025. Since then, executives from both companies have traveled between the two countries multiple times to draw up a cooperation roadmap for concrete joint projects and Vietnam’s AI strategy.
Under the agreement, KT and Viettel will collaborate on building a national AI strategy, developing industry-specific AX platforms, expanding AI projects in Southeast Asia through global partnerships, strengthening AI-based cybersecurity, and fostering local talent via targeted investments as well as training programs.
A centerpiece of the collaboration will be the joint development of a national general-purpose AI language model trained on Vietnam’s unique language, culture, and administrative systems. The model is expected to be applied across education, government administration, and public services, bolstering the nation’s digital sovereignty and AI adoption.
The two companies will also build vertical AX platforms optimized for key sectors such as healthcare, defense, and media, offering customized AI solutions for specific industry needs. Viettel will join KT’s broad global partnership network to cooperate with major global tech firms, share information, and leverage KT’s AI innovation experience in expanding AX adoption to neighboring markets.
To nurture AI talent, the partners plan to establish a Global AX Innovation Center (G-AXC) dedicated to research, development, and testing of the national AI language model. They will also create hands-on training programs and certification systems to help Vietnamese citizens apply AI in daily life.
KT and Viettel also aim to develop AI solutions to combat phishing crimes such as voice phishing and deepfakes, enabling real-time detection and blocking. Shared databases of phishing cases and technical know-how will support the security of the AX ecosystem.
KT said it will work closely with Viettel to build a global AX delivery model, enabling rapid and flexible responses to changing market conditions while pursuing comprehensive export strategies that extend to AI mass adoption.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[KT said on Tuesday that it signed a “Partnership 2.0” agreement with Vietnam’s state-owned ICT company Viettel Group to help develop the country’s national artificial intelligence (AI) strategy and ac]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.4f54e94b93734707b546723c2555c183_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (KT)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11392848]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
