<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11391246</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>573418</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-12 07:35:22</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean beauty stocks tumble despite strong Q2 earnings]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-12 07:35:22</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.02d2e32b7f554a05951d08f71d84b389_P1.png' alt=' (MK DB)'>
South Korea’s leading beauty companies saw their stocks plunge Monday despite robust results for the second quarter, as earnings fell short of investors’ lofty expectations.
The sell-off rippled across the cosmetics sector, hitting both major brands and smaller contract manufacturers.
On the main Kospi market, d‘Alba Global shares closed down 19.87 percent at 191,900 won ($139) after posting revenue of 128.4 billion won and operating profit of 29.2 billion won for the April to June 2025 period.
While revenue jumped 74 percent and operating profit surged 66 percent from a year earlier, both came in below market forecasts, triggering a wave of selling.
According to financial data provider FnGuide, domestic brokerage houses had projected d‘Alba’s operating profit to reach 36.2 billion won for the quarter, about 19 percent higher than the actual result.
Investor concerns were compounded by an upcoming lock-up expiration. On August 22, 1.96 million shares, or 16.2 percent of the company’s outstanding stock, will become eligible for sale on August 22nd.
Analysts said that the disappointing numbers were partly due to one-off expenses, including an additional 5 billion won in value-added tax following a regular audit and the deferral of some business-to-business sales in Russia to the third quarter.
“The earnings look weaker only because expectations were so high,” said Kwon Woo-jung, an analyst at Kyobo Securities. “Overseas operations remain strong, and given the brand’s high recognition in Europe compared to other indie brands, it’s still an attractive investment.”
Other beauty stocks also took a hit.
On the Kosdaq market, SILICON 2 shares fell 18.44 percent to 43,800 won on Monday after posting revenue of 265.3 billion won, up 46 percent year-on-year, and operating profit of 52.2 billion won, up 34 percent.
Both figures still came in below analyst estimates by 2 percent and 9 percent, respectively.
Kolmar Korea dropped 9.34 percent to 80,600 won on Monday after announcing revenue of 730.8 billion won and operating profit of 73.5 billion won, up 11 percent and 2 percent year-on-year but falling short of market projections by 1 percent and 11 percent.
The sell-off extended to smaller contract manufacturers such as Cosmax (-9.21 percent) and Cosmecca Korea (-7.68 percent), as well as major brands like APR (-1.74 percent) and Amorepacific (-1.71 percent).
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s leading beauty companies saw their stocks plunge Monday despite robust results for the second quarter, as earnings fell short of investors’ lofty expectations. The sell-off rippled acros]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.02d2e32b7f554a05951d08f71d84b389_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11391246]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
