<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11398056</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593640</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 11:20:05</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea to host APEC’s first-ever ministerial on culture in Gyeongju]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 11:20:05</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-20 11:27:51</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400104</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[South Korea will host the first-ever high-level dialogue in the cultural and creative industries within the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC).
The ministerial meeting will take place in Gyeongju, North Gyeongsang Province, for three days starting August 26th, 2025, under the theme “Cultural and Creative Industries: New Horizons for Prosperity.” Participants will exchange views on innovation, digitalization, and future cooperation in the cultural and creative sector.
APEC is the world’s largest regional economic cooperation body that accounts for 61 percent of global gross domestic product (GDP), and ministerial meetings have previously focused on areas including trade, energy, education, and food security. However, the upcoming agenda will include the cultural and creative industries, with Korea, the 2025 APEC chair, leading these discussions for the first time.
<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.f9dc39d341124ba5bc1ea22c823abf9a_P1.png' alt=' (BIGHIT MUSIC)'>
This meeting is special in several respects. Firstly, it is the first time APEC, a body that has traditionally centered on economic affairs, has recognized the cultural and creative industries as a major economic sector.
Today, culture is no longer merely a source of leisure and enjoyment; it has become a new growth engine for the digital economy. A report from the Hyundai Research Institute on the economic impact of K-pop superstar BTS assessed the group as equivalent to dozens of mid-sized companies, generating an average annual production-inducing effect of 4.14 trillion won ($2.97 billion) as of 2018.
Similarly, the popularity of Netflix Inc.’s animation “KPop Demon Hunters” boosted first half 2025 sales at the National Museum Foundation of Korea’s MU:DS brand to 16.3 billion won - up 56 percent year-on-year - and showing the sector’s wide-ranging ripple effects.
Secondly, many APEC member economies - including Vietnam, Indonesia, and Chile - have expressed interest in learning from and cooperating with the Korean cultural industry’s success.
During a recent state visit to Korea by Vietnam’s top leader, the Vietnamese government proposed a cultural industry roundtable involving business leaders in gaming, animation, and entertainment, set a goal of raising its cultural industry’s GDP share to 7 percent by 2030, and expressed a wish to expand cooperation with Korea.
In Indonesia, a 2024 overseas Korean Wave survey showed a remarkable 86.3 percent favorability rating for K-content in the country. In response, we opened a Content Talent Training Center in Jakarta as part of an official development assistance (ODA) project in the field of cultural content.
Finally, this high-level cultural industry dialogue is unique in being the only ministerial meeting held in Gyeongju, the ancient capital and the host city of the upcoming APEC Summit.
Of the more than 10 ministerial meetings scheduled during the summit, only the cultural industry dialogue will take place there.
That is why the first place I visited immediately after taking office was Gyeongju.
Hosting an APEC high-level dialogue in a city rich with UNESCO World Heritage sites such as Bulguksa Temple and Seokguram Grotto carries deep symbolic meaning as it links the value of traditional culture with 21st-century economic and digital discourse.
We hope this dialogue will serve as an opportunity to reaffirm the value of cultural and creative industries among APEC members and strengthen substantive cooperation within the organization.
Beyond simply exchanging opinions, our aim is for APEC members to share their cultural experiences and creativity, alongside charting new paths of cooperation that enable sustainable growth via culture.
The ultimate goal is to build a foundation for the continued growth of cultural and creative industries within the APEC region while enhancing mutual trust and exchange among economies. This high-level dialogue will be the opening chapter for harmony, where APEC members share a vision for the future of the cultural industry and work together to expand its power.
As a pre-event to the APEC Summit, the dialogue at the end of August 2025 will welcome cultural industry leaders from across the region to Gyeongju and serve as a solid foothold for a successful APEC Summit, highlighting the charm of Korea’s traditional culture, innovative content, and tourism.
<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.6bbfa0f3ea7048ac9fce133b98326862_P1.png' alt=' Minister of Culture, Sports and Tourism Chae Hwi-young'>
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea will host the first-ever high-level dialogue in the cultural and creative industries within the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC). The ministerial meeting will take place in Gyeongj]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400104</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[k-wave]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400104</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[k-wave]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.f9dc39d341124ba5bc1ea22c823abf9a_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (BIGHIT MUSIC)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.6bbfa0f3ea7048ac9fce133b98326862_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Minister of Culture, Sports and Tourism Chae Hwi-young]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11398056]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
