<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393607</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>580961</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 11:26:43</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Kia to convert Hwaseong plant for EVs amid European boom]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 11:26:43</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.9c3f9d199f8c46febad4c05a2285b585_P1.png' alt=' Kia EV6'>
Kia Corp. is moving to convert part of its Hwaseong plant, which currently produces internal combustion engine vehicles, into an electric vehicle (EV)–only facility.
The move is seen as part of the automaker’s strategy to expand its production base following the global success of its EV series, particularly in Europe.
According to the automaker‘s labor union on Wednesday, Kia’s labor and management have agreed to convert one of the three factories at Autoland Hwaseong, Gyeonggi Province, into a dedicated EV facility.
Once completed, Kia will have three EV-only plants in Korea.
The company has already transformed its Gwangmyeong Plant 2 into the Gwangmyeong EVO Plant, which produces the EV3 and EV4 compact EV models, and established the Hwaseong EVO Plant for purpose-built electric vehicles (PBVs), recently starting production of the PV5.
The conversion target is expected to be either Plant 2 or Plant 3 at Autoland Hwaseong, both of which currently produce Kia’s flagship EV6 model.
An industry official said, however, that the exact timing of the conversion has yet to be decided.
Kia’s decision to add another EV-only plant comes as global sales of its affordable EV series have been rising rapidly.
Kia sold about 29,000 EVs globally in 2021, the year it began full-scale EV series launches. Sales rose to 131,000 units in 2023 before falling to around 120,000 in 2024 amid a temporary slowdown in EV demand.
With overseas sales of the EV3 beginning this year, however, EV series sales are estimated to have reached 110,000 units in the first half alone.
With a significant share of EV6 production shifting from Hwaseong to Kia’s U.S. plant in Georgia, the need to reorganize Hwaseong’s production lines has grown.
Kia’s investor relations data showed that the Georgia plant, which began EV6 production this year, sold about 7,400 units in the first half, while EV6 exports from Hwaseong fell from about 33,000 units a year earlier to 9,800 units.
As a result, Hwaseong Plant 2 operated with empty slots in its production containers in the second half of last year due to a shortage of EV orders.
To address the production shortfall, the labor and management at Hwaseong have reportedly agreed to develop a new EV model, codenamed CB, and allocate it exclusively to the new EV plant to boost output.
Buoyed by the EV3’s strong sales in Europe, Kia plans to launch the EV4 electric sedan in the region in the second half of this year. The EV3, which entered the European market earlier this year, sold 30,000 units in the first half, and industry forecasts suggest it could surpass its annual sales target of 60,000 units.
Kia has also reportedly filed trademark applications with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office for both the EV2 and EV1. When developed, the EV1 is expected to be a small hatchback-sized EV.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Kia Corp. is moving to convert part of its Hwaseong plant, which currently produces internal combustion engine vehicles, into an electric vehicle (EV)–only facility. The move is seen as part of the au]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.9c3f9d199f8c46febad4c05a2285b585_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Kia EV6]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393607]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
