<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11400485</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>600885</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-22 14:53:07</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Samsung Securities, KAIST to support deep-tech startups]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-22 14:53:07</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.86494cf8fdfc4c45a1fc59ba81bb130f_P1.png' alt=' (Samsung Securities)'>
Samsung Securities Co. said Friday it has signed a memorandum of understanding with the Global Commercialization Center (GCC) of the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) to foster deep-tech startups and support their global expansion.
Under the agreement, Samsung Securities will provide tailored financial solutions for companies working with GCC, ranging from funding and capital management to initial public offerings. The brokerage plans to act as a strategic partner to help these firms explore new business opportunities.
Established in 2015 under KAIST, GCC is a research center specializing in global technology commercialization aimed at promoting overseas expansion of technologies and business models developed by universities, institutes, and companies.
The center has expanded its collaboration to convergence technologies and digital transformation and more recently has focused on robotics, mobility, biotechnology, semiconductors, batteries, and artificial intelligence.
It also serves as a government-designated lead institution for robot technology commercialization and supports 77 robotics startups.
“We will leverage our extensive corporate service expertise to help KAIST GCC’s innovative startups grow into global unicorns,” said a company official.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Samsung Securities Co. said Friday it has signed a memorandum of understanding with the Global Commercialization Center (GCC) of the Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST) to foste]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.86494cf8fdfc4c45a1fc59ba81bb130f_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Samsung Securities)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11400485]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
