<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384399</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554224</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 09:01:23</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Conglomerate chiefs ramp up Japan outreach to forge supply chain alliances]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 09:01:23</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.92d8d471a0284698a26174a2a2f218de_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korea’s major conglomerate leaders are accelerating efforts to strengthen industrial partnerships with Japan, shifting from traditional procurement relationships to strategic alliances that involve co-designing technologies and jointly building global supply chains.
A group of Samsung Group’s top executives visited Hitachi’s Central Research Laboratory located in Kokubunji, Tokyo, in June 2025, marking an unusual gathering. The delegation toured the facility and explored potential areas of collaboration with the Japanese industrial giant.
Hitachi, once Japan’s largest-ever corporate deficit holder with a record 787.3 billion yen loss in fiscal 2009, is now recognized for its dramatic “V-shaped” recovery through aggressive restructuring. Samsung Electronics Chairman Jay Y. Lee has frequently met with Hitachi’s leadership during visits to Japan and, this time, shared insights with group executives using Hitachi as a case study.
Samsung DX Division’s acting head Roh Tae-moon and senior executives visited the Osaka-Kansai Expo site in Japan earlier. The visit aimed to inspire future-oriented imagination among Samsung’s device leadership.
Executives from Korea’s major conglomerates are increasingly heading to Japan in search of key technology partners to shape the future of semiconductors, display equipment, precision parts, battery materials, and mobility. Observers note that these business trips are more than procurement - they represent strategic alliances jointly designing technologies and supply chains.
Lee reportedly visited Japan 12 times in 2024 and has continued to visit the country frequently in 2025. He is also known to attend Japan’s annual April “spring greetings” events, where local firms typically introduce new management.
In a notable move, Samsung opened a new private office for Lee inside the headquarters of Mitsui & Co. in Tokyo’s Otemachi district, which houses staff assisting Lee’s business in Japan. This is viewed as a symbolic rebirth of the “second Samsung Japan” following the dissolution of the original Samsung Japan in 2012 as part of restructuring efforts.
Samsung has long viewed Japan as a vital technology partner, and Lee is continuing that tradition. In 2023, he personally presided over the 30th anniversary ceremony of LJF (Lee Kunhee Japanese Friends), a private business exchange platform between Samsung and Japanese component firms founded by his father, the late Lee Kun-hee, in 1993. The next LJF event is expected to be held in Korea around October 2025.
Samsung’s ties with Japan are expanding further. Its Future Business Planning division is studying the transformation strategies of Japanese companies like Hitachi and Sony. Lee has also been strengthening the company’s local network through connections with Japanese firms such as Hitachi and SoftBank.
SK Group Chairman Chey Tae-won is also ramping up engagement in Japan, particularly in semiconductors, energy, and artificial intelligence. He reportedly travels to Japan every few months. In May, SK reassigned former SK innovation CEO Park Sang-kyu to oversee its Japan operations and lead SK Japan, a new unit formed through the consolidation of SK’s previous Japan investment entity launched in 2021. Chey also maintains a personal office at SK’s Hibiya branch in Tokyo.
Cooperation is also intensifying between the heads of Hyundai Motor Group and Toyota, the world’s top and third-largest automakers respectively. Hyundai Motor Group Chairman Chung Eui-sun and Toyota Chairman Akio Toyoda are working closely to build a hydrogen ecosystem, holding rare direct meetings across both countries. The two groups are leaders in the global hydrogen vehicle market and are jointly exploring infrastructure and technology standards. Their partnership is expected to grow into a broader “hydrogen alliance” encompassing both policy and regulatory efforts.
LG Group, under Chairman Koo Kwang-mo, is focusing on partnerships with Japanese automakers in the automotive parts segment. LG has established an R&D center in Yokohama for hydrogen and vehicle components and has held back-to-back “Tech Day” events at the Toyota and Honda headquarters to promote its products and strengthen the supply chain. This marks a shift from simple procurement to co-designing technology in a joint development model.
Experts view these shifts as signs of a structural transformation in Korea-Japan industrial relations.
Lee Chang-min, a professor at Hankuk University of Foreign Studies, noted, “These top-down business partnerships could open breakthroughs for both Korean and Japanese firms amid prolonged economic stagnation.” He emphasized that while bilateral economic cooperation offers opportunities, such as supply chain resilience, governance shifts, and industrial transitions, structural challenges such as geopolitical risks and overlapping industries must also be considered.
The evolving partnerships represent a move away from the traditional vertical buyer-supplier model toward a horizontal collaboration in value chain planning and design. More than a simple transactional relationship, the structure now involves shared ownership of technology direction and innovation. Observers say this shift indicates a growing trend of “industrial diplomacy,” led by conglomerate heads rather than formal government channels.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s major conglomerate leaders are accelerating efforts to strengthen industrial partnerships with Japan, shifting from traditional procurement relationships to strategic alliances that invo]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.92d8d471a0284698a26174a2a2f218de_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384399]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
