<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11400186</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>600118</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-22 11:17:11</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Bill Gates meets Korean startup developing eco-friendly toilet]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-22 11:17:11</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.0c3b470225d14eee98a2f60567b11d55_P1.png' alt=' (With Masters)'>
Microsoft founder and co-chair of the Gates Foundation Bill Gates met with Korean sanitation and environmental SME With Masters during his visit to Seoul. The company is developing prototypes for an “eco-friendly toilet” project spearheaded by the Gates Foundation to improve public health in developing countries.
According to With Masters, Gates met with CEO Kim Jong-ho on Thursday afternoon in Yeouido, Seoul. Kim said in a phone interview with Maeil Business Newspaper that he briefed Gates on the latest model of the Household Reinvented Toilet (HRT), which the firm has been co-developing with the Gates Foundation.
Kim, a former Samsung Electronics executive who led global quality innovation and set manufacturing, is known for developing a 100 percent wastewater recycling technology at Samsung, which the Gates Foundation later applied to sanitation projects in poor countries.
The HRT currently under development integrates sedimentation, oxygen aeration, microbial decomposition, filtration, and sludge drying functions, effectively operating as a self-contained sewage treatment system. Designed for homes and facilities without sewer infrastructure, the unit treats and recycles wastewater on site. Solid waste is separated via sedimentation and then dried at 750 degrees Celsius into non-toxic granules, while liquid waste undergoes microbial breakdown and filtration to produce water clean enough for reuse.
The Gates Foundation has invested $400 million to fight waterborne diseases in developing countries through toilet and sanitation projects, with HRT commercialization as a key focus, since 2011.
Dr. Doulaye Kone, director of the Gates Foundation’s Water, Sanitation & Hygiene Program, praised With Masters in a March 2025 interview with Maeil Business Newspaper, noting that “what takes other countries three to four years, they achieved in just nine months.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Microsoft founder and co-chair of the Gates Foundation Bill Gates met with Korean sanitation and environmental SME With Masters during his visit to Seoul. The company is developing prototypes for an “]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.0c3b470225d14eee98a2f60567b11d55_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (With Masters)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11400186]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
