<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393871</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>581926</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 15:14:23</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Gov’t to cut $84 bn in spending to fund policy goals]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 15:14:23</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.2a75185f497e438cb3805747d1e99668_P1.png' alt=' (Office of the President)'>
The Presidential Committee on Policy Planning announced on Wednesday that an additional 210 trillion won ($152.1 billion) in central government funding will be required over the next five years to implement national policy projects.
The committee plans to first secure 116 trillion won through spending cuts. The Ministry of Economy and Finance noted in a meeting on Wednesday that it will carry out 27 trillion won worth of spending restructuring starting with next year’s budget proposal.
“Next year’s budget proposal includes the largest-ever reduction of 27 trillion won – 25 trillion won in discretionary spending and 2 trillion won in mandatory spending,” said Yoo Byung-seo, director general for budget at the Ministry of Economy and Finance. “Of the 17,000-plus projects subjet to restructuring, we cut budgets in 4,400 projects – about a quarter of the total. The number of projects to be abolished will increase from around 200 in 2025 to about 1,300 next year.”
Savings will come from a wide range of areas.
For example, 47.9 billion won from events, publicity, and administrative costs, and 70 billion won from support for so-called zombie firms, defined as long-standing, unprofitable firms with a history of restructuring without repaying loans.
Official development assistance (ODA) costs will be cut by more than 1 trillion won, and some local education finance grants will be reduced in line with the declining school-age population. But deeper cuts in education were avoided, reflecting likely pushback from the sector.
The remaining 94 trillion won will be raised through higher tax revenues.
Plans include revising tax exemptions, improving AI-driven tax collection, and boosting returns from public institutions such as the Bank of Korea.
The government’s tax reform plan—raising corporate capital gains taxes—is expected to generate 35.6 trillion won, leaving a gap that may require further tax measures, including changes to real estate tax rules.
Any shortfall will be covered by issuing deficit bonds, which would push up the national debt ratio.
Already at 46 percent of GDP at the end of last year, the ratio is expected to hit 49 percent by the end of 2025 and could climb to 50.5 percent by 2028.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The Presidential Committee on Policy Planning announced on Wednesday that an additional 210 trillion won ($152.1 billion) in central government funding will be required over the next five years to imp]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.2a75185f497e438cb3805747d1e99668_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Office of the President)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393871]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
