<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405927</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>617772</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 11:01:21</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Minister of SMEs and Startups pledges stronger safety net]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 11:01:21</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.309c6856c3a344daa94c40d2385d0b0c_P1.png' alt=' Han Seong-sook, Minister of SMEs and Startups'>
South Korea’s Minister of SMEs and Startups Han Seong-sook emphasized the creation of a safety net for small businesses as her key task during her term. Marking her first month in office, Han highlighted three priorities at a press briefing held at the Korea Federation of SMEs in Yeouido on Thursday: establishing a livelihood safety net for small merchants, promoting the digital transformation of small manufacturers, and expanding venture investment. “We need stronger policy support to help small businesses and SMEs recover after closures,” she said.
Han has launched a “policy field tour” program since taking office, visiting 13 sites within a month with the goal of conducting 10 tours each across the SME, venture, and small business sectors. She said that while many policy areas require long-term improvements, urgent issues were addressed in as little as a week based on feedback from the field.
Han, who previously worked at Naver before her appointment, underscored the need for policy delivery focused on beneficiaries. She stressed that policies must reach 8.04 million SMEs, 4.83 million startups and venture firms, 7.66 million small merchants, and 50 million citizens. “Even when I tried using the website myself, it was difficult to find information quickly and I often had to close multiple pop-ups,” she said, pledging to improve communication channels and simplify processes. Plans include eliminating unnecessary paperwork and expanding inter-agency linkages to enable automatic submission of required documents.
She also announced that the ministry will adopt data-driven administration to improve internal operations.
Han gave a favorable assessment on the government’s consumer coupon program, noting that the consumer sentiment index hit its highest level in eight years and that even businesses with over 3 billion won ($2.17 million) in annual sales saw revenue growth. On the contentious “Yellow Envelope Act,” she said the government would use the six-month grace period to carefully craft detailed measures and that her ministry would actively present opinions to safeguard SMEs.
On the same day, the ministry unveiled a major plan to boost startups and ventures via artificial intelligence (AI). It announced seven leading “physical AI” projects, including AI-powered robots, automobiles, and ships, and the formation of task forces to support 15 leading AI initiatives in total.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s Minister of SMEs and Startups Han Seong-sook emphasized the creation of a safety net for small businesses as her key task during her term. Marking her first month in office, Han highligh]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.309c6856c3a344daa94c40d2385d0b0c_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Han Seong-sook, Minister of SMEs and Startups]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405927]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
