<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11391396</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>573911</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-12 10:21:33</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Celltrion expands autoimmune, cancer drug contracts in Italy]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-12 10:21:33</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.ab0b257c2ac54081bb3c6f35360fd8e5_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Celltrion said on Tuesday that it secured additional supply contracts in Italy for its autoimmune disease treatments and cancer drugs.
Celltrion’s Italian subsidiary won new bids to supply Steqeyma, a biosimilar version of ustekinumab sold under the brand Stelara, in the Veneto, Trentino-Alto Adige, and Sardinia regions. The win comes on top of earlier contracts awarded by four regional governments earlier in 2025. The company will supply the product to the newly contracted regions through May 2026.
Its autoimmune drug Remsima (infliximab) also continues to expand its footprint, holding a combined 66 percent market share in Italy in the first quarter of 2025. Celltrion recently won the Umbria region’s infliximab tender and renewed its contract for the subcutaneous formulation Remsima SC in the Puglia region. In Sardinia, where Celltrion previously had no presence, a new tender for the subcutaneous version has allowed the company to achieve coverage across all 20 Italian regional governments.
In oncology, Celltrion’s Truxima (rituximab) and Vegzelma (bevacizumab) were awarded contracts in Lazio and Umbria respectively, and have been supplied since the first half of 2025.
“Since introducing a direct sales system in Italy in 2020, we have built close ties with local tender agencies and key medical professionals, supported by a flexible pricing strategy, stable supply, and competitive products,” the company said. “With the addition of high-margin biosimilars to our portfolio in the second half of this year, we expect performance growth to accelerate.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Celltrion said on Tuesday that it secured additional supply contracts in Italy for its autoimmune disease treatments and cancer drugs. Celltrion’s Italian subsidiary won new bids to supply Steqeyma, a]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.ab0b257c2ac54081bb3c6f35360fd8e5_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11391396]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
