<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11403775</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>611176</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-27 09:50:58</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean businesses pledge $150 bn investment in U.S.]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-27 09:50:58</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.35686112058342b39637b3a2d1bfa8e5_P1.png' alt=' President Lee Jae-myung shakes hands with Hanjin Group Chairman Cho Won-tae at a Korea-U.S. business roundtable in Washington, U.S., August 25. (Yonhap)'>
South Korean companies have signed 11 memorandums of understanding (MOUs) in the United States in line with the latest Korea-U.S. summit in Washington, D.C. The agreements cover cooperation in automobiles, aviation, shipbuilding, nuclear power, liquefied natural gas (LNG), defense, and critical minerals.
The companies committed a total of $150 billion in fresh investment in the U.S.
Hyundai Motor Group announced on Monday (local time) that it plans to make an additional $5 billion investment in the U.S. over the next four years, focusing on the robotics sector.
This brings Hyundai‘s total investment in the U.S. to $26 billion.
Through this new investment, Hyundai plans to build a robot plant with an annual capacity of 30,000 units and manufacture products such as Spot, a quadruped robot, Atlas, a bipedal humanoid robot, and Stretch, a logistics automation robot - all developed by its subsidiary Boston Dynamics Inc.
The conglomerate also plans to expand cooperation with leading U.S. companies in future technologies such as autonomous driving, artificial intelligence (AI), and software-defined vehicles (SDVs), while accelerating the commercialization efforts of its U.S. affiliates including Boston Dynamics and Motional Inc.
“Through this investment, we will respond to U.S. government policies while expanding our business opportunities across diverse fields to strengthen our competitiveness in mobility and other future businesses,” the conglomerate said.
Korean Air Lines Co. signed an MOU with Boeing Co. Monday to purchase 103 next-generation aircraft worth $36.2 billion.
It also entered into a $690 million contract with GE Aerospace for 19 spare engines and a $13 billion engine maintenance service agreement, bringing its total investment to about 70 trillion won ($50.18 billion).
Combined with the 45 trillion won worth of aircraft and engine purchase contracts announced during the Minister of Trade, Industry and Energy‘s visit to the U.S. in March 2025, Korean Air’s total U.S. investment is expected to reach 115 trillion won.
HD Hyundai Co. and Samsung Heavy Industries Co. will take part in the Make American Shipbuilding Great Again (MASGA) Project that symbolizes Korea-U.S. cooperation in shipbuilding.
Doosan Enerbility Co. also agreed to collaborate with the U.S. on developing small modular reactors (SMRs).
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean companies have signed 11 memorandums of understanding (MOUs) in the United States in line with the latest Korea-U.S. summit in Washington, D.C. The agreements cover cooperation in automob]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.35686112058342b39637b3a2d1bfa8e5_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ President Lee Jae-myung shakes hands with Hanjin Group Chairman Cho Won-tae at a Korea-U.S. business roundtable in Washington, U.S., August 25. (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11403775]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
