<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397901</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593044</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 09:55:34</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Business groups go all-out to block Korea’s labor law revision]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 09:55:34</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.09e88368b44f47268af16d764971e4d8_P1.png' alt=' (Lee Chung-woo)'>
The business community in South Korea has come together in full force to make a final appeal to block an amendment to the country’s Trade Union and Labor Relations Adjustment Act – also known as the Yellow Envelope Bill.
The Korea Enterprises Federation (KEF), the Korea Chamber of Commerce and Industry (KCCI), the Federation of Korean Industries (FKI), the Korea International Trade Association (KITA), the Korea Federation of SMEs (KBIZ), and the Federation of Middle Market Enterprises of Korea (FOMEK) held a rally in front of the National Assembly’s main building on Tuesday, along with regional employers’ associations and industry-specific groups.
More than 200 business representatives gathered to announce a joint statement calling for revisions to the amendment.
They said that the National Assembly is ignoring the concerns of the business community and pushing ahead with the bill by reflecting only labor’s demands, warning that “the bill threatens our economy.”
The ruling Democratic Party of Korea plans to handle the Yellow Envelope Bill at the National Assembly plenary session starting on Thursday.
The amendment’s core provision is to expand the definition of employers to include primary contractors in cases involving subcontracted workers.
The business community points out that the bill defines the concept of “employer” in an excessively broad and ambiguous way.
They argue it unjustifiably overturns the long-standing principle that only parties with an explicit or implicit employment contract are considered employers.
In particular, they note that allowing collective bargaining agreements between subcontractor unions and primary companies would effectively nullify civil law provisions governing subcontract agreements.
With multiple provisions of the Trade Union Act already allowing for criminal penalties against employers, they warn that the vague definition of employers would severely constrain business activities and risk treating corporate leaders as potential criminals.
Concerns also persist that if the amendment passes, the industrial ecosystem between primary and subcontractor firms could collapse.
Industries with high reliance on subcontracting - such as shipbuilding, construction, and steel - would be forced to constantly respond to bargaining demands from subcontractor unions.
The business community also opposes expanding the scope of labor disputes to include business management decisions.
They argue that investment decisions, relocations, and restructuring are fundamental matters of managerial rights guaranteed by the Constitution and cannot be subjects of labor-management negotiations.
Business groups also maintain that even if the Yellow Envelope Bill passes the plenary session, there must be at least a one-year grace period before it takes effect.
Small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) also went all out to block the bill.
On the same day, the KBIZ held a meeting with Minister of Employment and Labor Kim Young-hoon and SME owners at its headquarters in Seoul to discuss the amendment.
“We expect major industries such as automobiles and shipbuilding to suffer widespread damage, which is causing great concern among us,” KBIZ Chairman Kim Ki-moon said. “We need to take at least a year to gather opinions from labor and management.”
However, Minister Kim maintained his principled stance that the bill is designed “to promote negotiations between primary and subcontractor firms, reduce internal corporate disparities, and foster shared growth.”
A recent public opinion survey conducted by the KCCI lends support to the business community’s position.
According to the poll of more than 1,200 people, about 76 percent of respondents said that labor-management conflicts in the workplace will “intensify further if the bill passes.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The business community in South Korea has come together in full force to make a final appeal to block an amendment to the country’s Trade Union and Labor Relations Adjustment Act – also known as the Y]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.09e88368b44f47268af16d764971e4d8_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Lee Chung-woo)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397901]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
