<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390191</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570396</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 08:33:26</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea’s Gimpo-Jeju route busiest in the world in 2024: IATA]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 08:33:26</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.defa97f652164c7c955a950fdacde5f7_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
The busiest air route in the world last year was found to be a domestic route in South Korea, with more than 13 million passengers traveling between Gimpo and Jeju.
The finding was revealed in the 2024 World Air Transport Statistics Report released by the International Air Transport Association (IATA) on Saturday (local time).
According to the report, nine of the world’s ten busiest routes, including Gimpo–Jeju, were located in the Asia-Pacific region.
In North America, the busiest route was between New York and Los Angeles in the United States, with 2.2 million passengers last year.
In Europe, it was between Barcelona and Palma de Mallorca in Spain, with 2 million passengers, while in Latin America, the busiest route was between Bogotá and Medellín in Colombia, with 3.8 million passengers.
The report also showed that the largest aviation market in the world was the United States, with 876 million passengers in 2023, up 5.2 percent from the previous year.
The majority of these passengers traveled on domestic routes.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The busiest air route in the world last year was found to be a domestic route in South Korea, with more than 13 million passengers traveling between Gimpo and Jeju. The finding was revealed in the 202]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.defa97f652164c7c955a950fdacde5f7_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390191]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
