<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11382846</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>549375</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-01 11:05:47</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[July exports up 5.9% led by semiconductors, autos, ships]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-01 11:05:47</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/01/news-p.v1.20250801.3126c9a533ec44ffa3e09c0563d62645_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
South Korea’s exports rose nearly 6 percent in July 2025 from a year earlier despite uncertainties stemming from the U.S. government’s planned reciprocal tariffs. This marked the second consecutive month of export growth, which was driven by semiconductors, automobiles, and ships.
The Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy on Friday said on Friday that July exports totaled $60.82 billion, up 5.9 percent from a year ago and continuing the recovery after a brief contraction in May. Semiconductor exports hit a record high for the month of July while automobile exports remained resilient, offsetting weakness in the U.S. market with strong demand from the European Union and other regions.
Among Korea’s 15 key export items, semiconductors, automobiles, and ships led the growth. Semiconductor exports surged 31.6 percent on-year to $14.71 billion, the highest ever for any July. The increase was driven by rising fixed prices for memory chips and robust demand for high-value products such as high-bandwidth memory (HBM) and DDR5.
Automobile exports rose 8.8 percent on-year to $5.83 billion. Although shipments to the United States were dampened by the proposed 25 percent tariff, strong performance in markets such as the European Union and Latin America helped maintain the upward trend for the second month in a row.
Ship exports jumped 107.6 percent to $2.24 billion, supported by increased deliveries of high-value vessels such as LNG carriers. This marked the fifth consecutive month of growth in the shipbuilding sector.
By contrast, exports of petroleum products and petrochemicals declined due to continued low oil prices and global oversupply. Petroleum product exports fell 6.3 percent to $4.21 billion while petrochemical exports dropped 10.1 percent to $3.75 billion.
Exports to the United States increased 1.4 percent to $10.33 billion despite weaker demand for steel and auto parts. Gains in semiconductors, wireless communication devices, cosmetics, and electrical machinery supported the overall growth.
Exports to China, Korea’s largest trading partner, fell 3 percent to $11.05 billion due to weaker demand for petrochemicals and wireless devices. Meanwhile, exports to ASEAN rose 10.1 percent to $10.91 billion thanks to strong semiconductor sales, which more than doubled from a year earlier.
Imports in July totaled $54.21 billion, up 0.7 percent from the previous year. As a result, Korea recorded a trade surplus of $6.61 billion for the month.
With the exception of January, Korea has maintained a monthly trade surplus since June 2023.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s exports rose nearly 6 percent in July 2025 from a year earlier despite uncertainties stemming from the U.S. government’s planned reciprocal tariffs. This marked the second consecutive mo]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/01/news-p.v1.20250801.3126c9a533ec44ffa3e09c0563d62645_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11382846]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
