<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385251</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>556914</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 08:00:52</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Shinsegae chief steps up online push with shopping, travel platforms]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 08:00:52</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.4d40c1aa96534462a8afc6e3182ef528_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
Chung Yoo-kyung, chairwoman of South Korean retailer Shinsegae Co., has started to significantly ramp up efforts in the online business space.
The newly launched shopping platform, Beyond Shinsegae, and the premium travel service, Via Shinsegae, are rapidly emerging as the two flagships of the company’s new digital ventures.
Shinsegae Department Store announced on Monday that it will officially unveil Beyond Shinsegae and Via Shinsegae – two new travel and shopping channels – through a redesigned version of its official app on Tuesday.
This marks the transformation of the largely inactive Shinsegae Department Store app into an active platform for shopping and travel.
Beyond Shinsegae allows users to search and purchase popular items from more than 220 brands sold at Shinsegae stores.
Previously, users could only browse items in the Shinsegae app. Purchases had to be made through the SSG.com app’s Shinsegae store section.
Historically focused on offline retail, the company now aims to expand its revenue online through this new channel.
Although Shinsegae Department Store recorded total sales of 12.5 trillion won ($9.03 billion) in 2022, this declined to 11.13 trillion won in 2023 and 11.5 trillion won in 2024, showing signs of growth stagnation.
Attention is now on whether the online channel can reinvigorate the department store’s performance.
The other pillar of Chung’s online strategy is travel.
Since travel and tourism can lead directly to shopping, particularly at duty-free stores and department stores, this aligns well with Shinsegae’s core business.
Ahead of the official launch of Via Shinsegae, the company offered pilot packages such as a South America trip and a tour to watch the prestigious golf tournament, The Open.
The South America trip, for instance, sold out in just three days.
Newly released travel packages also offer distinctive experiences.
In October, Travel with a Celebrity will feature architect Yoo Hyun-joon, who will guide participants through Rome and Tivoli while explaining iconic buildings.
Other offerings include tickets to see piano prodigy Lim Yun-chan perform at Carnegie Hall in New York, visits to six New York museums, and a Disney Cruise setting sail from Singapore – the first in Asia.
Industry observers see the move as not only a digital expansion but also a potential sign of growing independence between Shinsegae‘s leadership factions.
“SSG.com previously dominated online operations under Chairman Chung Yong-jin,” said an industry insider. “The department store‘s app was underutilized. But with Chung Yoo-kyung now steering her own course, Shinsegae is actively integrating commerce and travel into its app, signaling a strategic split.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Chung Yoo-kyung, chairwoman of South Korean retailer Shinsegae Co., has started to significantly ramp up efforts in the online business space. The newly launched shopping platform, Beyond Shinsegae, a]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.4d40c1aa96534462a8afc6e3182ef528_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385251]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
