<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11392845</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>578581</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-13 14:55:35</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean shipbuilders rally ahead of U.S. envoy’s Ulsan shipyard visit]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-13 14:55:35</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-14 09:25:50</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250813.aa55397191254885bb397bb349ad74cd_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
South Korean shipbuilding stocks rose on Wednesday morning ahead of a visit by the U.S. envoy to HD Hyundai Co.’s shipyard in Ulsan.
As of 9:17 a.m., HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. traded at 471,000 won ($340.42), up 3.4 percent from the previous session.
Hanwha Ocean Co. gained 3.08 percent, HD Hyundai Mipo Co. rose 2.42 percent, and Samsung Heavy Industries Co. advanced 1.81 percent. HD Korea Shipbuilding & Offshore Engineering Co. climbed 7.72 percent.
Foreign Minister Cho Hyun is scheduled to tour the Ulsan shipyard later in the day with acting U.S. Ambassador to Korea Joseph Yun to review bilateral cooperation in shipbuilding.
Lawmakers from the National Assembly’s Foreign Affairs and Unification Committee will also join the visit, which is viewed as part of the $150 billion Korea–U.S. shipbuilding cooperation project known as Make American Shipbuilding Great Again (MASGA).
Meanwhile, shares of Daewoong Co. jumped more than 10 percent in early trading after news that its in-house-developed microneedle patch delivered strong results in an initial pilot study.
At 9:08 a.m., the stock was at 24,300 won, up 12.76 percent from the previous day.
Daewoong Pharmaceutical Co. and Daewoong Therapeutics Inc. said their self-developed microneedle patch containing semaglutide achieved more than 80 percent bioavailability compared with injectable formulations in a human pilot study. The result marks the world’s first human application data for a semaglutide microneedle patch.
The companies noted that existing microneedle patches with the same ingredient typically achieve about 30 percent bioavailability relative to injections.
The new patch reached concentration levels about 160 times higher than semaglutide oral tablets, they said.
HD Hyundai Heavy Industries closed at 467,000 won. Hanwha Ocean ended at 106,300 won, HD Hyundai Mipo at 189,900 won, Samsung Heavy Industries at 19,030 won, and HD Korea Shipbuilding & Offshore Engineering at 379,500 won.
Daewoong shares finished at 22,500 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean shipbuilding stocks rose on Wednesday morning ahead of a visit by the U.S. envoy to HD Hyundai Co.’s shipyard in Ulsan. As of 9:17 a.m., HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. traded at 471,000 ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250813.aa55397191254885bb397bb349ad74cd_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11392845]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
