<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11382839</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>549380</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-01 11:05:29</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea and the U.S. must use summit to rebuild trust]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-01 11:05:29</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400105</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/01/news-p.v1.20250801.b80c03e3b339460ab627897bd1d22fbd_P1.png' alt=' Foreign Minister Cho Hyun shakes hands with U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio at the State Department in Washington, D.C., on July 31. (Yonhap)'>
The upcoming summit between South Korean President Lee Jae-myung and U.S. President Donald Trump, set to take place in August 2025, comes at a critical juncture. While the recently concluded tariff agreement is a notable milestone, the summit must serve a larger purpose: to reaffirm mutual trust and respect within the Korea-U.S. alliance.
Despite Korea’s pledge of a $350 billion investment in the United States and acceptance of a 15 percent reciprocal tariff, concerns linger in Seoul that the alliance remains imbalanced. Allies should not be left wondering whether massive economic commitments are met with adequate recognition and reciprocity.
Trump’s announcement on Truth Social that revealed Lee’s White House visit within the next two weeks confirms that the summit will be used to publicize the investment deal. But beyond economic figures, key details - such as tariff enforcement mechanisms and long-term trade stability - still require attention. The summit should eliminate any room for future disputes.
Yet the real test lies in matters that go beyond trade. Defense cost-sharing is likely to surface again, as it did during Trump’s first term when he demanded a fivefold increase in Seoul’s contribution to United States Forces Korea. Such proposals risk undermining recent progress and reigniting tensions, and Lee must navigate this carefully: defending national interest while keeping the alliance strong.
Another challenge will be reshaping perceptions. Lee has a lingering pro-China image, fueled in part by a past “xiexie” comment, with such ambiguity raising doubts in Washington in the current geopolitical climate. It is essential for the administration to make clear where Seoul stands - firmly aligned with its democratic allies.
This also requires action from Korea’s ruling Democratic Party. The opposition has pushed for revisions to the National Security Act seeking to broaden espionage definitions from “enemy states” to “foreign countries” - a move prompted by the growing threat of Chinese espionage - for months. While the Democratic Party has been hesitant, the time has come for responsibility. With both the defense minister and intelligence chief backing the change, the party should act quickly to support legislation ahead of the summit.
The Korea-U.S. relationship is rooted in more than military treaties or trade agreements. It is an alliance built on shared values, trust, and sacrifice. The upcoming summit must not only showcase economic cooperation - it must reaffirm that this alliance remains ironclad.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The upcoming summit between South Korean President Lee Jae-myung and U.S. President Donald Trump, set to take place in August 2025, comes at a critical juncture. While the recently concluded tariff ag]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400105</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400105</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/01/news-p.v1.20250801.b80c03e3b339460ab627897bd1d22fbd_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Foreign Minister Cho Hyun shakes hands with U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio at the State Department in Washington, D.C., on July 31. (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11382839]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
