<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11404923</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>615061</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-28 12:39:28</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Cho’s over $50 bn bet set to reshape Korean aviation industry]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-28 12:39:28</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.335f221439c9472b8d23526a513688a4_P1.png' alt=' (Korean Air)'>
Korean Air, led by Cho Won-tae, chairman of Hanjin Group, has unveiled a long-term investment plan focused on large-scale aircraft acquisitions and next-generation aviation infrastructure, marking the biggest corporate investment in Korean history by a single airline. The bold move is expected to reshape the domestic aviation landscape.
According to industry sources Wednesday, Korean Air signed a deal with Boeing to purchase 103 next-generation fuel-efficient aircraft worth $36.2 billion (50 trillion won). The order consists of 20 Boeing 777-9s, 25 Boeing 787-10s, 50 Boeing 737-10s, and eight 777-8F freighters, with deliveries scheduled through the late 2030s.
The airline also concluded contracts with GE Aerospace for $690 million in spare engines and $13 billion in engine maintenance services.
The investment, totaling about 70 trillion won, comes as a proactive measure following Korean Air’s merger with Asiana Airlines, aiming to address aircraft delivery delays after the pandemic, prepare for growing air travel demand, and strengthen Korea-U.S. aviation ties.
Industry observers say the 70 trillion won plan signals more than just aircraft purchases, representing a large-scale fleet modernization. Korean Air plans to streamline its fleet to five high-efficiency models—Boeing 777s, 787s, 737s, and Airbus A350s and A321neos—enabling stable supply chain management, improved operational efficiency, reduced fuel consumption and carbon emissions, and enhanced customer service.
The expansion of freighter aircraft is also notable. During the pandemic, Korean Air’s cargo operations gained competitiveness, and rising demand for high-value cargo such as semiconductors, batteries, and auto parts continues alongside e-commerce growth.
However, some industry watchers caution that the massive investment could intensify competitive pressure on low-cost carriers (LCCs) and smaller airlines. With domestic travel demand only growing slowly amid high inflation and interest rates, Korean Air’s aggressive fleet expansion and global route growth may deepen market polarization.
Financial concerns also linger. As of the first half of this year, Korean Air’s debt stood at 20.02 trillion won. Although the investment will be executed over 15 years, a further rise in debt could increase interest expenses and strain cash flow.
“This large-scale investment is a forward-looking strategy to secure future competitiveness and expand global networks,” an industry official said. “While it provides positive momentum for Korea’s aviation industry, it may burden LCCs and other competitors. Financial stability and performance integration will be key to watch during the execution process,” the official added.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Korean Air, led by Cho Won-tae, chairman of Hanjin Group, has unveiled a long-term investment plan focused on large-scale aircraft acquisitions and next-generation aviation infrastructure, marking the]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.335f221439c9472b8d23526a513688a4_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Korean Air)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11404923]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
