<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388465</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566186</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:46:17</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Kakao denies rumors of selling Kakao Entertainment]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:46:17</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.6dadc15fd3f3419baea5dea2110a8978_P1.jpg' alt=' (Kakao)'>
Kakao on Thursday officially denied rumors that it was planning to sell its subsidiary Kakao Entertainment, marking the first time the parent company has publicly addressed the speculation since it surfaced in April.
In a regulatory filing responding to market rumors and media reports, Kakao said it had “discussed changes in Kakao Entertainment’s shareholder structure, but has decided to halt the review.”
The company added, “We will continue to explore a variety of strategic options to boost Kakao Entertainment’s global performance and strengthen its business competitiveness.”
Kakao Entertainment is one of Kakao’s core subsidiaries, operating across multiple entertainment sectors, including web novel and webtoon content as well as music and video businesses.
Rumors of a sale first emerged in April, when reports claimed Kakao had sent letters to shareholders — including Anchor Equity Partners and Saudi Arabia’s Public Investment Fund (PIF) — expressing its intention to sell its management stake.
Kakao Entertainment’s management has repeatedly denied the reports, saying they were based on a misunderstanding of discussions over potential changes in financial investors and shareholding.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Kakao on Thursday officially denied rumors that it was planning to sell its subsidiary Kakao Entertainment, marking the first time the parent company has publicly addressed the speculation since it su]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.6dadc15fd3f3419baea5dea2110a8978_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Kakao)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388465]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
