<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11406116</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>618419</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 14:38:40</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Ceragem Completes Master V Collection Lineup with Launch of ‘Master V11’]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 14:38:40</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.ed3ad2f568e44ac883ba87aa801440fc_P1.jpg' alt=' Ceragem’s ‘Master V11’ is equipped with the Dual Position System. (Ceragem)'>
Ceragem announced on the 11th that it has launched the ‘Master V11’, first unveiled at CES 2024, thereby completing its Master V Collection lineup.
Inspired by the experience of first-class travel, the ‘Master V11’ offers the sense of private and comfortable space similar to an aircraft’s premium cabin. It delivers three-dimensional rotational massage covering from neck to pelvis and, with the Dual Position System, provides precise spinal management regardless of posture or environment — whether sitting or lying down. Like personalized services in first-class, it delivers deep and comprehensive relaxation effects with fine-tuned traction for each spinal region, offering meticulous spinal care.
Ceragem has previously offered diverse spinal healthcare solutions tailored to each individual’s spinal condition, lifestyle, and space environment — from the Master V4, focused on basic spine relaxation; the Master V7, featuring intensive massage for the neck and shoulders plus leg massage; to the Master V9, with three-dimensional rotational massage from neck to pelvis and reclining feature. With the launch of ‘Master V11’, a product that combines refined design and top performance, Ceragem has completed the Master V Collection lineup and broadened consumers’ choices.
<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.96f0768cd3b14502be8b3bfa7f2511f6_P1.jpg' alt=' (Ceragem)'>
The ‘Master V11’ scans not only the neck, back, waist, and pelvis but also spinal length and curvature to provide personalized massage. It offers full-spine traction mode, along with specific modes tailored to enhance conditions such as lumbar disc herniation, lumbar stenosis, cervical disc herniation, and cervical stenosis. In particular, the Spinning (motion) Spine-Tech (SST) CeraCore Engine applies massage modules that move horizontally, vertically, and rotate 360° along the entire spinal line, ensuring seamless massage from neck to pelvis.
The full-body heating function and directly heated spinal massage rollers deliver deep warmth to relax stiff, tight muscles. In addition, the abdominal LED ultrasonic vibration applicator (a certified medical device for muscle pain relief and menstrual pain alleviation) and the air-cell leg massager (a certified medical device for improving blood circulation and preventing deep vein thrombosis) enable comprehensive care extending to the abdomen and lower body.
The device comes with 33 customized massage modes — including CEO mode, Golf mode, and Senior mode — allowing users to select based on lifestyle, age, and condition. Additional premium options include IoT-based app connectivity, a Bluetooth sound system, and low-noise design, providing not only spinal care but also a high-end healthcare experience. With its premium specifications, the Master V11 fits seamlessly into homes, VIP lounges, luxury hotel suites, and executive offices.
Ceragem has opened a pop-up store at Hyundai Department Store’s Trade Center branch to showcase the Master V11, proactively expanding consumer touchpoints. Based on consumer response at the pop-up, Ceragem plans to expand operations sequentially to major retail locations such as Lotte Department Store, Starfield, and Shinsegae Department Store starting in September. Visitors can experience the Master V11 firsthand and consult with specialists on-site.
A Ceragem representative said, “The Master V11 is a masterpiece that combines the refined comfort inspired by first-class seating, the Dual Position System enabling full performance whether sitting or lying down, and precise spinal care technology. Through our pop-up stores, we hope more customers will experience Ceragem’s differentiated technology and design.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Ceragem announced on the 11th that it has launched the ‘Master V11’, first unveiled at CES 2024, thereby completing its Master V Collection lineup. Inspired by the experience of first-class travel, th]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.ed3ad2f568e44ac883ba87aa801440fc_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Ceragem’s ‘Master V11’ is equipped with the Dual Position System. (Ceragem)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.96f0768cd3b14502be8b3bfa7f2511f6_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Ceragem)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11406116]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
