<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405893</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>617671</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 10:37:36</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[LG, Samsung to unveil new robot vacuum models at IFA]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 10:37:36</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.cd6e8ecce7d94c2192cc7e3c4717205a_P1.png' alt=' (LG Electronics)'>
LG Electronics Inc. and Samsung Electronics Co. will unveil new robot vacuum models at IFA 2025, Europe’s largest home appliance exhibition kicking off next week in Berlin, Germany.
The new models come as they step up efforts to challenge Chinese brands that control nearly 60 percent of the Korean market.
LG Electronics said Thursday it will unveil two new robot vacuums, the Hidden Station and the Objet Station, designed to appeal to consumers seeking both performance and space efficiency.
The models feature a built-in design that conceals the device when not in use and, for the first time globally, apply steam-cleaning functions to both the vacuum body and the docking station.
The Hidden Station is engineered for compact homes, fitting into underutilized areas such as the kickboard space beneath a kitchen sink.
An automatic door hides the unit when idle, maintaining a clean appearance. To accommodate the tight installation, LG replaced traditional rotating drainage with an air-pump system to reduce component size. The model connects directly to water pipes for automated supply and drainage.
The Objet Station is a freestanding unit styled as a table, designed to blend seamlessly into living spaces such as bedrooms and living rooms. Both models automatically handle dust collection, mopping, and mop washing and drying, offering greater convenience.
The products also incorporate LG’s in-house artificial intelligence technology for object recognition, combining AI chips, LiDAR, 3D cameras, ultrasonic sensors, and bumpers to navigate and clean with precision.
Samsung Electronics will also debut its Bespoke AI Jet Bot Steam at IFA, focusing on steam cleaning and cybersecurity. The model has already earned the highest Diamond rating in internet-of-things security from certification body UL Solutions.
“Chinese appliance makers are targeting Korea’s robot vacuum market, and since local firms entered the all-in-one segment relatively late, they must compete with stronger performance, security, and design,” an industry insider said.
Beijing Roborock Technology Co. Ltd., which leads the Korean robot vacuum market, also sells washer-dryers, while Xiaomi Corp. recently opened its first offline store in Korea, adding robot vacuums and TVs to its lineup.
Chinese models, however, face growing scrutiny over inflated performance claims and data security concerns.
Some have advertised suction power in kilopascals to appear stronger than competitors. The Korean Agency for Technology and Standards mandated wattage as the unified measurement standard last month, allowing consumers to compare products more accurately.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[LG Electronics Inc. and Samsung Electronics Co. will unveil new robot vacuum models at IFA 2025, Europe’s largest home appliance exhibition kicking off next week in Berlin, Germany. The new models com]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.cd6e8ecce7d94c2192cc7e3c4717205a_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (LG Electronics)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405893]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
