<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405039</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>615374</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-28 14:22:29</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Colosseum selects Daishin Securities as IPO lead underwriter]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-28 14:22:29</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.98f1470526ec4c909a7893b5b67cfb77_P1.png' alt=' Colosseum Corporation CI'>
South Korea’s global logistics DX partner Colosseum Corporation Inc. announced on Wednesday that it appointed Daishin Securities Co. as the lead underwriter for its upcoming initial public offering (IPO).
Founded in 2019, Colosseum has developed a unique model that digitally connects existing warehouses into high-performance logistics hubs.
Its business is anchored by the logistics SaaS solution “COLO AI” and its global expert group Fulfillment Director (FD).
Leveraging this model, the company operates a network of 53 logistics centers in Korea and overseas, linking warehouse automation equipment with middle- and last-mile delivery systems.
This integrated infrastructure enables Colosseum to provide a wide range of services, including e-commerce, business-to-business (B2B), cross-border, franchise, and food fulfillment, as well as comprehensive logistics consulting.
The company has achieved an average annual growth rate of 191 percent over the past three years, with its cumulative revenue surpassing 100 billion won ($71.75 million) and total handled logistics volume reaching 6 million cases.
Colosseum also operates 12 overseas hubs in markets such as the United States, Japan, Taiwan, Thailand, Vietnam, and Malaysia, supporting the global expansion of K-beauty and K-food brands.
In particular, it has been stably operating a U.S. fulfillment center since 2023 in partnership with global beauty platform CTK to assist Korean cosmetics companies in entering the local market.
Building on this experience, Colosseum is now establishing subsidiaries in Japan and Singapore to accelerate its expansion in Asia.
Colosseum aims to more than triple its revenue by 2026 and secure 100 global logistics hubs equipped with specialized functions such as cold storage and customized packaging.
The company also plans to capitalize on the growing global popularity of Korean brands while investing heavily in research and development (R&D) and technology upgrades to strengthen its competitiveness.
“This partnership is not just about a successful IPO but a strategic step toward becoming Asia’s leading logistics DX partner,” said Colosseum Chief Executive Officer (CEO) Park Jin-su. “Grounded in a customer-first philosophy and artificial intelligence (AI)-driven innovation, we will grow into a company that leads the global logistics market.”
In June, Colosseum raised 27 billion won in Series B funding despite a cooling investment climate, ranking third among logistics and distribution sector fundraisings in the first half of 2025.
The company also drew industry attention by becoming the first in Korea to issue dual-class shares, securing a stable governance structure ahead of its IPO.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s global logistics DX partner Colosseum Corporation Inc. announced on Wednesday that it appointed Daishin Securities Co. as the lead underwriter for its upcoming initial public offering (I]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.98f1470526ec4c909a7893b5b67cfb77_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Colosseum Corporation CI]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405039]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
