<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397904</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593040</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 09:55:35</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Shinhan joins rivals with new senior-focused brand SOLmate]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 09:55:35</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.899accc07dd340069eeec412664df641_P1.png' alt=' (Shinhan Financial Group)'>
Shinhan Financial Group launched its senior-focused brand Shinhan SOLmate on Tuesday, with the move aimed at capturing the fast-growing elderly wealth segment after rivals introduced similar initiatives.
The brand, which officially began operations this week, is a portmanteau of Shinhan’s digital platform SOL and “soulmate,” reflecting its positioning as a lifelong companion. Led by Shinhan Bank, affiliates including Shinhan Life, Shinhan Investment & Securities, and Shinhan Card will jointly develop products and services under the new brand.
SOLmate is not only targeting seniors but customers preparing for retirement or career transitions as well, offering a mix of financial and lifestyle services. On the financial side, Shinhan plans to enhance retirement-focused products including pensions, trusts, funds, insurance, exchange-traded funds (ETFs), and loans, while strengthening cash flow-based wealth management solutions designed to mitigate post-retirement income gaps.
Non-financial services will include access to premium nursing homes and silver towns, hospital reservation support, dementia prevention programs, and re-employment assistance. Shinhan is also partnering with GC Care Corp., which is under Korean biopharmaceutical group Green Cross, to provide comprehensive health checkups, as well as with an artificial intelligence (AI) humanoid company to introduce rental and purchase options for household robots.
Customers can access SOLmate via Shinhan’s mobile app and offline channels, with the app also offering participation in cultural, health, and arts programs.
The data indicates that South Korea is now a super-aged society, with those aged 65 and above comprising more than 20 percent of the population and controlling an estimated 4,000 trillion won ($2.87 trillion) in assets.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Shinhan Financial Group launched its senior-focused brand Shinhan SOLmate on Tuesday, with the move aimed at capturing the fast-growing elderly wealth segment after rivals introduced similar initiativ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.899accc07dd340069eeec412664df641_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Shinhan Financial Group)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397904]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
