<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402175</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>606300</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-25 14:27:14</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Celltrion holds first R&D event highlighting ADC pipeline]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-25 14:27:14</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.0da3478923564cc79d31bd6406e96c59_P1.png' alt=' (Celltrion)'>
Celltrion Inc. held its first research and development (R&D) event in Seoul on Friday with antibody-drug conjugates (ADCs) as the main theme.
The event, the Celltrion Science & Innovation Day 2025, was aimed at sharing drug development achievements, strategies, and long-term vision with the investment community, the company said Monday.
It invited domestic and global pharmaceutical and biotech analysts.
The program featured six sessions and a panel discussion covering Celltrion’s drug development strategy, progress on bio-better ADCs, and innovations such as a new camptothecin payload for PBX-7016 and next-generation ADC pipelines. The company also presented detailed clinical roadmaps.
In the opening session, Kwon Ki-seong, head of R&D, emphasized Celltrion’s transition into a full-fledged drug development company.
He said the company is expanding its ADC pipeline based on two decades of antibody research and manufacturing expertise, while pursuing open innovation to secure promising technologies.
Lee Soo-young, head of the new drug research division, outlined the ADC development strategy and pipeline status, highlighting clinical progress on CT-P70, which is in Phase 1, as well as CT-P71 and CT-P73.
Lee said the candidates show strong commercialization potential based on target indications, patient populations, and unmet medical needs.
Celltrion also announced plans to advance bispecific ADCs that target two antigens and dual-payload ADCs that combine payloads to enhance therapeutic effect.
Other speakers included Tae Han, co-founder of ProfoundBio US Co., Jung Doo-young, CEO of Pinotbio Inc., Jimmy Li, CEO of WuXi XDC Cayman Inc., and Cho Byoung-chul, head of the Lung Cancer Center at Yonsei Severance Hospital and a participant in the CT-P70 trial.
Celltrion CEO Seo Jin-seok said the company is accelerating new drug development by combining its antibody expertise with active partnerships.
Seo added that it aims to quickly commercialize therapies in oncology and other areas with high unmet medical demand.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Celltrion Inc. held its first research and development (R&D) event in Seoul on Friday with antibody-drug conjugates (ADCs) as the main theme. The event, the Celltrion Science & Innovation Day 2025, wa]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.0da3478923564cc79d31bd6406e96c59_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Celltrion)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402175]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
