<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11403076</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>609370</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-26 14:35:50</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai Steel subcontractor union ups pressure after bill passage]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-26 14:35:50</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.8f0115ca3ac443a2abfde4f3db3f942f_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
Subcontractor unions are turning up the pressure on major corporations following the passage of a revised labor law that broadens the definition of “employer” under Articles 2 and 3 of the Labor Standards Act.
The Hyundai Steel subcontractor branch of the Korean Metal Workers’ Union held a press conference in front of the National Assembly in Yeouido, Seoul, on Monday, demanding direct employment from the parent company.
“Hyundai Steel, the real employer, must negotiate with subcontracted workers,” the union said.
The so-called Yellow Envelope Law allows subcontracted workers to negotiate directly with parent companies rather than subcontractors, raising concerns in the business community about a wave of aggressive demands and potential strikes.
The term Yellow Envelope Law originates from a 2014 solidarity campaign during a SsangYong Motor strike. At the time, a court ordered workers to pay heavy compensation, prompting citizens to collect donations in yellow envelopes as a gesture of support.
The subcontracted workers are technically employed by partner companies but work inside Hyundai Steel facilities.
Until now, their bargaining counterpart was the subcontractor. Once the law takes effect after cabinet approval and a six-month grace period, they will be able to demand negotiations directly with Hyundai Steel. While the law does not mandate direct employment, it allows unions to increase pressure on the parent company.
On Tuesday, the union plans to stage a rally in front of the Supreme Prosecutors’ Office in Seoul and file a complaint accusing Hyundai Steel of unfair labor practices.
About 1,900 workers are expected to participate in the filing. The union argues that Hyundai Steel has attempted to sidestep direct employment by converting subcontracted workers into employees of affiliates, which it claims amounts to illegal dispatch.
The government has pledged to use the six-month grace period before enforcement to establish clear guidelines on employer status and bargaining procedures, but confusion is already mounting.
“The law itself is ambiguous, and companies urgently need concrete guidance on the scope of employer responsibility,” said one industry official. “Right now, management has no clear answers on how to respond.”
James Kim, chairman and CEO of the American Chamber of Commerce in Korea, also issued a statement on Monday urging the government to provide “clear and consistent standards to ensure the law does not undermine Korea’s economic competitiveness.”
“For Korea to strengthen its standing as a global business hub beyond Asia, a fair, transparent, and predictable labor and management environment is essential,” Kim said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Subcontractor unions are turning up the pressure on major corporations following the passage of a revised labor law that broadens the definition of “employer” under Articles 2 and 3 of the Labor Stand]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.8f0115ca3ac443a2abfde4f3db3f942f_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11403076]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
