<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387411</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>563281</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 10:43:47</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics shares gain on Apple chip deal]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 10:43:47</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-07 16:50:06</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.14272552e26747dfaef4bc6326eddb3e_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Shares of Samsung Electronics rose sharply in early trading Thursday following reports that the tech giant will manufacture Apple’s next-generation chips at its U.S.-based foundry plant.
As of 9:15 a.m., Samsung was trading at 70,000 won ($50.45) on the Korea Exchange, up 1.74 percent from the previous session, reclaiming the symbolic “70,000 club” status.
Investor sentiment was buoyed by news that Apple is strengthening its collaboration with Samsung and other partners as part of a broader investment expansion in the United States. Market watchers also suggested that Samsung could be a key beneficiary of U.S. tariffs on semiconductor imports proposed by President Donald Trump.
During an Apple investment announcement event held at the White House early Thursday (Korea time), Trump reiterated his plan to impose a 100 percent tariff on certain chip products. However, he added that chips manufactured at U.S.-based facilities would be exempt from the tariff—positioning Samsung’s local operations favorably.
Meanwhile, shares of eco-friendly plastic and packaging companies rallied early Thursday after reports emerged that the Korean government is pushing a national roadmap for plastic reduction as part of its key policy agenda.
As of 9:18 a.m., shares of Samryoong were up 8.44 percent to 9,510 won, while Serim B&G and EcoPlastic rose 4.75 percent and 1.36 percent, respectively.
According to media reports, the Ministry of Environment recently submitted a detailed implementation plan for the roadmap to the Presidential Planning Committee. During his confirmation hearing last month, Environment Minister Kim Sung-hwan pledged to finalize the roadmap by year-end, emphasizing a transition from a one-way consumption model to a circular economy structure.
Samsung Electronics shares closed at 70,500 won on Thursday, up 2.47 percent from the previous day. Shares of Samryoong stayed flat at 8,770 won while those of Serim B&G finished 0.16 percent lower at 1,827 won and EcoPlastic 1.36 percent lower at 3,635 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Shares of Samsung Electronics rose sharply in early trading Thursday following reports that the tech giant will manufacture Apple’s next-generation chips at its U.S.-based foundry plant. As of 9:15 a.]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.14272552e26747dfaef4bc6326eddb3e_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387411]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
