<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384410</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554276</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 09:10:46</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[K-beauty shines in Hollywood with pop-up event]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 09:10:46</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.3fb07ccf919344bfacadf3572600ef78_P1.jpg' alt=' (Hansung USA)'>
Ten leading South Korean beauty brands gathered for the K-Beauty Hall of Fame pop-up event held in Hollywood, Los Angeles, from July 17 to 20, displaying K-beauty’s global influence.
The event was organized by K-beauty distributor Hansung USA in partnership with Ulta Beauty, a leading U.S. beauty retailer.
Spanning skincare, makeup, and haircare, the pop-up featured 10 representative K-beauty brands and attracted more than 5,500 visitors, highlighting surging interest in Korean cosmetics.
On the first day, over 200 industry insiders attended the VIP session, including Caitlin Reinhard, Vice President of Merchandising at Ulta Beauty, as well as MD teams and editors from beauty media outlets.
The event also marked the Ulta Beauty debut of several K-beauty brands—TIRTIR, fwee, and VT Cosmetics, known for its Reedle Shot line—making them the first Korean makeup labels to officially launch in a major U.S. offline retail channel this summer.
Throughout the four-day event, attendees enjoyed a range of programs, including a masterclass on LAKA led by celebrity makeup artist Daniel Martin, a TIRTIR panel talk featuring Ulta MDs and beauty influencers, and an influencer session co-hosted by beauty creator Wendyskin (1.2 million TikTok followers) and skincare brand Manyo Factory.
“This pop-up served not only as an opportunity for K-beauty to reach American consumers, but also as a turning point to strengthen our foothold in the North American market through our partnership with Ulta Beauty,” said Choi Jae-ho, CEO of Hansung USA.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Ten leading South Korean beauty brands gathered for the K-Beauty Hall of Fame pop-up event held in Hollywood, Los Angeles, from July 17 to 20, displaying K-beauty’s global influence. The event was org]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.3fb07ccf919344bfacadf3572600ef78_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hansung USA)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384410]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
