<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384550</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554775</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 10:39:38</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean battery trios’ Jan.-June market share drops to 16.4%]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 10:39:38</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.cf9feccb32d54111afec8b5969c3aa4a_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korean battery trios – LG Energy Solution Ltd., SK on Co., and Samsung SDI Co. – saw their combined market share in global battery usage for electric vehicles (EVs) fall by 5.4 percentage points in the first six months of 2025 from the same period a year ago.
According to data from energy market research firm SNE Research on Monday, the combined market share of the three companies declined to 16.4 percent in the first six months of this year.
LG Energy Solution recorded battery usage of 47.2 GWh, up 4.4 percent year-on-year, maintaining third place with a 9.4 percent market share.
SK on increased its usage by 10.7 percent to 19.6 GWh, securing fifth place with a 3.9 percent share.
Samsung SDI, on the other hand, saw its usage fall by 8 percent to 16 GWh, and its market share dropped from 4.7 percent to 3.2 percent. A decline in battery demand from major original equipment manufacturers in Europe and North America played a role.
SNE Research data, in the meantime, also showed that total battery usage for EVs, plug-in hybrids (PHEVs), and hybrids (HEVs) registered worldwide from January to June reached 504.4 GWh, up 37.3 percent from the same period last year.
Chinese battery manufacturers continued their dominance.
Contemporary Amperex Technology (CATL) maintained its lead with a 37.9 percent market share and 190.9 GWh in shipments, up 37.9 percent from a year earlier. BYD, in second place, saw usage jump 58.4 percent to 89.9 GWh.
Six Chinese firms, including China Aviation Lithium Battery (CALB) and SVOLT Energy Technology Co., were among the global top 10. Japan’s Panasonic Corp, a key Tesla supplier, ranked sixth with 18.8 GWh.
SNE Research noted that intensifying regulations and supply chain shifts in the U.S. and Europe are reshaping the battery market.
“Battery makers now face pressure not only to boost technological competitiveness but also to secure independent supply chains and build in greater flexibility,” it said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean battery trios – LG Energy Solution Ltd., SK on Co., and Samsung SDI Co. – saw their combined market share in global battery usage for electric vehicles (EVs) fall by 5.4 percentage points]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.cf9feccb32d54111afec8b5969c3aa4a_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384550]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
