<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11400188</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>600113</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-22 11:17:12</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean shipbuilding, nuclear stocks rise ahead of Lee-Trump summit]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-22 11:17:12</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-22 17:33:43</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.97399e08185b49e894ab7107cc68303a_P1.jpg' alt=' (Office of the President)'>
Korean shipbuilding and nuclear power-related stocks were up on Friday ahead of next week’s first summit between South Korean President Lee Jae-myung and U.S. President Donald Trump.
According to the Korea Exchange, HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. shares rose 0.95 percent to 476,500 won ($230.50) as of 9:09 a.m. Hanwha Ocean Co.’s shares gained 3.05 percent, while those for HD Hyundai Mipo Co. added 0.69 percent and Samsung Heavy Industries Co.’s were up 0.83 percent.
Nuclear power stocks were also stronger, with those for Doosan Enerbility Co. up 1.14 percent, KEPCO Engineering & Construction Company Inc. advancing 1 percent, and Hanshin Machinery Co. climbing 1.69 percent.
Lee is scheduled to meet Trump on August 25th, 2025 (local time), with Korean business leaders accompanying him as part of an economic delegation.
The talks are expected to reinforce the bilateral alliance through wide-ranging cooperation from shipbuilding - highlighted by the Make American Shipbuilding Great Again (MASGA) initiative - to semiconductors and nuclear power. Lee is also set to visit Hanwha Philly Shipyard in Philadelphia during the trip.
Separately, wearable medical device maker Seers Technology Co. saw its shares hit a 52-week high in early trade the same day after reporting strong second-quarter 2025 earnings and on expectations of sustained growth.
The stock jumped 6.84 percent to 40,600 won on the Kosdaq market as of 9:27 a.m. after briefly hitting 41,100 won, its highest level in a year.
Seers Technology posted second-quarter revenue of 8 billion won, up 799.5 percent from a year earlier, and swung to an operating profit of 1.5 billion won. Analysts attributed the rally to expectations for continuous earnings momentum, driven by the rapid uptake of ThynC, the company’s real-time inpatient monitoring service.
Korea Investment & Securities Co. analyst Yoon Chul-hwan said ThynC’s growth marks the start of sustained expansion rather than a one-off gain, citing projections that the number of hospital wards adopting the service will increase from three in 2023 to more than 100 by 2025.
Yoon added that the company stands to benefit from operating leverage as revenue scales further.
HD Hyundai Heavy Industries shares closed at 483,000 won and Seers Technology shares closed at 44,100 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Korean shipbuilding and nuclear power-related stocks were up on Friday ahead of next week’s first summit between South Korean President Lee Jae-myung and U.S. President Donald Trump. According to the ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.97399e08185b49e894ab7107cc68303a_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Office of the President)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11400188]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
