<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11403077</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>609371</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-26 14:36:00</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Revised labor law raises concerns about direct negotiations]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-26 14:36:00</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.f4761cdba42c4ac3954d66438abac410_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
The passage of amendments to Articles 2 and 3 of the Labor Union and Labor Relations Adjustment Act, commonly referred to as the Yellow Envelope Act, has sent shockwaves through South Korea’s retail industry.
Concerns are spreading that the law could lead to widespread direct confrontations between corporate headquarters and groups such as part-time workers, delivery riders, and outsourced cleaners or security staff. Industry insiders fear that prolonged disputes could undermine the very foundation of service-dependent sectors.
On Monday, industry officials told Maeil Business Newspaper that the law could intensify labor-management conflicts.
“To minimize disruptions at worksites, the government must establish clear enforcement decrees and allow sufficient grace periods with supplementary legislation,” they said.
Korea’s retail sector is largely structured around large corporations or franchise headquarters subcontracting operations like logistics, services, and outlets to smaller partners. With the new law broadening the interpretation of “employer” to include headquarters, businesses worry they could face unavoidable operational risks.
The parcel delivery industry, in particular, is on alert over the possibility of frequent large-scale strikes. Even before the law, the industry suffered significant disruptions from past labor stoppages. Under the new law, delivery workers could be guaranteed wider rights to collective action.
CJ Logistics Corp., for example, is currently in litigation over whether it is obligated to negotiate directly with the National Courier Workers’ Union.
The franchise sector is also expressing concern.
It remains unclear whether franchisors should be regarded as employers when they manage franchisees’ service quality. The issue becomes more complex when factoring in part-time staff hired by franchisees. The question of how far headquarters’ responsibility extends, and to what extent workers can demand direct bargaining, remains unresolved.
Industry observers say this could elevate the issue of a “three-way labor relationship” among franchisors, franchisees, and part-time workers into a major flashpoint.
Previously, part-time workers signed contracts only with franchisees, without a direct tie to the headquarters. Under the Yellow Envelope Act, however, if a franchisor provides wage guidelines, operating hours, or work manuals, part-time workers organized under so-called “part-time worker unions” could demand collective bargaining directly with headquarters.
Analysts note that this scenario is no longer hypothetical, pointing to past cases where groups of franchise part-timers sought negotiations with headquarters rather than store owners.
“If extreme bargaining or collective action were to arise during negotiations on pricing, supply costs, or marketing fees, both headquarters and franchisees could be strained, with consumers also feeling the impact,” one industry official said. “We need safeguards that reflect the unique characteristics of each industry so that the law’s intent does not translate into excessive burdens in practice.”
Food delivery platforms are equally uneasy. With the law enabling riders not directly employed by companies to join strikes, operations such as logistics, delivery, and in-store stocking could be paralyzed, causing serious business losses.
The same risks apply to department stores and duty-free outlets if contracted service workers launch strikes, insiders noted.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The passage of amendments to Articles 2 and 3 of the Labor Union and Labor Relations Adjustment Act, commonly referred to as the Yellow Envelope Act, has sent shockwaves through South Korea’s retail i]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.f4761cdba42c4ac3954d66438abac410_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11403077]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
