<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397905</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593041</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 09:55:46</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[LG’s U.S.-based ad tech firm Alphonso eyes IPO in H2]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 09:55:46</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.f4393dce644a42e4be2dde9d45f09f39_P1.png' alt=' Alphonso founder and board member Ashish Chordia. (News1)'>
Alphonso, a U.S. connected TV ad company majority-owned by LG Electronics, said that it plans to go public in the United States later in 2025. The announcement comes as Alphonso unveiled the technology and vision behind its global connected TV (CTV) advertising brand, LG Ad Solutions, highlighting LG’s strategy to expand its webOS ecosystem worldwide amid the industry shift toward ad-supported platforms.
At a press briefing in Seoul on Tuesday, Alphonso founder and board member Ashish Chordia said, “Alphonso plays a central role in realizing LG’s vision of evolving smart TVs into digital platforms where content, advertising, commerce, and artificial intelligence naturally converge.”
Founded in 2013 in Mountain View, California, Alphonso specializes in advertising and content data analytics. LG’s U.S. R&D subsidiary Zenith acquired a 65.7 percent stake in the company in 2020, making it a core partner. Alphonso has since launched LG Ad Solutions and expanded its capabilities in advertising and content personalization, leveraging over 200 million webOS-powered smart TVs worldwide.
The backbone of LG Ad Solutions is automatic content recognition (ACR) technology, which identifies in real time what content viewers are watching. This allows advertisers to target audiences precisely while tracking ad reach and effectiveness simultaneously. Alphonso emphasized that advertisers benefit from greater efficiency, while viewers enjoy more personalized experiences, with competitors in space including Samsung Ads and Roku. Alphonso also noted that LG’s webOS-based advertising and content business topped 1 trillion won ($735 million) in revenue in 2024.
Chordia added that even global players such as Netflix and Amazon are shifting to ad-based models, recognizing the limitations of subscription-only businesses. Alphonso aims to extend the webOS ecosystem beyond TVs into automobiles, airplanes, hotels, and smart home appliances.
The company announced that it intends to list on the U.S. stock market in 2025, in accordance with shareholder agreements established during Zenith’s investment. According to these terms, founders and major shareholders may request a U.S. listing within three years if specific performance milestones are met.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Alphonso, a U.S. connected TV ad company majority-owned by LG Electronics, said that it plans to go public in the United States later in 2025. The announcement comes as Alphonso unveiled the technolog]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.f4393dce644a42e4be2dde9d45f09f39_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Alphonso founder and board member Ashish Chordia. (News1)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397905]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
