<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11392850</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>578579</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-13 14:55:49</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[China’s robotics industry growing at a faster pace than expected]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-13 14:55:49</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.9a520a88fda0436db1e440b6a741e3ec_P1.png' alt=' (Song Kwang-sub)'>
The pace of development of China’s robotics industry is faster than expected, according to Chang Jae-hoon, vice chairman of South Korea’s Hyundai Motor Group.
“China is quick when it comes to commercialization and mass production of robot products,” Chang said, in an interview with Maeil Business Newspaper on Monday.
The interview was held after he toured the World Robot Conference (WRC) 2025 held in the Yizhuang Economic and Technological Development Zone in Beijing, China.
“Visiting the booths, I learned that some companies receive strong support from local governments. Not only is China’s robotics ecosystem solid, but it also feels generally well-structured.”
Chang arrived in Beijing that morning and headed straight to the WRC venue.
Wearing an earpiece for interpretation, he spent three to four hours with more than 20 staff members touring every corner of the A, B, and C exhibition halls.
He personally stepped into and examined products at roughly a dozen booths.
One booth that drew his particular interest was that of Unitree Robotics, one of China’s leading robotics companies.
<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.387231e8ad554b36a2c5bca285df4e4e_P1.png' alt=' (Xinhua/Yonhap)'>
Even on a weekday, crowds flocked to see Unitree’s demonstration of its humanoid robot G1 in a martial arts performance.
After watching briefly, Chang turned toward the company’s quadruped robots -commonly known as robot dogs - and engaged in a lengthy discussion with Unitree staff.
The attention was notable given that Boston Dynamics Inc., a Hyundai Motor Group affiliate, is well known for its own quadruped robot Spot.
Chang also spent considerable time at the booth of Chinese humanoid robotics firm Galbot Co., observing a wheeled humanoid robot approaching a convenience store–style display and retrieving requested items for customers.
At another booth, Chang focused on a demonstration of the humanoid robot DexForce W1 Pro, which is based on Simulation to Reality (Sim2Real) technology - a process in which robots reproduce in the real world the skills and strategies they learned in virtual environments.
He also visited the booths of UBTECH Robotics Co., the maker of Tiangong, which won the world’s first humanoid robot marathon held in Beijing in April 2025; PaXini Tech, a humanoid robot company made famous by investment from BYD Co., now the world’s largest electric vehicle manufacturer; and RoboTerra, Inc. a startup spun out of a Tsinghua University research team in 2023.
Marking its 10th anniversary this year, the WRC 2025 was held from August 8 to 12 under the theme “Making Robots Smarter, Making Embodied Agents More Intelligent.”
The 2025 event featured a record 220 companies showcasing some 1,500 products - most of them from Chinese domestic firms.
Before leaving the venue, Chang was asked about Hyundai Motor Group’s robotics business plans.
“Building an industrial ecosystem seems important,” he said. “I will take my time to think about what needs to be done once I return to Korea.”
The event revealed that not only complete robot manufacturers but also numerous parts suppliers were present, underscoring China’s grip on the robotics supply chain.
Chang’s remarks appeared to reflect this context.
Hyundai Motor Group leads the Korean robotics industry through its affiliate Boston Dynamics.
Its quadruped robot Spot is currently deployed for patrol duties at Hyundai’ Motor Co’s Ulsan plant, Kia Corp.’s Hwaseong and Gwangju plants, Hyundai Motor Group Innovation Center in Singapore (HMGICS), and Hyundai Motor Group Metaplant America (HMGMA) in the United States.
Recently, Spot appeared on the popular American variety show America’s Got Talent, performing a perfectly synchronized dance routine.
Boston Dynamics’ humanoid robot “Atlas” is scheduled for pilot application on Hyundai Motor Group production lines by the end of this year.
Earlier, the company released a video on its YouTube channel showing Atlas operating autonomously in a factory environment, as well as running, somersaulting, and performing various movements.
Hyundai’s Robotics LAB is also preparing for mass production of its four-wheel-drive mobility robot MobED by the end of the year.
“We plan to expand our range of robots and services while advancing our technologies to provide a total robotics service,” a Hyundai official said. “We will continue to lead the future robotics market.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The pace of development of China’s robotics industry is faster than expected, according to Chang Jae-hoon, vice chairman of South Korea’s Hyundai Motor Group. “China is quick when it comes to commerci]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.9a520a88fda0436db1e440b6a741e3ec_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Song Kwang-sub)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.387231e8ad554b36a2c5bca285df4e4e_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Xinhua/Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11392850]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
