<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388490</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566235</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:59:26</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Nine LCCs in operation in Korea as market expands]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:59:26</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.04426af53e66478bbe1b57c755ce92d8_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
A total of nine low-cost carriers (LCCs) are competing for a larger share of South Korea’s rapidly growing market, seeking different route strategies and aircraft operation methods for growth.
According to sources from the aviation industry on Thursday, the number of domestic LCCs has increased to nine after Parata Air - formerly Fly Gangwon - received a renewed Air Operator Certificate (AOC).
Parata Air is preparing to launch operations next month.
With new airlines joining existing carriers, competition in the industry is becoming increasingly fierce, sources noted.
The LCCs are largely divided into two groups: those focusing on medium- to long-haul routes and those concentrating on short-haul routes.
Long-haul LCCs aim to capture demand for overseas long-haul travel, while short-haul LCCs target domestic and nearby regional markets.
Air Premia Inc., Parata Air, and T’way Air Co. are among the carriers focusing on long-haul routes.
These airlines are introducing wide-body aircraft such as the Airbus A330 series to expand services to destinations such as North America, Europe, and Hawaii, offering differentiated services.
Air Premia, Korea’s only mid-to-long-haul hybrid carrier, is pursuing a model that combines the service quality of full-service airlines with the price competitiveness of LCCs.
It is quickly establishing itself as a “value-for-money” airline, offering a distinct customer experience in the long-haul market.
In particular, Air Premia operates a single aircraft type - the Boeing 787-9 - and offers just two seat classes: wide premium and economy.
The wide premium class is optimized for long-haul flights with generous seat spacing of up to 46 inches and ample reclining space, resulting in high customer satisfaction.
Parata Air recently introduced the long-haul-capable Airbus A330-200 as its first aircraft, signaling its ambition to eventually launch routes to North America.
The airline expects synergies from its owner Winix Inc.’s business network in the region to support this strategic direction.
Parata plans to operate domestic and short-haul international routes to destinations such as Japan and Vietnam before launching North American routes.
The carrier has finalized the introduction of one A330-200 and two A320-200 aircraft this year, aiming to enhance on-time performance.
T’way Air is also continuing its long-haul expansion strategy.
Following the launch of European routes, the airline began regular service between Incheon and Vancouver this month, marking its entry into the North American market and further expanding its international reach.
On the other hand, the remaining six carriers, including Jeju Air Co., Jin Air Co., Eastar Jet Co., Air Busan Co., and Air Seoul Co., are concentrating on short- and medium-haul routes to destinations such as Japan, Southeast Asia, and China.
These airlines focus on stable profitability by operating small to mid-sized aircraft with high efficiency on short-haul routes.
However, concerns are rising about excessive competition as the risk of declining profit margins and rising operational costs is increasing with the fast-paced growth of the market.
Industry observers warn of heightened management risks stemming from aggressive price wars and overexpansion of routes.
They believe that differentiated route strategies and enhanced service competitiveness will be key drivers for boosting diversity and competitiveness in Korea’s LCC market.
“The domestic LCC market is clearly reorganizing into two segments - mid-to-long-haul and short-haul - based on aircraft types and route characteristics,” said an industry insider. “We expect the overall diversity and competitiveness of the aviation industry to improve as each airline capitalizes on its unique strengths to implement differentiated strategies.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[A total of nine low-cost carriers (LCCs) are competing for a larger share of South Korea’s rapidly growing market, seeking different route strategies and aircraft operation methods for growth. Accordi]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.04426af53e66478bbe1b57c755ce92d8_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388490]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
