<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11391231</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>573362</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-12 06:43:07</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Duty-free retailers cry foul over ‘excessive’ Incheon Airport rents]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-12 06:43:07</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.0173cb6eee3644bf8bcb8c641957c814_P1.jpg' alt=' (Shinsegae Duty Free)'>
A simmering dispute between Incheon International Airport Corp. (IIAC) and domestic duty-free operators over rental fees has escalated after a court-commissioned appraisal concluded that current rents are far above market value.
Samil PwC, tasked by the Incheon District Court to assess the matter, found that rents for the airport’s duty-free zones - if put out for rebidding - would likely fall to about 60 percent of current levels. The finding could mark a turning point in the standoff between IIAC and major retailers Shilla Duty Free and Shinsegae Duty Free, which have been pushing for a 40 percent rent reduction.
According to documents reviewed by Maeil Business Newspaper on Monday, Samil PwC submitted its report to the court on August 7th, 2025. The appraisal considered current and projected sales for the affected duty-free areas through 2033, along with rental obligations and interest expenses from security deposits. The firm estimated that, under a rebidding scenario, rents would drop roughly 40 percent from present levels.
While per-customer spending is assumed to hold steady, Samil PwC projected that sales in the zones would grow by an average of 4.5 percent annually, thanks to rising passenger traffic. However, it said that the growth rate would still outpace inflation, and higher rents would eat into operators’ profitability.
The airport’s rental structure has been tied to passenger volume since July 2023, with monthly rent calculated by multiplying the number of departing passengers by a per-capita rate. The two duty-free companies currently pay about 30 billion won ($21.7 million) each per month.
Samil PwC warned that even as outbound passenger numbers have rebounded to pre-COVID-19 pandemic levels and continue to climb, rent obligations will also keep rising despite duty-free sales in key categories lagging behind 2019 levels. Sales of fashion, accessories, and luxury boutique items have recovered and are growing, but cosmetics and perfume sales remain at just 53 percent of 2019 figures, while liquor and tobacco sales are at about 65 percent.
The report cited two major factors: changing spending habits among Chinese tourists, once a key growth driver, toward value-oriented and experiential purchases, and the steady rise of online duty-free sales among Korean consumers, particularly hurting cosmetics and perfume revenues.
Based on target profit margins set by the retailers, Samil PwC concluded that any new winning bid in a rebid process would come in at just 52 to 69 percent of the current per-passenger rent. In previous bids, Shilla and Shinsegae won leases at rates in the 8,000-won range per passenger, but current estimates put a likely winning bid at 4,000 to 5,000 won. Even under aggressive bidding, rents would still fall more than 30 percent from present levels, the firm said.
Industry officials say that with per-customer spending in the affected categories in decline, there is little incentive for retailers to bid aggressively.
It remains to be seen whether the findings will soften IIAC’s stance. The airport authority has so far refused to participate in court-mediated settlement talks, arguing that rents were set through a competitive bidding process and are therefore not subject to revision. It also maintains that no “national disaster” such as the COVID-19 pandemic exists to justify extraordinary rent cuts.
However, Shilla and Shinsegae are urging IIAC to at least come to the negotiation table. Should either retailer exit before the end of their contracts, they would reportedly face penalties of about 200 billion won.
“Incheon Airport and the domestic duty-free industry are supposed to be long-term partners,” Lee Jong-woo, a business professor at Ajou University, said. “They need to find some form of compromise.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[A simmering dispute between Incheon International Airport Corp. (IIAC) and domestic duty-free operators over rental fees has escalated after a court-commissioned appraisal concluded that current rents]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.0173cb6eee3644bf8bcb8c641957c814_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Shinsegae Duty Free)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11391231]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
