<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393879</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>581940</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 15:14:46</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Dongbu swings to profit in H1 on cost reduction efforts]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 15:14:46</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.75b52283e81349ae813da592cbf3881e_P1.png' alt=' (Dongbu Corp.)'>
Dongbu Corp. said Thursday it swung to a profit in the first half, posting an operating income of 16.6 billion won ($12.12 million), up 128.3 percent from a year earlier.
Sales fell about 4 percent to 829.4 billion won, while net income rose 113.2 percent to 10.7 billion won.
The company’s cost ratio dropped to about 87 percent from over 100 percent a year ago, supported by a higher share of high-margin projects, tighter cost control, and the completion of sites that had carried heavy cost burdens last year.
Its debt-to-equity ratio improved by roughly 16 percentage points to 248 percent.
The order backlog stood at around 10.9 trillion won at end-June.
New wins included a 340 billion won package for Section 1 of the Busan New Port–Gimhae Expressway and nearly 600 billion won in urban-renewal projects across Seoul, including in Mangwoo-dong, Gocheok-dong, and Cheonho-dong, bringing total new contracts across public, private, and overseas businesses to more than 1 trillion won in the first half.
“We delivered meaningful results across profitability, stability, and growth in the first half, and will expand high-value projects while diversifying our portfolio and strengthening risk management in the second half,” a company official said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Dongbu Corp. said Thursday it swung to a profit in the first half, posting an operating income of 16.6 billion won ($12.12 million), up 128.3 percent from a year earlier. Sales fell about 4 percent to]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.75b52283e81349ae813da592cbf3881e_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Dongbu Corp.)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393879]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
