<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11396046</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>588186</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-18 14:44:10</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Devsister’s Cookie Run game attracts attention in North America]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-18 14:44:10</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.91f7640f7d90479391145999906e2aae_P1.png' alt=' (Devsister)'>
“Cookie Run: Braverse,” a trading card game created by South Korea’s Devsisters Corp., is causing a sell-out frenzy in North America following its launch in July 2025 as demand surges.
The initial supply sold out immediately after release and the number of retail stores carrying the game more than doubled within a month, reflecting the enthusiastic response from local players.
The game - officially titled “Cookie Run: Braverse Trading Card Game,” Devsisters planned and directly developed the physical trading card game (TCG) based on its Cookie Run IP, which has more than 200 million cumulative users worldwide. Players can collect physical cards, build their own decks, and enjoy strategic gameplay.
According to Devsisters, over 10 million cards will be distributed across the United States and Canada in four waves by October 2025. Based on local retail prices, this amounts to roughly 9 billion won ($6.5 million) in sales.
Starter decks and booster packs distributed at launch sold out quickly, and card shops in the region are continuously requesting restocks.
In response, Devsisters plans to release an emergency second batch - around 50 percent of the initial supply - within August 2025, followed by a third batch in October that will surpass the original supply.
A new booster pack scheduled for early October 2025 will be produced at three times the volume of the first run.
Cookie Run Card Game is currentlt available in around 500 card shops across North America, with over 100 more shops waiting to stock it. Compared to the initial 200 stores supplied at launch, the number of retail locations has more than doubled in less than a month.
Local card shops report that card packs sell out quickly, with players consistently requesting restocks.
This success in North America is significant as it marks the first step toward establishing a sustainable ecosystem for a homegrown Korean IP in the global TCG stronghold.
According to BCC Research, the global TCG market was $7.8 billion in 2024, with North America accounting for about 43.5 percent of the total.
The brand awareness that Cookie Run has built in the United States over the years also played a key role in securing early players.
The 2021 release of the collectible RPG “Cookie Run: Kingdom” was particularly extremely popular in the United States, which now generates about 50 percent of the game’s total revenue.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[“Cookie Run: Braverse,” a trading card game created by South Korea’s Devsisters Corp., is causing a sell-out frenzy in North America following its launch in July 2025 as demand surges. The initial sup]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.91f7640f7d90479391145999906e2aae_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Devsister)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11396046]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
