<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11382836</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>549369</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-01 11:05:18</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[FuriosaAI becomes new chip unicorn with $718mn valuation]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-01 11:05:18</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/01/news-p.v1.20250801.0700d13393794d68a8ff43e70b5c823e_P1.png' alt=''>
South Korean artificial intelligence (AI) chip startup FuriosaAI Inc. joined the ranks of unicorns - unlisted companies valued at over 1 trillion won ($717.9 million) - after raising 170 billion won in a Series C bridge funding round.
FuriosaAI said on Thursday that around 40 investors participated in this round. Major participants included Korea Development Bank (30 billion won), Keistone Partners (20 billion won), and Pipartners (13.2 billion won).
The amount raised in this single round is nearly equivalent to the company’s cumulative funding over the past seven years, indicative of the strong market confidence in its vision and capabilities.
FuriosaAI noted that its corporate valuation has surpassed 1 trillion won, up from the previous 830 billion won thanks to this funding round.
The funds will be used for the mass production of its 2nd-generation neural processing unit (NPU), RNGD, and the development of its 3rd generation NPU.
As RNGD begins entering large-scale enterprise markets, securing production volume in advance has become crucial, the company said.
FuriosaAI recently completed testing with LG AI Research’s large language model (LLM), EXAONE, and signed an official partnership.
As EXAONE’s user base grows, demand is expected to rise for RNGD-equipped data centers supporting the model.
“RNGD not only meets LG’s high-performance standards but has also proven to deliver 2.25 times the performance per watt compared to traditional GPUs, making it a compelling reference in the global market,” the company said.
FuriosaAI CEO Baek Jun-ho added that “this investment marks a crucial point as we enter RNGD’s mass production phase.”
“It shows that the capital market strongly believes in our technology and vision,” Baek said. “We aim to expand our revenue from global enterprise customers.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean artificial intelligence (AI) chip startup FuriosaAI Inc. joined the ranks of unicorns - unlisted companies valued at over 1 trillion won ($717.9 million) - after raising 170 billion won i]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/01/news-p.v1.20250801.0700d13393794d68a8ff43e70b5c823e_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11382836]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
