<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11399071</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>596695</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-21 10:45:38</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean banks’ global net profit up 10% in H1]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-21 10:45:38</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.506892fbc9a64e18bc3f50993d68059c_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
South Korea’s four major commercial banks posted a 10 percent jump in net profit from their overseas operations in the first half of 2025, data showed on Wednesday.
According to data from the Financial Supervisory Service on Wednesday, the combined net profit from the overseas subsidiaries of the four banks - KB Kookmin, Shinhan, Hana, and Woori - stood at 465.3 billion won ($332.85 million) in the first half of 2025, up 10 percent from 423.6 billion won a year earlier.
The improvement was largely attributable to KB Kookmin Bank.
Its overseas operations, which had posted a 37.1 billion won loss in the first half of 2024, swung to a 72.7 billion won profit - a turnaround of roughly 110 billion won in just one year.
The main driver was the improved performance of KB Bank Indonesia, formerly Bank KB Bukopin, which was long considered a weak spot for the group.
KB Bank has been working to cut non-performing loans and streamline its cost structure, aiming to transform into a growth-oriented institution.
This year, the bank appointed a local CEO, while KB Financial Group‘s head of global business, Lee Jae-keun, has been spending one month each quarter on-site to oversee operations.
As a result, KB Bank’s losses in the first half were reduced to 53.8 billion won, about half the level of a year earlier.
KB Financial has declared 2025 the year to bring KB Bank into the black.
KB Kookmin Bank also posted strong results in Cambodia, where its net profit reached 111.8 billion won, doubling its growth year-on-year.
Shinhan Bank posted 315.2 billion won in net profit in the first half from 10 overseas subsidiaries in the United States, Canada, Europe, China, and elsewhere.
This represents a 6 percent increase from 296.2 billion won a year earlier, though growth slowed compared with the 14 percent increase recorded in the first half of 2024.
The weaker growth was mainly due to underperformance in Vietnam.
Shinhan Bank Vietnam’s net profit fell 9.4 percent year-on-year to 128 billion won during the cited period, as profitability was hit by the fallout from U.S. President Trump’s reciprocal tariff policies across Southeast Asia.
On the other hand, Shinhan’s Japanese unit, Shinhan Bank Japan, offset some of the weakness, with net profit rising 20 percent from 71.5 billion won to 85.4 billion won.
Hana and Woori Bank, however, saw significant declines in the first half.
Hana Bank’s overseas net profit fell 36 percent to 44.9 billion won from 70.1 billion won a year earlier, as lower benchmark rates in Canada and Germany cut into interest income, while its Russian unit suffered foreign-exchange losses from the weakening ruble.
Woori Bank’s overseas subsidiaries reported net profit of just 32.5 billion won, one-third of the 94.4 billion won recorded a year earlier.
The main drag was PT Bank Woori Saudara Indonesia, which booked losses exceeding 60 billion won.
The bank was hit by a financial fraud incident in the second quarter of 2025 that cost over 100 billion won, forcing it to set aside large provisions and recognize losses.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s four major commercial banks posted a 10 percent jump in net profit from their overseas operations in the first half of 2025, data showed on Wednesday. According to data from the Financia]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.506892fbc9a64e18bc3f50993d68059c_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11399071]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
