<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405890</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>617676</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 10:37:25</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[BOK stands still again despite near-zero growth]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 10:37:25</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400105</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.f0b3645469fe4efb959224437b89fe90_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
The Bank of Korea’s Monetary Policy Board kept its key interest rate unchanged at 2.5 percent on Thursday, extending the freeze for a second consecutive month. The central bank faces a dilemma: while the economy is languishing at near-zero growth, household debt and housing prices remain stubborn risks that make an immediate rate cut politically and financially fraught.
Governor Rhee Chang-yong acknowledged the real estate factor, saying that “interest rates alone cannot control housing prices,” but also warning against fueling speculative expectations with premature liquidity.
Mortgage lending growth slowed in July compared with June, but the underlying risks remain. A sudden shift to rate cuts could reignite debt and housing bubbles. The record-high gap with U.S. interest rates only adds to the hesitation.
Yet the bigger problem is growth—or the lack of it.
Even after revising up its 2025 outlook from 0.8 to 0.9 percent, the BOK is still projecting the economy to barely expand. Consumer demand and investment remain weak, and new U.S. tariffs threaten to further sap momentum. Fiscal stimulus through a supplementary budget may help, but without monetary easing the effect will be muted. All eyes now turn to the U.S. Federal Reserve’s September 17 meeting, which could shape Seoul’s next move.
To boost domestic demand and restore growth, a rate cut is ultimately unavoidable. The continued uncertainty surrounding U.S. tariff negotiations also adds to the downward pressure on the economy, underscoring the need for lower rates.
But for fiscal and monetary policy to work in tandem, the government must first get household debt and housing prices under control. Only by swiftly introducing effective housing supply measures to calm market anxiety can the central bank take bolder steps toward monetary easing.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The Bank of Korea’s Monetary Policy Board kept its key interest rate unchanged at 2.5 percent on Thursday, extending the freeze for a second consecutive month. The central bank faces a dilemma: while ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400105</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400105</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.f0b3645469fe4efb959224437b89fe90_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405890]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
