<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390179</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570372</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 08:08:59</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean institutes court U.S. scientists amid brain drain fears]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 08:08:59</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.c43cc5faf49a497fb66774ac79fea2ec_P1.jpg' alt=' (KOSAC)'>
South Korean research institutions are ramping up efforts to recruit U.S.-based scientists, as deep funding cuts and policy shifts in Washington threaten to trigger a large-scale brain drain.
The talent push was a key undercurrent at the 2025 U.S.–Korea Conference on Science, Technology and Entrepreneurship (UKC), held last week at the Georgia Institute of Technology in Atlanta.
While the annual event serves as a networking hub for leading researchers from both countries, this year’s discussions carried a more somber tone, reflecting shared concerns over the future of science policy.
At a joint science and technology policy workshop hosted by Korea’s Institute of S&T Evaluation and Planning (KISTEP), the Korea Foundation for Science and Creativity (KOSAC), the Science and Technology Policy Institute (STEPI), and Georgia Tech, participants exchanged views on budgetary challenges and the need for resilient science policy.
Cassidy Sugimoto, chair of Georgia Tech’s School of Public Policy, warned that most scholars expect the U.S. science budget to drop by more than 50 percent next year.
“From an investment standpoint, it’s reasonable to say the U.S. will cede scientific leadership to China by year’s end,” she said.
Sugimoto argued that anti-science and anti-immigration policies, along with steep cuts, especially in international cooperation, could isolate U.S. research and accelerate the exodus of talent.
Survey data from Nature suggests the risk is real, with 75 percent of U.S. scientists saying they have considered leaving the country over Trump-era policy shifts.
Beyond policy talks, Korean institutions used the conference to deepen partnerships with U.S. counterparts.
Ajou University opened cooperation channels with Emory University, discussing faculty exchanges, joint research, and potential overseas research centers. Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology (UNIST) launched a nationwide U.S. recruitment tour targeting physician-scientists and leading experts in multiple fields.
“We’re looking for outstanding talent without any numerical limits,” said Bae Sung-chul, UNIST vice president for academic affairs.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean research institutions are ramping up efforts to recruit U.S.-based scientists, as deep funding cuts and policy shifts in Washington threaten to trigger a large-scale brain drain. The tale]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.c43cc5faf49a497fb66774ac79fea2ec_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (KOSAC)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390179]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
