<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388450</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566155</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:36:03</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea to expand incentives to spur regional consumption]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:36:03</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.fb040138c1ce4bcbadc0f067fe1acc08_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
The South Korean government plans to introduce measures to boost spending in non-capital regions, including broader voucher programs and the launch of a lottery that rewards regional purchases with gift certificates.
At the economic ministers’ meeting on Thursday, consumption revitalization outside the capital was a key agenda item. “After a prolonged slump, consumption is beginning to recover,” said Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Economy and Finance Koo Yoon-cheol. “To ensure this recovery continues, the government will maintain momentum through consumer coupons and large-scale promotional events every month until the end of the year.”
The focus on regional consumption stems from concerns over the uneven pace of recovery between the capital and other areas.
According to the Bank of Korea, Seoul’s consumer sentiment index rose by 10 points in April from the previous month, while the six major metropolitan cities recorded a six-point increase and other regions just five. The government aims to address this imbalance through targeted local incentives.
A central element of the initiative is the “consumer lottery” program.
Through October 9, consumers who spend more than 50,000 won ($36.10) using credit cards in non-capital regions will be automatically entered into the lottery. Ten first-prize winners will receive digital gift certificates worth 20 million won each, redeemable at traditional markets.
Participants can earn up to 10 entries in 50,000-won increments. Entry is also automatic through a reimbursement program that returns part of card spending in the form of traditional market gift certificates.
The cultural voucher program will expand to a total of 8.1 million vouchers. This includes 800,000 accommodation vouchers offering discounts of 30,000 won or 20,000 won depending on booking value, 1.6 million art exhibition vouchers, 500,000 performing arts vouchers, 4.5 million movie vouchers, and 700,000 sports facility vouchers.
For exhibitions and performances, residents in non-capital regions can receive up to 10 additional coupons, doubling the general limit.
Tourism incentives will be rolled out alongside these measures. During the fall travel campaign, tourist train fares will be discounted by up to 50 percent, domestic airline tickets by 20,000 won, and bus routes to depopulated areas by 30 percent. Travelers with a “digital tourism resident pass” will see their tourism, lodging, and dining voucher limit raised from 500,000 won to 1 million won. The pass, introduced to promote tourism in declining regions, provides discounts on accommodations, food, and local activities.
To further encourage consumption across the country, the government will promote sisterhood partnerships between non-capital municipalities and at least two central government agencies, public institutions, private companies, or local governments in the Seoul metropolitan area.
These partnerships will collaborate on joint purchases of local specialties and expanded tourism exchanges to foster sustainable local consumption.
The government also plans to leverage the weeklong Chinese National Day holiday in early October and the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit in Gyeongju later that month to attract foreign tourists. Starting with this month’s accommodation discount promotion, a series of large-scale consumption events will be held monthly, with the number of participating businesses expanded to record levels to amplify regional economic impact.
A Ministry of Finance official said that with overall consumption showing signs of recovery, these additional measures are intended to accelerate spending in areas still lagging behind the capital.
To maximize the stimulus effect, the government is also speeding up fiscal spending.
As of the end of July, 8.8 trillion won, or 74 percent, of the 11.7 trillion won first supplementary budget allocated in May had been executed, surpassing the target of 70 percent. Of the 20.6 trillion won second supplementary budget passed in early July, 11 trillion won, or 53.4 percent, had already been spent by the end of the month.
Deputy Prime Minister Koo added that the government is also preparing a new economic growth strategy.
“By selectively supporting high-impact innovation initiatives, the government will aim for tangible results in the short term,” Koo said.
The strategy will be finalized and announced later this month.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean government plans to introduce measures to boost spending in non-capital regions, including broader voucher programs and the launch of a lottery that rewards regional purchases with gi]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.fb040138c1ce4bcbadc0f067fe1acc08_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388450]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
