<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11403780</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>611173</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-27 09:51:12</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea Zinc to supply germanium to Lockheed Martin]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-27 09:51:12</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.2f0d727a904646909f313a8a42dd259d_P1.png' alt=' (Korea Zinc)'>
Korea Zinc Inc. has agreed to supply germanium to U.S. defense giant Lockheed Martin Corp., becoming the first South Korean producer of the strategic mineral.
The company said Tuesday it signed a memorandum of understanding with Lockheed Martin in Washington on Monday covering germanium supply, purchase, and broader cooperation on critical mineral supply chains.
The deal is viewed as the first private-sector initiative to deepen Korea-U.S. cooperation on strategic minerals following the recent summit between the two countries. Germanium is a key material for night-vision goggles, thermal imaging cameras, solar cells, and high-performance semiconductor devices, making it essential to the defense, aerospace, and semiconductor industries. Its role in infrared optics and satellite communications makes it particularly critical for contractors such as Lockheed Martin.
China’s move in August 2023 to impose export controls on germanium and gallium has intensified efforts among Western countries to diversify supply chains. With China producing more than 60 percent of the world’s germanium, reducing reliance on Chinese supply has become an urgent priority.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Korea Zinc Inc. has agreed to supply germanium to U.S. defense giant Lockheed Martin Corp., becoming the first South Korean producer of the strategic mineral. The company said Tuesday it signed a memo]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.2f0d727a904646909f313a8a42dd259d_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Korea Zinc)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11403780]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
