<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384353</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554085</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 07:18:37</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Matcha desserts capture young Korean consumers’ attention]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 07:18:37</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.db781464f6d942699c862e24bc3200f1_P1.jpg' alt=' (Lotte Shopping Co., Ltd.)'>
Matcha-based dessert shops are expanding in Korea as the finely ground green tea gains traction among younger consumers drawn to the wellness trend.
Industry sources said Sunday that sales at matcha specialty outlets in Lotte Department Store locations nationwide climbed about 15 percent in the first half of 2025 compared with a year earlier. The growth stands out given the overall decline in franchise café numbers and the intense competition in the dessert market. Market research firm The Business Research Company forecasts the global matcha market will expand 10.4 percent this year, rising from $3.84 billion in 2023 to $4.24 billion in 2024.
Lotte’s Jamsil branch opened Kyoto Perfect Matcha, a dessert café from Tsujiri, one of Japan’s leading matcha brands, in September 2024. It is the brand’s first location outside Japan. Other matcha-focused outlets such as Super Matcha and O’sulloc at Lotte Department Store’s major branches also reported visitor numbers in July 2025 that were up more than 30 percent from a year earlier.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Matcha-based dessert shops are expanding in Korea as the finely ground green tea gains traction among younger consumers drawn to the wellness trend. Industry sources said Sunday that sales at matcha s]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.db781464f6d942699c862e24bc3200f1_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Lotte Shopping Co., Ltd.)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384353]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
