<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397900</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593046</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 09:55:33</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Industry-academia-gov’t should collaborate for battery lead: KRICT]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 09:55:33</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.ec8ed2321f254132ac4fd0f053bccb78_P1.png' alt=' KRICT President Lee Young-kuk'>
South Korea’s industry, academia, and government should form a one-team strategy to take the lead in the secondary battery sector and catch up with China, according to Korea Research Institute of Chemical Technology (KRICT) President Lee Young-kuk.
“To catch up with China now, the industry, academia, and government research institutes must tear down barriers and unite,” Lee said in a recent interview with Maeil Business Newspaper. “We must form a one-team strategy that eliminates redundant national research and secures gap technologies … There is no time to waste.”
The Ministry of Science and ICT has been running the Global Top Strategic Research Group Project since 2024 under this very premise. Each research group receives tens of billions of won in annual R&D funding to drive major breakthroughs, with the key strategy being to break down silos among government-funded research institutes and unify industry, academia, and research.
KRICT oversees the most research groups among these types of institutes, with two in total - the Strategic Research Group on Carbon Resource Utilization for Climate Crisis Response and the Next-Generation Secondary Battery Innovation Strategic Research Group.
“After running the battery strategy group for about a year, I became convinced this model works,” Lee said.
The battery group includes Korea’s three major secondary battery makers - LG Energy Solution Ltd., Samsung SDI Co., and SK on Co. - as well as seven government-funded research institutes such as the Korea Institute of Science and Technology and the Korea Institute of Industrial Technology, with 69 organizations participating in total.
The group’s mission is critical: to restore Korea’s position as a global leader in the secondary battery industry. Korea previously surpassed Japan to achieve leading status, but the position has since gone to China, who has deployed substantial resources and workforce.
KRICT’s goal is to secure and commercialize next-generation batteries characterized by ultra-high energy density and lightweight design.
“The current commercial secondary battery technology is already about three years behind China’s,” Lee said. “Given China’s trillion-won budgets, it is very difficult to catch up and this is why we are targeting next-generation battery development instead.”
He added that with companies now actively joining, everyone is frankly sharing their situations and discussing strategies to help Korea regain the top position.
The National Distinguished Research system introduced in March 2025 gave the effort a further boost. This system allows government institutes to bypass salary restrictions and recruit top scholars with competitive treatment, enabling the battery group to recruit former LG Energy Solution President Kim Myung-hwan as its head.
“Under Kim’s leadership, we have built a powerful one-team system that moves as a single unit,” Lee said.
However, the future of the Global Top Strategic Research Group Project remains uncertain, with concerns that the project may fall victim to political reversal given that it was a flagship project under the previous Yoon Suk Yeol administration.
It is possible that no new budget will be allocated for 2026, and groups previously designated for funding could see reductions.
“We are currently working on overall budget allocation for next year,” an official from the science ministry said. “Discussions are still ongoing.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s industry, academia, and government should form a one-team strategy to take the lead in the secondary battery sector and catch up with China, according to Korea Research Institute of Chem]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.ec8ed2321f254132ac4fd0f053bccb78_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ KRICT President Lee Young-kuk]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397900]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
