<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11398259</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>594525</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 15:03:35</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hanssem relaunches ‘Four Season’ premium mattress line]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 15:03:35</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.949093ade2184837b099ec70b48721e2_P1.png' alt=' (Hanssem)'>
Hanssem said on Wednesday that it relaunched its premium mattress line “Hanssem Four Season” with a complete renewal of the lineup.
The home interior company expanded the use of its proprietary “Black T Spring” technology across all products. The Black T Spring, made from oil-tempered steel wire heat-treated above 1,000 degrees centigrade, provides excellent elasticity and durability.
Each mattress also incorporates a spring structure that combines “comfort zones” to gently absorb impact and “support zones” to provide firm support, which are arranged in diverse patterns for optimized performance.
The models are equipped with the “Clima System,” which is designed to maintain an optimal skin temperature of 28 to 31 degrees Celsius by absorbing heat in summer and releasing it in winter to ensure comfortable sleep.
Hanssem also updated the product design with lower saturation tones for a more sophisticated look, while rebranding the product identity from the Korean name to the English “Four Season.”
A company official said, “We plan to strengthen the value of the Four Season mattress as a premium product that provides the best sleep environment and will continue to introduce products that combine advanced technology with refined design.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hanssem said on Wednesday that it relaunched its premium mattress line “Hanssem Four Season” with a complete renewal of the lineup. The home interior company expanded the use of its proprietary “Black]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.949093ade2184837b099ec70b48721e2_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hanssem)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11398259]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
