<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11392846</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>578582</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-13 14:55:37</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KEPCO’s H1 OP rises 131% on higher electricity sales]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-13 14:55:37</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.c085678dac744235ac46d6e7449338cb_P1.jpg' alt=' KEPCO CI'>
South Korea’s state utility Korea Electric Power Corp. (KEPCO) announced on Tuesday that its operating profit in the first half of 2025 soared 131 percent from the same period a year ago.
According to KEPCO, its sales stood at 46.17 trillion won ($33.38 billion) in the first six months of the year. Its operating profit reached 5.89 trillion won, up 131 percent from last year.
The surge is attributed to higher electricity sales revenue following increases in industrial electricity rates.
KEPCO’s electricity sales volume fell slightly by 0.05 percent in the first half from a year earlier, but the average unit selling price rose 5.7 percent year-on-year, boosting electricity sales revenue by 2.45 trillion won.
KEPCO achieved eight consecutive quarters of profitability until the second quarter of 2025. Its financial structure, however, still needs to be improved, analysts noted.
Its accumulated operating losses since 2021 have totaled 28.8 trillion won and its total debt has topped 200 trillion won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s state utility Korea Electric Power Corp. (KEPCO) announced on Tuesday that its operating profit in the first half of 2025 soared 131 percent from the same period a year ago. According to]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.c085678dac744235ac46d6e7449338cb_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ KEPCO CI]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11392846]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
