<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387325</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>562914</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 09:37:11</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KCC Glass’ Q2 revenue down 0.3% on construction slump]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 09:37:11</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.d1bf6bebbd7e496a878a6b9c974dec16_P1.jpg' alt=' (KCC Glass)'>
South Korea’s KCC Glass Corp. announced on Wednesday that its revenue for the second quarter of 2025 was tentatively tallied at 512.9 billion won ($370.22 million), down 0.3 percent from the same period a year ago.
The company swung to an operating loss of 35.4 billion won during the April-June period and a net loss of 35.3 billion won during the same period.
KCC Glass noted that the prolonged slump in the construction industry led to a decline in architectural glass prices, while a drop in the exchange rate also impacted its performance.
“Price competition intensified due to low-cost imported glass, and the fall in glass prices led to an increase in inventory valuation loss provisions for our glass stock,” a company official said. “Once glass prices normalize, we expect it will contribute to a reduction in cost of goods sold.”
Looking ahead, KCC Glass plans to strengthen its sales and promotional efforts for high-value-added products such as high-insulation coated glass, particularly targeting redevelopment project sites.
The company also plans to diversify its business portfolio through the development of new technologies, including smart glass and glass substrates for semiconductor packaging.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s KCC Glass Corp. announced on Wednesday that its revenue for the second quarter of 2025 was tentatively tallied at 512.9 billion won ($370.22 million), down 0.3 percent from the same peri]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.d1bf6bebbd7e496a878a6b9c974dec16_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (KCC Glass)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387325]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
