<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11399110</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>596861</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-21 11:11:11</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean Air, LIG Nex1 bid for $1.3 bn electronic warfare aircraft project]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-21 11:11:11</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.a7ca410501f74e209ed3fb97b1612fe9_P1.png' alt=' (Korean Air)'>
Korean Air has teamed up with LIG Nex1 to compete for the Republic of Korea Air Force’s Block-I electronic warfare aircraft development program.
The carrier said Thursday that the duo formed a consortium and will submit their proposal in early September 2025. Worth 1.78 trillion won ($1.31 billion), the project aims to develop a large special mission aircraft capable of collecting and analyzing threat signals from neighboring countries as well as conducting electronic attacks to paralyze both enemy air defense networks and wireless command systems during wartime.
If selected as the system integrator, Korean Air would be responsible for system integration and aircraft modification and production while LIG Nex1 would handle system development and the production and installation of electronic warfare equipment. The program will proceed with modifications of foreign-made mid-sized civilian aircraft to mount the necessary mission equipment.
The project is considered highly challenging, as only the U.S. Air Force has undertaken a comparable program with its next-generation EA-37B electronic warfare aircraft. Korean Air and LIG Nex1 are seen as the only domestic companies capable of developing such a platform.
Korean Air has built capabilities in modifying and producing civilian aircraft for military use over the past five decades, carrying out projects such as the P-3C maritime patrol aircraft upgrade and the first Baekdu reconnaissance program alongside securing flight safety certification for converted aircraft. The company operates more than 100 special mission experts across its Busan Tech Center and Daejeon R&D Center, along with personnel in UAVs, space launch vehicles, and advanced air mobility. It also manages 710,000 square meters of government-certified hangar space, having delivered more than 5,500 aircraft to date that includes 3,700 for U.S. forces across the Pacific.
For its part, LIG Nex1 successfully developed electronic warfare equipment for key national defense programs, including the KF-21 fighter, next-generation naval vessels, submarines, and the new Baekdu reconnaissance aircraft.
“This project is expected to enhance our military’s electronic spectrum warfare capabilities. Based on our partnership with LIG Nex1, we will also seek to expand into manned and unmanned special mission aircraft and actively explore opportunities in the global defense market,” a Korean Air official said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Korean Air has teamed up with LIG Nex1 to compete for the Republic of Korea Air Force’s Block-I electronic warfare aircraft development program. The carrier said Thursday that the duo formed a consort]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.a7ca410501f74e209ed3fb97b1612fe9_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Korean Air)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11399110]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
