<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402919</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>608663</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-26 11:18:21</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Businesses concerned about corporate governance risks after law revision]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-26 11:18:21</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.76086787b665425aa05fe7def0a2148b_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
South Korea’s business community is raising concerns about intensifying risks to management control after the country’s National Assembly passed the second amendment to the Commercial Act on Monday.
The revision includes introducing cumulative voting and expanding the separate election of audit committee members.
Companies fear that exposure to hostile takeovers by hedge funds and other speculative capital could derail their long-term investment plans and even threaten their survival.
A recent study by Leaders Index, a corporate analysis institute, found that among 130 listed companies affiliated with the country’s top 50 business groups by assets, about 37.8 percent of friendly stakes may lose their voting rights if both the “3 percent rule” introduced in the first amendment and the cumulative voting/separate audit committee election rules in the second amendment were applied simultaneously.
For example, SeAH Group holds 67.8 percent in friendly stakes on average, but would lose 64.8 percent of its voting rights under the 3 percent rule.
Hankook & Company Group and Lotte Group are also projected to lose 57.0 percent and 55.3 percent of voting rights, respectively.
On the other hand, the National Pension Service (NPS) holds more than 5 percent stakes in 74 of the surveyed 130 companies (56.9 percent), meaning it would be able to exercise voting rights on par with controlling families in audit committee elections.
This raises the likelihood that the NPS could hold the “casting vote” in future shareholders’ meetings.
A recent survey by the Korea Chamber of Commerce and Industry (KCCI) of 300 listed firms also showed that 74 percent of respondents believed mandatory cumulative voting combined with expanded separate election of audit committee members would pose a threat to their management control.
Business lobby groups have expressed regret over the passage of the amendment and urged follow-up legislation to minimize side effects such as heightened management uncertainty and increased litigation risk.
Eight major business groups, including the Federation of Korean Industries (FKI), the Korea Chamber of Commerce and Industry (KCCI), the Korea Enterprises Federation (KEF), the Korea Federation of SMEs (KBIZ), issued a joint statement calling for governance safeguards on Monday.
“It is urgent to establish management control defense mechanisms in line with global standards to ensure corporate activities free from the threats of speculative capital,” the statement said.
It also emphasized the need to codify the “principle of managerial discretion” so that companies can make bold decisions for the future; rationally reform the crime of breach of trust; and overhaul economic criminal laws as well as differentiated regulations and incentives by company size, to allow companies to focus on innovation and growth.
The passage of the second amendment to the Commercial Act also fueled partisan conflict.
“The ruling Democratic Party will continue reforms without pause to improve people’s lives,” its leader Jung Chung-rae said in a post on Facebook. “Maximum reform means maximum livelihood.”
The party’s floor leader Kim Byung-kee added: “We hope this amendment will help our country move away from excessive reliance on real estate and foster a healthy market ecosystem where companies and shareholders grow together. We will also swiftly review rational reforms of criminal and civil liabilities, including breach of trust.”
The main opposition People Power Party, however, strongly pushed back.
Its interim leader Song Eon-seog asserted during a general meeting of lawmakers: “If President Lee Jae-myung truly cares for the people, he must exercise his veto.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s business community is raising concerns about intensifying risks to management control after the country’s National Assembly passed the second amendment to the Commercial Act on Monday. T]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.76086787b665425aa05fe7def0a2148b_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402919]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
