<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11396867</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>590218</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-19 10:49:40</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Naver eyes control of Dunamu’s unlisted stock trading platform]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-19 10:49:40</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.9eea3cbd327745d78aa8f387f56b983d_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
South Korea’s platform giant Naver Corp. is planning an unlisted acquisition of Stockplus, a subsidiary of Dunamu Inc., operator of the country’s largest cryptocurrency platform Upbit.
Naver’s move is seen as an attempt to strengthen its financial services by acquiring an unlisted stock trading platform, given its status behind its local rival Kakao Corp., which already owns a securities company.
According to sources from the investment banking (IB) and information technology (IT) industries on Monday, Naver and Dunamu are in talks over the sale of unlisted shares of Stockplus.
The target is the full stake that Dunamu has held since spinning off the company on July 1, 2025.
Discussions cover scenarios in which Naver acquires the entire stake in consortium with securities firms, as well as alternatives where Dunamu retains a partial stake, sources said.
Dunamu initially planned to apply for a brokerage license under the Financial Services Commission’s upcoming system for exclusive unlisted stock trading platforms.
However, the plan hit a setback when the Korea Financial Intelligence Unit (KoFIU) imposed a partial business suspension on Dunamu in February 2025 for violating the Act on Reporting and Using Specified Financial Transaction Information.
This raised the possibility that regulators would disallow Dunamu from remaining the largest shareholder of Stockplus.
As a result, Dunamu has been seeking other investors.
Through Stockplus, Naver aims to build a “financial super app” by adding a direct stock investment platform to its existing suite of services around Naver Pay, including simple payments, money transfers, insurance comparison, and investment information.
Naver and Dunamu said “nothing has been decided yet.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s platform giant Naver Corp. is planning an unlisted acquisition of Stockplus, a subsidiary of Dunamu Inc., operator of the country’s largest cryptocurrency platform Upbit. Naver’s move is]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.9eea3cbd327745d78aa8f387f56b983d_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11396867]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
