<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385245</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>556895</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 07:43:31</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Samsung, Apple ready for new smartphone releases in Sept.]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 07:43:31</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.4aa259a2d90548f3a264b940819f5385_P1.jpg' alt=' (Samsung Electronics)'>
Samsung Electronics Co. and Apple Inc. are set to go head-to-head in September 2025 as both prepare to release new smartphones.
According to foreign media outlets and industry sources on Monday, Samsung Electronics will launch the Galaxy S25 FE on September 19, more than a month earlier than its typical FE release schedule.
The FE model distills key features from the premium Galaxy S25 lineup into a more affordable package, targeting price-sensitive consumers who still want flagship-level performance.
Apple, meanwhile, is expected to unveil its iPhone 17 series at a media event on September 10 or 11, with sales beginning September 19 in major markets including the U.S.
The new lineup is likely to feature a 24-megapixel front camera across all models, a next-generation A19 chip, and up to 12GB of RAM for higher-end variants.
The iPhone 17 is expected to come in five colors: black, white, grey, dark blue, and orange. A slight price increase over the iPhone 16 series is also anticipated amid inflationary pressures and evolving tariff policies.
Currently in the U.S., the iPhone 16 series is priced at $799 for the iPhone 16, $899 for the iPhone 16 Plus, $999 for the iPhone 16 Pro, and $1,199 for the iPhone 16 Pro Max.
Apple has kept the base model iPhone price unchanged since 2019, but a slight adjustment is expected in 2025 due to factors such as U.S. President Donald Trump’s tariff policies.
Industry experts predict that this September, while Samsung will target the value-for-money segment to lead the budget-conscious market, Apple will go head-to-head by leveraging its premium brand value to dominate the high-end market.
However, some argue that a direct competition between Samsung’s FE series and Apple’s iPhone17 series is unlikely.
This is because the FE series is a cost-effective model that offers some flagship features at a reasonable price, making it distinct from Apple’s premium strategy in terms of performance and brand power.
“The FE series may contribute to expanding market share to some extent, but it is difficult to view it as a direct competitor capable of driving the premium market like Apple’s iPhone 17,” said an industry insider. “Samsung’s FE series targets price-conscious consumers, whereas the iPhone 17 is positioned at the top of the lineup in both price and specs, meaning the two companies are targeting different markets.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics Co. and Apple Inc. are set to go head-to-head in September 2025 as both prepare to release new smartphones. According to foreign media outlets and industry sources on Monday, Samsu]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.4aa259a2d90548f3a264b940819f5385_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Samsung Electronics)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385245]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
