<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402000</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>605635</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-25 11:28:07</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[AI-driven skin diagnostics, consulting services widen K-beauty’s lead]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-25 11:28:07</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.c9224dc02de34c98a9e691ab6c4cfe67_P1.png' alt=' (LG Household &amp; Health Care)'>
K-beauty is expanding beyond cosmetics sales into artificial intelligence (AI)-based skin diagnostics and personalized consulting services, marking a new phase of growth.
Companies are not only developing their own services but also collaborating with major distribution channels to introduce innovative offerings.
CJ Olive Young Corp. plans to install self-diagnosis devices at 100 stores nationwide by the end of the year. The devices measure skin and scalp types as well as personal color. The retailer has also introduced package-type services designed to guide customers from experience-based testing to actual product purchases.
Starting with its flagship Olive Young N Seongsu location, the company has deployed professional beauty consultants at three stores, including Central Gangnam Town and Beomgye Town, to provide skin, scalp, and personal color diagnostics.
Since the launch, over 10,000 customers used the service within just two weeks at the Central Gangnam Town store.
Amorepacific Corp. has expanded customized beauty services at four locations, including Seongsu and Yongsan. Since their rollout, sales at these stores have risen between 63 percent and 977 percent, respectively.
The Hera Silky Stay Custom Match service, which enables on-the-spot ordering and manufacturing, has drawn an average of 1,500 monthly users.
Word of mouth among global customers has also driven foreign visitors to account for 85 percent of users. Amorepacific’s AI-powered Skin Note service on its Amore Mall platform has conducted more than 160,000 diagnoses since launching in January last year.
LG Household & Health Care Ltd. is also drawing attention with its generative AI-based skin diagnostic solution.
Customers take a facial photo, which is then analyzed by AI to categorize them into one of 16 skin types and recommend tailored care methods and products.
In partnership with LG AI Research, the company plans to launch high-performance ingredient-based cosmetics from next year, with candidate substances identified by the Exaone Discovery AI model in just a single day.
Retailers are also rolling out advanced services in collaboration with beauty experts.
Shinsegae Department Store opened an experiential beauty zone at its Chicor Gangnam Station store in June.
Services include AI-based scalp diagnosis for customized shampoo serum production, as well as personalized makeup consultations by professional artists.
According to the company, 20 to 25 teams use the services daily, with foreign customers accounting for 60 to 70 percent. Demonstrations of K-idol makeup have especially attracted interest, boosting related product sales.
Convenience stores are also joining the AI beauty trend.
GS25 has installed an AI Beauty Device at its New Annyeong Insadong branch, frequented by foreign tourists, offering trial services for 2,000 won ($1.45). The company plans to expand the service to 10 stores this year.
The device scans skin, eyes, and lips to analyze brightness, saturation, and color temperature, providing personalized color recommendations. It also performs detailed facial shape analysis to suggest tailored makeup, hairstyles, and jewelry styling options.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[K-beauty is expanding beyond cosmetics sales into artificial intelligence (AI)-based skin diagnostics and personalized consulting services, marking a new phase of growth. Companies are not only develo]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.c9224dc02de34c98a9e691ab6c4cfe67_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (LG Household &amp; Health Care)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402000]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
