<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11386361</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>560412</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-06 10:37:33</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[EcoPro BM climbs on strong Q2 results, upbeat outlook]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-06 10:37:33</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-06 16:29:23</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.8c702693be9746b2a4eb3ae926e4a144_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
EcoPro BM Co.’s shares rose in early trading on Wednesday after several brokerage houses raised their target prices, citing strong second-quarter 2025 earnings and expectations of a market recovery.
According to the Korea Exchange, the stock was trading at 128,300 won ($92.30) on the Kosdaq as of 9:12 a.m., up 3.05 percent from the previous session.
The rally followed the company’s earnings release on Tuesday, which prompted multiple analysts to revise their forecasts, with EcoPro BM posting consolidated sales of 779.7 billion won and operating profit of 49 billion won for the second quarter of 2025. While sales fell 3.7 percent from a year earlier, operating profit surged 1,159 percent.
Daol Investment & Securities Co. upgraded its rating on the stock from “Hold” to “Buy” and raised its target price from 105,000 won to 160,000 won. “The second-quarter results confirmed the sector had reached its trough. The sales decline appears to have ended, and earnings in the energy storage system segment are starting to recover rapidly,” analyst Yoo Ji-woong said.
NH Investment & Securities Co. lifted its target price by 14 percent to 153,000 won from 134,000 won, citing recent moves toward structural reforms in lithium supply that could stabilize selling prices. This led the firm to raise its mid- to long-term earnings outlook by 5 to 6 percent.
Kiwoom Securities Co. increased its target price from 120,000 won to 140,000 won. Analyst Kwon Joon-soo said the company is likely to remain profitable for the time being, noting that higher valuation multiples in the broader secondary battery sector were factored into the revision.
However, Kwon cautioned that the core business is still expected to post losses, with uncertainty over European electric vehicle demand from key customers likely to persist in the second half of the year. Kwon maintained an “Outperform” rating.
In other market news, semiconductor and pharmaceutical shares fell after U.S. President Donald Trump signaled additional tariffs on both sectors.
Samsung Electronics Co. shares were down 1.29 percent at 67,000 won as of 9:09 a.m., dropping below the 70,000-won level. For their part, SK hynix Inc.’s shares dropped 1.61 percent to 259,250 won, slipping under the 260,000-won mark.
Pharmaceutical stocks were also lower, with Samsung Biologics Co. down 1.62 percent, Celltrion Inc. down 0.90 percent, and Yuhan Corp. down 1.39 percent.
In an interview with CNBC, Trump said he plans to announce additional product-specific tariffs “next week or so,” naming semiconductors and pharmaceuticals as possible targets. For pharmaceuticals, he said initial tariffs would be “small,” but could rise to 150 percent within 12 to 18 months and then to 250 percent thereafter.
Industry observers warn that, as semiconductors are a key Korean export to the United States, such tariffs could further pressure the country’s trade position.
EcoPro BM shares closed at 125,900 won, Samsung Electronics shares closed at 68,800 won, and SK hynix shares closed at 258,500 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[EcoPro BM Co.’s shares rose in early trading on Wednesday after several brokerage houses raised their target prices, citing strong second-quarter 2025 earnings and expectations of a market recovery. A]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.8c702693be9746b2a4eb3ae926e4a144_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11386361]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
