<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397899</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593048</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 09:55:32</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KASBA conference focuses on AI management innovation]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 09:55:32</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.a766d3db4260416d87f93ac4a81f47b6_P1.png' alt=' (Han Joo-hyung)'>
South Korean scholars and business leaders gathered in Ulsan this week to explore management innovation in the era of artificial intelligence (AI).
The 27th Korean Academic Society of Business Administration (KASBA) Convergence Conference opened on Tuesday under the theme “Value-Up Management Innovation in the AI Era.” Co-hosted by Maeil Business Newspaper, the event drew figures including KASBA President Yang Hee-dong, Ulsan Mayor Kim Doo-gyeom, Maeil Business CEO Son Hyun-duk, Hana Financial Group Chairman Ham Young-joo, and former LG Energy Solution Vice Chairman Kwon Young-soo.
Participants stressed that Korea’s next economic leap will depend on balancing investment in AI, data, and people. In his opening remarks, Yang said the conference would serve as a platform to seek “mega-management solutions” for the AI era and to discuss strategies for corporate growth and economic development. “We aim to share KASBA’s core visions of globalization, leadership, technological innovation, and relationship-building, as well as help Ulsan and the nation become one of the world’s top three AI powerhouses,” he said.
In a congratulatory address, Maeil Business Newspaper’s Son emphasized the importance of “linking AI with domain expertise across industries.” He expressed hope that the conference would be a starting point for accelerating AI transformation among Korean companies, underscoring the need for close collaboration between academia and industry.
The conference also placed Ulsan in the spotlight as the city seeks to redefine itself as an “AI capital” after decades of growth built on heavy process industries. “Ulsan, which has long contributed to national development as Korea’s industrial capital, is now ready for the future. Today, we proclaim Ulsan as the capital of the AI era and as a city that will lead future industries,” the city’s mayor Kim said in his welcome speech.
The city has anchored national industries such as shipbuilding, automobiles, and petrochemicals since the Ulsan Mipo National Industrial Complex was designated as Korea’s first industrial zone in 1962, alongside having the highest per capita GDP in Korea outside of Seoul.
The city is now adding new growth engines such as AI, hydrogen, future mobility, and secondary batteries, building on its traditional strengths in shipbuilding, autos, and petrochemicals, Kim noted.
In a keynote speech, former LG Energy Solution vice chairman Kwon emphasized that people remain the most vital asset in the AI era. “Strategy and talent ultimately depend on winning people’s hearts. The most important duty of a CEO is to earn their employees’ trust,” he said, pointing to listening, empathy, and coaching as essential leadership qualities.
Recalling his experience working with Apple, Kwon said Steve Jobs often stayed silent in meetings, choosing instead to listen closely. “Employees felt respected simply by being heard. That was the driving force behind Apple’s creativity and innovation.” He concluded, “Strategy, finance, and technology are all important, but it is people who move companies. In the AI era, what matters even more than AI is human-centered leadership.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean scholars and business leaders gathered in Ulsan this week to explore management innovation in the era of artificial intelligence (AI). The 27th Korean Academic Society of Business Adminis]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.a766d3db4260416d87f93ac4a81f47b6_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Han Joo-hyung)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397899]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
