<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388486</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566224</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:56:20</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KT&G sees growth in sales, OP for third straight quarter in Q2]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:56:20</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.847ee1ff06b6409a9cfbe3a296e3c0d4_P1.jpg' alt=' (KT&amp;G)'>
South Korea‘s tobacco company KT&G Corp has achieved growth in sales and operating profit for three consecutive quarters since the fourth quarter of 2024. The growth is driven by strong overseas tobacco sales and a rebound in its next-generation products (NGP) business.
KT&G announced on Thursday that its second-quarter sales reached 1.5 trillion won ($1.08 billion), up 8.7 percent from the same period a year ago. Its operating profit also rose 8.6 percent to 349.8 billion won.
The tobacco business remained the main growth engine, posting sales of 1.09 trillion won, up 10 percent year-on-year. Its operating profit reached 321.8 billion won, up 1.6 percent.
Overseas cigarette sales achieved triple growth – increases in sales, operating profit, and sales volume – for the fifth consecutive quarter.
Sales from international markets jumped 30.6 percent to 469 billion won, with shipments rising 9.1 percent to a record 16.7 billion cigarettes.
Excluding a one-off reversal of bad debt provisions from last year, adjusted operating profit surged 51.1 percent, securing a strong growth momentum.
Since CEO Bang Kyung-man took office last year, KT&G’s top priorities – the global, locally integrated value chain strategy and transition to the CIC system – have now produced tangible results, insiders noted.
In major regions such as Asia-Pacific, Central Asia, and Latin America, the strategy of launching competitive new products centered on the ESSE brand, expanding the share of premium products through strengthened brand power, and raising sales prices proved effective.
In its domestic NGP unit, sales of its lil AIBLE heated tobacco sticks rose, with the brand holding a 45.8 percent market share in the first half. Overseas stick shipments increased 4.2 percent to 2.2 billion units.
KT&G’s board of directors, in the meantime, resolved to raise its interim dividend to 1,400 won per share, up by 200 won from last year.
The company also plans to consider further dividend increases in line with future stock price and profit growth.
Starting Friday, KT&G will repurchase and cancel treasury shares worth about 300 billion won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea‘s tobacco company KT&G Corp has achieved growth in sales and operating profit for three consecutive quarters since the fourth quarter of 2024. The growth is driven by strong overseas tobac]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.847ee1ff06b6409a9cfbe3a296e3c0d4_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (KT&amp;G)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388486]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
