<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387306</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>562866</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 09:25:49</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Balance of fixed deposits, savings surge in Korea in July]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 09:25:49</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.e33b20deedaa4144b0e9c0510b96c9cc_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
The total balance of fixed deposits and savings at South Korea’s five major commercial banks saw a sharp increase in July.
In particular, corporate participation in fixed deposits rose across all banks. This is seen as a result of banks actively attracting fixed deposits following the outflow of low-interest funds in June – typically a period of tax payments due to the half-year end.
According to multiple sources from the financial sector on Wednesday, the combined balance of fixed deposits at Korea’s five banks reached 944.86 trillion won (681.3 billion) at the end of July, up about 13 trillion won from the end of June.
The five banks are KB Kookmin Bank, Shinhan Bank, Hana Bank, Woori Bank, and NH Nonghyup Bank Co.
Since the end of last year, time deposits have grown by about 18 trillion won in just seven months.
While the total volume of savings deposits is smaller, the growth rate is steeper.
Since February, savings deposits have steadily increased, rising from 38 trillion won in January to 43 trillion won in July – a 9 percent jump in six months.
Financial industry experts noted multiple factors have contributed to this unusual growth in deposits amid expectations of a base rate cut.
One major factor is a defensive move against the volatility of low-cost deposits such as demand deposits and money market deposit accounts, whose fluctuations are becoming increasingly difficult to predict.
As it becomes harder to rely on these low-cost funds, banks are focusing more on securing fixed deposits and savings.
The gap between the highest and lowest levels of low-cost deposits reached 57 trillion won last year, and it has already hit 43 trillion won this year.
“Due to expected outflows of low-interest funds in July – such as VAT payments, IPOs, and public institution budget executions – we actively attracted corporate fixed deposits to secure funds in advance, leading to the increased balance,” said an official from a bank.
Another key variable is the increase in the deposit protection limit from 50 million won to 100 million won per account starting in September.
The change is prompting both commercial and second-tier financial institutions to compete more aggressively for deposits, especially from customers looking to diversify and secure higher insured coverage.
Some savings banks have already moved to attract funds by raising interest rates, even against the broader trend of falling base rates.
Major lenders have responded with high-profile promotions.
Shinhan Bank, for example, launched a promotional product, offering a maximum interest rate of 7.7 percent, which sold out 300,000 accounts.
Hana Bank and Woori Bank also released special deposit products last month, offering up to 8.15 percent interest rates timed with Liberation Day on August 15.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The total balance of fixed deposits and savings at South Korea’s five major commercial banks saw a sharp increase in July. In particular, corporate participation in fixed deposits rose across all bank]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.e33b20deedaa4144b0e9c0510b96c9cc_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387306]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
