<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385319</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>557125</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 09:18:18</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Taihan grabs turnkey contract for Anma offshore wind subsea cables]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 09:18:18</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.20eed5ab5f1449ab91767cd60531c146_P1.png' alt=' (Taihan Cable &amp; Solution)'>
Taihan Cable & Solution Co. has won a 181.6 billion won ($132.6 million) turnkey contract to supply subsea cables for South Korea’s largest offshore wind project, the company announced on Monday.
Under the contract, Taihan will be responsible for the end-to-end delivery of internal network subsea cables for the Anma Offshore Wind Farm project, including design, manufacturing, transportation, and installation through the end of 2028.
The deal is seen as further validation of the company’s technological capabilities across the full subsea cable value chain.
Located off the western coast of Anma Island in Yeonggwang County, South Jeolla Province, the Anma Offshore Wind Farm will have a generation capacity of 532 megawatts and cover a site area of 83.9 million square meters.
Once completed, the wind farm is expected to generate 1,400 GWh of electricity annually—enough to power about 1.4 million people.
The internal network of subsea cables that Taihan will supply will be used to connect wind turbines to each other and offshore substations.
With the scaling up of wind farms, the volume of cable required also increases. For the Anma project, Taihan will supply more than 100 kilometers of subsea cables.
Production will take place at Taihan’s new Subsea Cable Plant No. 1 in Dangjin, South Chungcheong Province, which was completed in June. For the installation phase, the company’s own cable-laying vessel (CLV), the PALOS, will be deployed.
To meet growing global and domestic demand for subsea cables, Taihan is also expanding its infrastructure.
Following the completion of its first subsea cable plant, the company plans to break ground on Subsea Cable Plant No. 2 within this year, targeting full operation by 2027.
“Building on our subsea cable expertise developed since 2009, we’re now delivering tangible results in Korea’s offshore wind market,” a company official said. “We aim to further strengthen our turnkey capabilities to support major projects like the West Coast Energy Expressway and enhance our export competitiveness in the global offshore wind sector.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Taihan Cable & Solution Co. has won a 181.6 billion won ($132.6 million) turnkey contract to supply subsea cables for South Korea’s largest offshore wind project, the company announced on Monday. Unde]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.20eed5ab5f1449ab91767cd60531c146_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Taihan Cable &amp; Solution)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385319]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
