<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11386269</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>560042</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-06 09:29:46</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Naver acquires Spain’s C2C platform Wallapop]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-06 09:29:46</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.046a6d5a50c94ef49a660c18c1dfb726_P1.jpg' alt=' (Naver)'>
Naver Corp. has acquired a controlling stake in Wallapop, Spain’s largest consumer-to-consumer (C2C) platform, as part of its broader strategy to secure a foothold for business expansion in Europe.
The South Korean tech giant announced Monday that it has invested 377 million euros ($436 million) to acquire an additional 70.5 percent stake in Wallapop, effectively taking over the company.
Founded in 2013, Wallapop has over 19 million monthly active users and facilitates peer-to-peer transactions in everything from household goods and electronics to automobiles.
The platform has expanded into Southern Europe, including Italy and Portugal, while continuing to grow steadily thanks to its user-friendly service.
Since 2018, former eBay executive Rob Cassedy has served as CEO.
Naver first began investing in Wallapop in 2021, acquiring a 29.5 percent stake through two rounds totaling 255 billion won. The companies have explored collaboration in areas such as technology integration, but recently concluded that deeper cooperation would require a stronger strategic alignment. The acquisition reflects their mutual decision to formalize that partnership.
Since 2016, Naver has expanded its European presence through indirect investments via Korelya Capital, a Paris-based venture capital firm founded by former French Minister for Digital Economy Fleur Pellerin.
With this acquisition, Naver aims to integrate its technologies—including search, advertising, payments, and AI—into Wallapop to accelerate its European operations.
Naver also operates C2C platforms such as Poshmark, KREAM, and SODA in markets like North America, Korea, and Japan.
“Since Naver’s initial investment, we’ve explored many ways to create synergy,” said Cassedy. “We’ve come to see Naver as the ideal partner to help Wallapop grow, given its technological capabilities and business expertise as one of Korea’s leading internet companies.”
Naver CEO Choi Soo-yeon added, “This acquisition will help us better understand European users, especially in Spain, while also enhancing the diversity of our data, which is a key competitive edge in the AI ecosystem.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Naver Corp. has acquired a controlling stake in Wallapop, Spain’s largest consumer-to-consumer (C2C) platform, as part of its broader strategy to secure a foothold for business expansion in Europe. Th]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.046a6d5a50c94ef49a660c18c1dfb726_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Naver)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11386269]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
