<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385504</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>557755</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 11:06:17</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[CJ CheilJedang hosts Korean cooking competition in Indonesia]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 11:06:17</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.7b9e6fd2f4d045db97895d179375f3f2_P1.jpg' alt=' (CJ CheilJedang)'>
CJ CheilJedang Corp. announced Tuesday that it hosted the Bibigo × Sages Young Chef Competition in collaboration with Akademi Sages, a leading culinary school in Indonesia, aiming to discover emerging chefs specializing in Korean cuisine.
The event was part of CJ’s global K-food chef development platform, Cuisine K, which sponsored the competition exclusively.
The contest began with online preliminary rounds in May, attracting around 110 young Indonesian chefs, of whom 36 advanced to the semifinals and finals held on July 30–31 at Sages in Surabaya, Indonesia.
Participants showcased creative dishes using popular Korean food products in Indonesia, such as Bibigo dumplings, seaweed, gochujang, and doenjang.
The grand prize was awarded to Michael Khen Samuel, a chef from Sages, who elevated the flavor of Bibigo dumplings with the umami of doenjang, impressing the judges with a dish that blended Korean authenticity with Indonesian culinary appeal.
The runner-up was Lauw Louise Garcia J, a chef from the Sahid Tourism Institute.
Both the winner and runner-up received prize money, trophies, and will be invited to Korea for further training.
The judging panel included Kang Seok-min, R&D head & head chef of CJ Foods Indonesia, Jang Jin-beom, head chef at Jinjoo’s Fine Dining in Jakarta, and Jung Chan-hyuk, owner and head chef of Jung Chan Dining in Bandung.
CJ CheilJedang said it will continue to create opportunities to discover and nurture global talent in Korean cuisine.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[CJ CheilJedang Corp. announced Tuesday that it hosted the Bibigo × Sages Young Chef Competition in collaboration with Akademi Sages, a leading culinary school in Indonesia, aiming to discover emerging]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.7b9e6fd2f4d045db97895d179375f3f2_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (CJ CheilJedang)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385504]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
