<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387460</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>563492</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 11:16:58</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea’s current account surplus hits all-time high on strong chip exports]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 11:16:58</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.33fd4a4c5f0b4614be444421899fb246_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korea’s current account surplus reached an all-time high of $14.27 billion in June, thanks to robust exports of semiconductors and increased dividend income.
According to data released by the Bank of Korea (BOK) on Thursday, the country’s current account surplus stood at $14.27 billion in June, up from $10.14 billion in the previous month and $13.1 billion from the same period a year ago.
This is the largest monthly figure on record and the third-longest surplus streak since 2000 at 26 consecutive months.
The cumulative surplus for the first six months of 2025 totaled $49.37 billion, up about $9.2 billion from $40.16 billion in the same period a year ago.
The country’s goods account surplus in June was $13.16 billion, up $2.5 billion from $10.66 billion in May, data showed. It is the third-largest on record after $14.52 billion in September 2017 and $13.32 billion in March 2016.
Korea’s exports stood at $60.37 billion in June, up 2.3 percent from a year earlier, driven by continued strength in information technology (IT) items such as semiconductors and higher exports of non-IT goods such as pharmaceuticals.
In particular, customs-cleared exports of computer peripherals (up 13.6 percent), semiconductors (up 11.3 percent), and pharmaceuticals (up 51.8 percent) showed growth.
Exports of passenger cars, on the other hand, fell 0.3 percent, petroleum products 0.9 percent, and steel products 2.8 percent.
By region, exports to the European Union rose 14.7 percent and to Southeast Asia 6 percent, while those to the United States fell 0.5 percent and China declined 2.7 percent.
Imports also rose in June for the first time in three months, reaching $47.21 billion, but the year-on-year growth rate was only 0.7 percent.
Imports of capital goods rose 14.8 percent, led by semiconductor manufacturing equipment (up 38.8 percent) and semiconductors (up 22.7 percent), while those of consumer goods increased 7.6 percent, with direct consumer products up 10.9 percent and passenger cars up 7.3 percent.
Raw materials imports, on the other hand, fell 6.4 percent due to lower energy prices, with petroleum products down 33.1 percent, coal down 25.9 percent, and crude oil down 15.2 percent.
The services account deficit widened to $2.53 billion in June from $2.28 billion in May and $1.64 billion a year ago.
The travel deficit totaled $1.01 billion in June, up from $950 million in May as the number of inbound travelers decreased.
The primary income account, which tracks wages of foreign workers and dividend payments overseas, recorded a surplus of $4.16 billion, up from $2.15 billion in May largely due to an increase in dividend income.
The dividend income surplus rose from $1.59 billion to $3.44 billion.
Net assets in the financial account increased by 17.29 billion in June.
Direct investment of Koreans overseas rose $3.92 billion in June while that of foreigners in Korea increased $740 million.
In securities investment, Koreans’ overseas investments rose $9.84 billion, mainly in stocks, while foreigners’ investments in Korea gained $5.41 billion, mainly in bonds.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s current account surplus reached an all-time high of $14.27 billion in June, thanks to robust exports of semiconductors and increased dividend income. According to data released by the Ba]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.33fd4a4c5f0b4614be444421899fb246_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387460]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
