<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11395754</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>587263</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-18 10:47:57</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[SeAH advances superalloy tech to boost aerospace material sovereignty]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-18 10:47:57</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.286547a904c440d895822a6a70557d89_P1.png' alt=' (SeAH Group)'>
SeAH Group’s development of superalloy technology is expected to reduce national security risks and serve as a key milestone in securing “material sovereignty.”
Special alloys, including superalloys, have largely remained dependent on imports, making South Korea vulnerable to export restrictions from other nations.
SeAH Changwon Integrated Special Steel Corp. plans to deliver prototype superalloy materials for turbine engine retainers—critical aircraft engine components—to Hanwha Aerospace later this month. In addition, the company succeeded in January this year in developing an ultra-high temperature superalloy capable of withstanding 1,650 degrees Celsius in partnership with Doosan Enerbility.
The material is designed for use in gas turbine disks, which absorb the power of high-temperature, high-pressure combustion gases and transmit it to the engine shaft.
Superalloys are essential for components in extreme environments, such as space launch vehicles, aircraft engines, and nuclear power gas turbines. Due to high entry barriers, only a few countries—the United States, Japan, and members of the European Union—possess independent production technologies. Domestic products have historically failed to meet the heat resistance and strength requirements demanded by defense contractors, leading to heavy reliance on imports.
The technology is particularly significant for reducing foreign dependence in defense.
During the COVID-19 pandemic, Japan tightened export controls on key materials to Korea and China, prompting Seoul’s Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy to make localization a national policy priority. SeAH Group, working in a consortium with Hanwha Aerospace and Doosan Enerbility, has achieved results from these efforts.
Beyond special alloys, SeAH has built an integrated portfolio that includes stainless steel and high-strength aluminum. In 2023, its aerospace materials unit became the first Korean supplier of extruded aluminum products for Boeing, winning a contract worth 25 billion won ($18.2 million).
The company is also accelerating global expansion.
Last year, SeAH invested about 213 billion won to establish SeAH Superalloy Technology (SST) in Texas, which is now constructing a plant slated to begin operations in the second half of 2026. The site will serve as a key production base to target the North American market, which accounts for 40 percent of global demand for superalloys.
The special alloy market is rapidly growing as nations expand defense spending and the aerospace sector advances. At a NATO summit in June, defense spending targets were raised from 2 percent to 5 percent of gross domestic product, fueling further demand for advanced materials. According to The Business Research Company, the global aerospace materials market is projected to grow from $34.3 billion in 2023 to $72.8 billion by 2032. SeAH Group has increased its group-wide research and development spending by 73 percent over the past three years.
“By localizing superalloys and building a production base in the United States, we aim to secure stability in the materials supply chain,” said a group official.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[SeAH Group’s development of superalloy technology is expected to reduce national security risks and serve as a key milestone in securing “material sovereignty.” Special alloys, including superalloys, ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.286547a904c440d895822a6a70557d89_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (SeAH Group)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11395754]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
