<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11400481</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>600876</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-22 14:52:35</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Former NTS officials launch Korea’s largest tax firm]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-22 14:52:35</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.2e6e33d3fe1e4e9f899f3fa53906f6db_P1.png' alt=' CENTRIC CI'>
Former officials from South Korea’s National Tax Service (NTS), including former NTS Commissioner Han Sung-hee, have launched a new tax corporation, the largest single entity of its kind, in the country.
According to sources from the tax industry on Thursday, CENTRIC, a merger between E-hyun Tax Corporation and DR & AJU LLC, was officially launched on the same day.
The merger came to fruition through the partnership of former Commissioner Han and An Man-sik, former head of E-hyun Tax, both of whom have wielded significant influence in the tax services market as NTS alumni.
Industry watchers note that this is the first-ever merger between tax corporations in Korea.
The name CENTRIC reflects the firm’s commitment to delivering the highest-quality services in the professional tax market, it said.
Former NTS audit bureau investigators, former heads of regional NTS offices, and former national tax officials and professors have joined the company.
The total number of tax accountants at CENTRIC is expected to reach around 100.
CENTRIC plans to provide highly specialized tax services - traditionally offered only by large law and accounting firms - through its so-called “Tax Cooperation Belt.”
This system enables expert tax accountants to collaborate with legal and accounting professionals on complex tax cases, including corporate tax audits, tax litigation, mergers and acquisitions (M&A), inheritance and gift taxes, and family business succession.
Former Commissioner Han has joined CENTRIC as chief executive officer (CEO), enhancing the firm’s credibility and expertise.
Co-CEO An is also widely recognized in the industry as one of the foremost experts in tax practice.
Joining them is Kim Yong-gyun, former head of the NTS Jungbu Regional Tax Office, who is considered an authority in international taxation - having even authored a practical manual on the subject.
He will lead CENTRIC’s international tax team alongside Park Joo-il, another highly regarded former NTS international tax expert.
In the tax audit field, CENTRIC has recruited Ma Sook-ryong, a veteran representative tax accountant with extensive NTS experience, Kang Seung-yoon, former head of NTS Banpo District Office and the Seoul Regional Tax Office Investigation Bureau 4, as well as Lee Myung-jin, also a former member of the Investigation Bureau 4.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Former officials from South Korea’s National Tax Service (NTS), including former NTS Commissioner Han Sung-hee, have launched a new tax corporation, the largest single entity of its kind, in the count]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.2e6e33d3fe1e4e9f899f3fa53906f6db_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ CENTRIC CI]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11400481]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
