<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384361</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554104</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 07:57:22</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Coupang expands private-label beauty, household goods lineup]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 07:57:22</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.32baea56a6f741358209a57096d3fed7_P1.jpg' alt=' (Coupang Inc.)'>
Coupang Inc. expanded its private-label offerings with new products in its in-house beauty and household goods lines as consumers face persistent inflation.
The company said Sunday it has launched seven products under its private-label beauty brand Elle Paris. The new offerings are divided into two ranges: the EGF Vitamin line features a serum, sheet mask, and ampoule containing epidermal growth factor (EGF), an ingredient known for promoting skin vitality. The ampoule uses a liposome delivery system to help enhance the body’s absorption of vitamin C.
The Exo Hydra line includes an ampoule, bubble water, sheet mask, and soothing cream designed for hydration. The products are formulated with hyaluronic acid and plant-derived exosomes to provide lasting moisture and support healthy skin care.
In household goods, Coupang’s Tamsa label has introduced the Basic Clear File and the Lucky Home Perpetual Ledger, a hardcover household account book made for durability.
Under its Comet brand, Coupang has added new sizes of Baby Swimming Pants for pool use, available in extra-large and large. The swim diapers are individually packaged to prevent contamination during storage and to make it easier for parents to carry only what they need when traveling.
According to Statistics Korea, the living necessities price index in July 2025 rose between 2.3 and 2.5 percent year-on-year for the past three months. Cosmetics and daily essentials saw even higher increases, rising up to 4.9 percent and 4.4 percent respectively to outpace the overall consumer price index.
Coupang said most of its new private-label products are priced around 10,000 won ($7.19) to help reduce the burden on consumers. The company’s suppliers use Coupang’s nationwide logistics network to cut marketing and distribution costs, allowing them to focus on research and development and keep prices competitive.
“Functional skincare products containing EGF or vitamin derivatives typically retail for 30,000 to 50,000 won, so Coupang’s private-label offerings are highly cost-effective,” Yang Ji-hye, chief executive officer of PFNature, which partnered with Coupang, said. “Selling directly through Coupang lets us quickly gather customer feedback and apply it to research and development, strengthening our capabilities.” PFNature has hired four additional employees since partnering with Coupang and expects annual sales to reach about 30 billion won in 2025, an increase of roughly 5 billion won from the previous year.
Coupang said it plans to continue working with leading small and medium-sized partners to deliver high-quality, value-for-money products to customers.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Coupang Inc. expanded its private-label offerings with new products in its in-house beauty and household goods lines as consumers face persistent inflation. The company said Sunday it has launched sev]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.32baea56a6f741358209a57096d3fed7_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Coupang Inc.)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384361]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
