<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384356</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554094</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 07:35:13</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[WKF 2025 to feature top-tier open session speakers]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 07:35:13</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.a9e913e8e394458f8b8f7cf330282818_P1.jpeg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
The 26th World Knowledge Forum (WKF), Asia’s largest knowledge festival hosted by Maekyung Media Group, will host top-tier open session speakers and engaging topics in a diverse lineup.
The annual WKF’s open sessions, scheduled for September 9-10 at Jangchung Arena in central Seoul, are a knowledge-sharing event that provides students, professionals, and the general public with free access to insightful ideas and expertise.
Notable guests include Jared Diamond, author of “Guns, Germs, and Steel: The Fates of Human Societies,” a book often referred to as the bible of human civilization studies, as well as senior executives from Sony Pictures Entertainment Inc., the studio behind the global phenomenon “KPop Demon Hunters,” and the chief executive officer (CEO) of Binance, the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange.
The event will kick off with a keynote speech by Binance CEO Richard Teng, who will speak on the topic, “The Future of Assets: The Power of Cryptocurrency.”
He will be followed by Jared Diamond, professor emeritus at UCLA.
Guns, Germs, and Steel, the book that cemented Diamond’s status as a global intellectual, has been translated into over 60 languages and sold more than 25 million copies worldwide.
In his session, Diamond will share wisdom and choices necessary for humanity, based on the grand currents of human civilization, a subject he has dedicated his life to studying.
Next is a session on quantum computing.
Titled “A Meeting of Global Leaders in Quantum Computing,” it will feature Subodh Kulkarni, CEO of Rigetti Computing Inc., and Professor Jungsang Kim from Duke University’s Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering.
As leading figures in the development of quantum computing technologies, they will discuss the current state and future of the field.
The final speaker on the opening day comes from Hollywood: Sony Pictures, known for blockbusters like “Spider-Man” and “Venom.”
Most recently, the studio scored another mega-hit with the animated film KPop Demon Hunters.
Sanford Panitch, president of Sony Pictures Motion Picture Group and a Hollywood veteran, is expected to captivate the audience with insights into “Everything About Filmmaking,” including ideation and market strategy.
The open session on the second day, September 10, will begin with Dr. Anna Lembke, a professor at Stanford University School of Medicine and author of the bestseller Dopamine Nation.
Through her lecture, she will deliver a message on the importance of balance in an age saturated with addiction to smartphones, social media, gaming, shopping, and over-the-top (OTT) media platforms.
A book signing will follow immediately after her talk.
Next up is a session on K-beauty.
Cheun Ju-hyuk, CEO of Goodai Global Inc., which is known for Korean beauty brands such as Beauty of Joseon and TIRTIR, will take the stage.
Cheun, who led the company to nearly 1 trillion won ($720.19 million) in sales last year and grew it more than 10,000-fold in just four years, will share insights on the growth strategies and future of the K-beauty industry.
Also speaking on the second day will be celebrity chef Edward Lee, who rose to fame through last year’s cooking survival show, “Black and White Chef.”
Recognized as one of the top chefs in the United States, Lee will share highlights from his 30-year culinary career and convey the message that food can be a medium that connects people and cultures beyond being mere sustenance.
The final speaker of the open sessions will be Cody Keenan, former White House chief speechwriter.
He authored speeches for former President Barack Obama during his second term, who once called Keenan his Hemingway.
Keenan is best known for writing Obama’s moving 2015 speech honoring victims of the Charleston church shooting - a moment when the president was brought to tears.
In his session, Keenan will share behind-the-scenes stories of Obama’s most memorable speeches and tips for writing that inspires.
Applications for the open sessions are available on the WKF website until August 28.
Successful applicants will receive an individual QR code granting access to the event venue.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The 26th World Knowledge Forum (WKF), Asia’s largest knowledge festival hosted by Maekyung Media Group, will host top-tier open session speakers and engaging topics in a diverse lineup. The annual WKF]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.a9e913e8e394458f8b8f7cf330282818_P1.jpeg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384356]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
