<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11403772</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>611162</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-27 09:50:45</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[LG Uplus uses AI to prevent IPTV failures in advance]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-27 09:50:45</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.25cf8359796a44aeb76c387b6fd0c37f_P1.png' alt=' (LG Uplus)'>
LG Uplus Corp. introduced an artificial intelligence (AI)-powered system to detect and address IPTV issues before they occur. In a pilot test conducted ahead of the official rollout, the AI system was able to predict potential service disruptions with about 30 percent accuracy, resulting in a 10 percent decrease in complaints filed with the customer service center.
LG Uplus announced on Tuesday that it will initially apply this in-house developed AI-based prediction and preemptive response system to 900,000 set-top boxes.
The system analyzes over 1 trillion data points daily to detect anomalies such as degraded video quality or screen freezes. It then resolves potential problems automatically through remote interventions or reboots before users even notice them.
Users previously had to report issues directly to the call center for troubleshooting, but preemptive responses are now possible.
Data processing speed has also improved significantly, reducing analysis time from 70,000 hours to just 6 hours and cutting issue resolution from up to three days to near instantaneous. All this ensures users enjoy a stable viewing experience without long waits.
LG Uplus applied the latest deep learning algorithms, specifically a transformer-based model, to this system. It learns from over 700 types of data generated by set-top boxes and network equipment, distinguishing normal patterns from abnormal ones, and updates in 10-minute intervals for real-time monitoring and prediction.
The trained model can detect not only outright service failures but also subtle declines in quality, enabling more precise responses.
The company plans to expand this system to all 4 million IPTV devices by 2026 and to establish a fully autonomous management framework across IPTV and home networks by that year, eliminating the need for human intervention. Once fully deployed, the system will resolve even minor issues such as video quality drops or internet connection errors instantly, ensuring uninterrupted viewing for users.
LG Uplus aims to leverage this as a competitive edge in the stagnant IPTV market and to extend AI-based quality management to home networks and wireless communications.
“We developed and implemented this AI-based system to provide the highest quality service that all users can recognize,” LG Uplus head of the Quality Innovation Center Kang Bong-soo said. “Moving forward, we plan to expand AI applications across all our services to completely eliminate customer inconvenience.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[LG Uplus Corp. introduced an artificial intelligence (AI)-powered system to detect and address IPTV issues before they occur. In a pilot test conducted ahead of the official rollout, the AI system was]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.25cf8359796a44aeb76c387b6fd0c37f_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (LG Uplus)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11403772]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
