<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393609</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>580959</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 11:26:53</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean stock market held back by policy uncertainty]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 11:26:53</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400105</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.656cdf2eae7940feaab0b921e61cefd4_P1.png' alt=' (Reuters/Yonhap)'>
The South Korean stock market remains sluggish while the U.S. and Japanese stock markets are hitting record highs.
Although President Lee Jae-myung has consistently emphasized the need to revitalize the stock market since taking office, the country’s stock index is unfortunately stuck in a narrow range due to growing policy uncertainty. If this trend persists, the government’s plan to redirect capital concentrated in real estate toward the stock market will inevitably face setbacks.
The government must act consistently and take the necessary measures in order to avoid a repeat of the pattern where “leaving the Korean market is the smart choice” as the U.S. and Japanese markets continue to see booms.
Korea’s stagnant market looks even more lackluster when compared to those in the United States and Japan. The U.S. S&P 500 and Nasdaq both closed at record highs on Tuesday, while Japan’s Nikkei index topped the 43,000-mark for the first time on Wednesday, setting new records for two consecutive days.
<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.854e6291a3834c5e8d11d229dba37527_P1.png' alt=' (AFP/Yonhap)'>
The U.S. rally was driven by lower-than-expected July Consumer Price Index (CPI) growth, fueling expectations of a September rate cut. The reduced policy risk after the conclusion of mutual tariff negotiations and the postponement of additional tariffs on China also played a role, analysts said.
In Japan, the Nikkei’s rise was attributed to the tariff deal and improved corporate profitability.
Korea has also concluded its tariff talks with the United States and is benefiting from expectations surrounding a Korea-U.S. summit, but the market’s gains remain limited.
One of the main reasons is the outlook for corporate earnings, with a possible increase in the top corporate tax rate to 25 percent anticipated to hurt profitability. Anti-business legislation such as the “Yellow Envelope Bill” is also dampening investor sentiment.
Above all, the lowering of the threshold for the large shareholder capital gains tax and the smaller-than-expected expansion of separate taxation for dividend income are cited as key factors dragging down share prices.
The ruling party and government hinted at the possibility of restoring the previous capital gains tax threshold for large shareholders when the market plunged on August 1st, 2025, but no decision has been reached - and investors are moving money abroad in the meantime.
According to the Korea Securities Depository, investments in U.S. stocks turned net positive in July and August 2025.
Uncertainty is what the stock market fears most. More investors will leave the longer the government delays making decisions while torn between boosting the market and securing tax revenue.
For the KOSPI to follow the United States and Japan to new record highs, it must avoid being held back by policy uncertainty.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean stock market remains sluggish while the U.S. and Japanese stock markets are hitting record highs. Although President Lee Jae-myung has consistently emphasized the need to revitalize t]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400105</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400105</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.656cdf2eae7940feaab0b921e61cefd4_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Reuters/Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.854e6291a3834c5e8d11d229dba37527_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (AFP/Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393609]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
