<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397910</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593059</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 09:55:58</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai E&C, Hanwha Ocean team up on offshore wind projects]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 09:55:58</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.a44de984771a4c2e95ae8f372dc2657e_P1.png' alt=' (Hanwha Ocean)'>
Hyundai Engineering & Construction Co. and Hanwha Ocean Co. have teamed up to strengthen South Korea’s offshore wind supply chain by partnering on engineering, procurement, and construction (EPC) projects. The collaboration will begin with the Shinan Ui offshore wind farm near Shinan County, South Jeolla Province.
Under a memorandum of understanding (MOU) signed Tuesday, Hanwha Ocean will oversee offshore installations while Hyundai E&C manages onshore construction, a division of roles expected to create strong synergies.
Hanwha Ocean emphasized that it will contribute to localizing key infrastructure by building its own wind turbine installation vessel (WTIV).
The company plans to deploy a self-built WTIV capable of installing 15-megawatt offshore wind turbines at the site in the first half of 2028.
The Shinan Ui offshore wind project, led by Hanwha Ocean, is scheduled to secure financing and break ground in October this year, with Hyundai E&C participating as a construction investor and co-contractor.
Hyundai E&C has already proven its expertise by completing Korea’s first offshore wind project, the Southwest Demonstration Offshore Wind Farm, as well as the Jeju Hallim Offshore Wind project.
Currently, the two companies are jointly pursuing seven offshore wind projects, including sites in Tongyeong, South Gyeongsang Province, and Shinan Ui. Their strengthened cooperation is expected to significantly expand Korea’s offshore wind capacity.
Both firms also agreed to use Hanwha Ocean’s WTIV in upcoming domestic offshore wind projects, adopting a similar collaborative model to the Shinan Ui project.
“Strengthening the supply chain from the early stage of market development is essential to ensuring security in Korea’s offshore wind sector,” said Hanwha Ocean CEO Kim Hee-cheul. “Through this partnership, we will maximize technological synergies and establish a stable foundation for clean energy supply.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Engineering & Construction Co. and Hanwha Ocean Co. have teamed up to strengthen South Korea’s offshore wind supply chain by partnering on engineering, procurement, and construction (EPC) proj]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.a44de984771a4c2e95ae8f372dc2657e_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hanwha Ocean)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397910]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
