<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405892</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>617672</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 10:37:36</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[SK hynix develops mobile DRAM with highly efficient heat dissipation]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 10:37:36</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.407774cd1b734ae486c0dec8e2bbfc9f_P1.png' alt=' SK hynix high-thermal-conductivity mobile DRAM'>
South Korean memory chipmaker SK hynix Inc. announced on Thursday that it developed the industry’s first high-thermal-conductivity mobile DRAM using a new material and began supplying it to customers.
The new material developed by SK hynix is High-K Epoxy Molding Compound (EMC). EMC is an essential material in semiconductor back-end processing that protects chips from moisture, heat, shock, and electrical charge, while also serving as a channel to dissipate heat.
High-K refers to the use of materials with a high thermal conductivity coefficient (K) in EMC, thus enhancing heat transfer. A higher thermal conductivity enables faster heat dissipation.
“The heat generated during high-speed data processing for on-device artificial intelligence (AI) has become a key factor undermining smartphone performance,” SK hynix said. “This product addresses overheating issues in high-end flagship smartphones and has earned strong recognition from global customers.”
Recent flagship smartphones use the Package on Package (PoP) structure, which stacks DRAM on top of the mobile application processor (AP) - the chip that serves as the smartphone’s brain. This design improves space efficiency and data processing speed, but heat generated by the AP often accumulates in the DRAM, degrading overall smartphone performance.
To address this issue, SK hynix focused on improving the thermal conductivity of EMC, the key material that encapsulates DRAM packages.
The company developed High-K EMC by mixing alumina with silica, the material traditionally used in EMC. This innovation enhanced thermal conductivity by about 3.5 times compared to conventional materials and reduced thermal resistance along vertical heat pathways by 47 percent. The improved heat dissipation not only boosts smartphone performance but also lowers power consumption, contributing to longer battery life and extended device lifespan.
“This product is a meaningful achievement that goes beyond a simple performance improvement as it addresses the inconvenience that many high-performance smartphone users may have had,” Lee Gyujei, head of Package Product Development, said. “We are committed to firmly establishing our technological leadership in the next-generation mobile DRAM market with our technological innovation in materials.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean memory chipmaker SK hynix Inc. announced on Thursday that it developed the industry’s first high-thermal-conductivity mobile DRAM using a new material and began supplying it to customers.]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.407774cd1b734ae486c0dec8e2bbfc9f_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ SK hynix high-thermal-conductivity mobile DRAM]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405892]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
