<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11404921</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>615057</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-28 12:39:17</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[BOK keeps rate steady at 2.5% amid concerns about rising housing prices]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-28 12:39:17</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.44b1da3522534cbdbe9c867de217ded4_P1.png' alt=' (BOK)'>
The Bank of Korea (BOK) kept its benchmark interest rate unchanged at 2.5 percent on Thursday, citing risks that an early cut could reignite overheating in the housing and household debt markets.
The BOK shifted to an easing stance in October 2024 with a 25-basis-point cut and followed up in November with back-to-back reductions for the first time since the global financial crisis.
In the first half of this year, it lowered rates at two of four meetings to offset weakness in construction, consumption, and the drag from U.S. tariffs.
Since July, however, the bank has paused for two straight months, reflecting heightened financial instability.
Despite caps on home mortgage loans in the Seoul metropolitan area at 600 million won ($432,000), apartment prices in the capital rose 0.09 percent in the third week of August from the previous week, according to the Korea Real Estate Board.
Household lending at commercial banks grew by 2.8 trillion won in July, half of June’s increase, but caution remains as much of the mortgage borrowing contracted before the government’s June curbs is still being released with a lag.
Governor Rhee Chang-yong also cautioned lawmakers last week that although the debt-control package has curbed some overheating, housing prices in parts of Seoul are still climbing and need close monitoring.
The record interest-rate gap with the U.S. is seen as another factor in the latest decision.
With the Federal Reserve’s target rate at 4.25 to 4.5 percent, the spread already stands at two percentage points. A Korean rate cut ahead of a possible Fed move in September would have widened the gap to 2.25 points, raising risks of capital outflows and downward pressure on the won.
Improved sentiment and easing tariff concerns have also given the board room to wait, insiders noted.
The composite consumer sentiment index rose to 111.4 in August, according to the BOK, the highest since January 2018.
On Thursday, the BOK also raised its 2025 growth forecast to 0.9 percent from 0.8 percent, reflecting stronger consumption and an improved trade outlook.
Park Jeong-woo, an economist at Nomura Securities, said the bank is now more likely to revise forecasts upward and monitor the pace of recovery before considering additional easing.
Most analysts, however, still expect another rate cut later this year given sub-one-percent growth, with October seen as the most likely timing.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The Bank of Korea (BOK) kept its benchmark interest rate unchanged at 2.5 percent on Thursday, citing risks that an early cut could reignite overheating in the housing and household debt markets. The ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.44b1da3522534cbdbe9c867de217ded4_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (BOK)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11404921]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
