<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393612</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>580967</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 11:27:06</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Naver and Disney to release Spider-Man Avengers webtoons]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 11:27:06</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.d03a8cacc2cb4819bd2ec9b2dbad6fcb_P1.png' alt=' (Naver Webtoon)'>
Disney’s globally beloved hits - including “Spider-Man,” “Avengers,” and “Star Wars” - will soon be available in webtoon format.
Naver Webtoon is teaming up with Disney to release over 100 series as webtoons. The partnership is considered highly symbolic as it signals Naver Webtoon’s official recognition in the mainstream U.S. content market.
Naver Webtoon’s U.S. headquarters, Webtoon Entertainment, announced on Wednesday that it signed a multi-year global content partnership with The Walt Disney Company. Under this collaboration, iconic titles from Disney, Marvel, Star Wars, and 20th Century Studios will be adapted into vertically scrolling webtoons. The duo plan to release around 100 series sequentially through a newly created Disney section in the English-language version of Naver Webtoon’s global platform WEBTOON.
In addition to reimagined works, the companies are also developing original webtoon series from Disney, Marvel, Star Wars, and 20th Century Studios. These new originals will span a wide range of genres - from superhero action to grand space adventures - offering fans fresh takes on familiar characters.
The first five titles will be “The Amazing Spider-Man,” “Avengers,” “Star Wars,” “Alien,” and “A Very Old Story.”
The Amazing Spider-Man will premiere at the end of August 2025, and the others will follow in stages. Although pricing details are yet to be revealed, the model is expected to match that of Naver Webtoon in Korea, with some initial episodes free and later episodes available via paid access.
“We are thrilled to present these legendary works in a webtoon format optimized for the mobile generation,” Kim Yong-soo, chief strategy officer and head of global webtoon business at Naver Webtoon, said. “This is only the beginning of our collaboration with Disney, and we will continue to lead the way in making beloved stories available to fans anytime, anywhere.”
The partnership was finalized after about a year of discussions. Disney reportedly evaluated multiple webtoon companies before concluding that Webtoon Entertainment was the “clear forerunner.” Factors in Naver’s favor included its Los Angeles headquarters and status as a Nasdaq-listed company.
Under the agreement, all webtoons produced will be created using traditional methods, with no AI technology involved.
This is not Naver’s only major global alliance. The company has been aggressively expanding partnerships with international firms. It joined forces with Netflix in 2024 to include the streaming service in Naver Plus Membership benefits. Microsoft’s Xbox Games Pass was added in July 2024, and talks with Spotify are reportedly underway.
The strong synergy in the Netflix deal in particular boosted new membership sign-ups by 1.5 times compared to before the partnership.
Meanwhile, Webtoon Entertainment has also achieved improved results in the second quarter of 2025. The company announced on Tuesday (local time) that its second-quarter operating loss narrowed to $8.76 million, down nearly 90 percent from a year ago. Revenue rose 8.5 percent to $348. 3 million, supported by growth in paid content, advertising, and intellectual property (IP) sales, with a notable 13.2 percent increase in revenue from Japan contributing to the gains.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Disney’s globally beloved hits - including “Spider-Man,” “Avengers,” and “Star Wars” - will soon be available in webtoon format. Naver Webtoon is teaming up with Disney to release over 100 series as w]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.d03a8cacc2cb4819bd2ec9b2dbad6fcb_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Naver Webtoon)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393612]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
