<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11400480</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>600875</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-22 14:52:35</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Software, AI to drive future of mobility: Hyundai chief]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-22 14:52:35</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.dfe6f91457e74fa698f2f3725ee0578b_P1.png' alt=' Hyundai Motor Group Executive Chair Euisun Chung'>
Hyundai Motor Group Executive Chair Euisun Chung on Thursday underscored the role of software-defined vehicles (SDVs) and artificial intelligence (AI) in shaping the future of the automotive industry.
In an interview with U.S. trade outlet Automotive News on Thursday, Chung said the fusion of SDVs and AI will be one of the defining forces of mobility over the next 25 years. He noted that the industry is entering an era shifting from horsepower to processing power, stressing that what matters is not just how cars drive but how they “think, learn and evolve.”
Chung noted that Hyundai is shifting away from the traditional cycle of updating models every few years and is instead developing vehicles as platforms that continuously improve, much like smartphones. He added that while electrification redefined the powertrain, software is now reshaping the entire value chain, from product development and vehicle architecture to user interaction and business models.
Earlier, Automotive News honored Hyundai’s three generations of leadership, naming founder Chung Ju-yung, Honorary Chairman Chung Mong-koo, and current Chair Chung Euisun as recipients of its Centennial Award.
Addressing tariff issues, Chung said Hyundai will expand local production in the U.S. He cited agility as one of the group’s greatest strengths and reaffirmed Hyundai’s belief in producing where it sells. The company is investing more than $21 billion in U.S. manufacturing, supply chains, and steel production.
On intensifying competition from Chinese automakers, Chung stressed a customer-first approach, saying technology is meaningless if it fails to meet real human needs. He added that this philosophy has guided Hyundai’s success and will continue to do so.
Chung also said Hyundai seeks partnerships that help it move faster, think bigger, and deliver better services, adding that cooperation in the industry is now essential rather than optional.
When asked which figures have most transformed the automotive industry, he pointed to Tesla CEO Elon Musk, calling him a pioneer who popularized long-range electric vehicles, redefined the role of software in cars, and accelerated the EV market.
As for his personal favorites, Chung cited the Porsche 911, Volkswagen Golf, and Lamborghini Countach, describing the 911 as the benchmark for sports cars both technically and emotionally, and the Golf as the standard for compact hatchbacks.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Group Executive Chair Euisun Chung on Thursday underscored the role of software-defined vehicles (SDVs) and artificial intelligence (AI) in shaping the future of the automotive industry.]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.dfe6f91457e74fa698f2f3725ee0578b_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Hyundai Motor Group Executive Chair Euisun Chung]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11400480]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
