<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397907</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593057</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 09:55:47</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KHNP withdraws from Polish nuclear power project]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 09:55:47</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.2699a522df2f4ed38ed2cb29508972c4_P1.png' alt=' KHNP President Whang Joo-ho. (News1)'>
South Korea’s Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power Co. (KHNP) withdrew from a Polish nuclear power project. The move comes amid the state-run nuclear power agency’s settlement of an intellectual property (IP) dispute with U.S.-based Westinghouse Electric Company LLC and is another retreat from the European market.
KHNP President Whang Joo-ho said during a National Assembly audit on Tuesday that the company “has effectively withdrawn” from the Polish project.
“We were pursuing both government-led and state-owned enterprise-led projects, but Poland decided not to proceed with the state-owned enterprise project after a new government came into power there. That is why we withdrew our business there,” Whang explained.
This marks the fourth time KHNP has withdrawn from a European market since its settlement with Westinghouse in January 2025, with the company giving up on nuclear bids in Sweden, Slovenia, and the Netherlands.
KHNP reportedly ceded leadership of nuclear projects in Europe to Westinghouse when it settled its IP dispute with the U.S. company in order to secure a contract for a new nuclear power plant in the Czech Republic. As a result, it is barred from entering the nuclear markets of European Union member states (except the Czech Republic), North America, the United Kingdom, Japan, and Ukraine. It is also now restricted to pursuing projects in Southeast Asia, Central Asia, the United Arab Emirates, Saudi Arabia, South America, and Türkiye.
Industry experts pointed out at the time that the settlement terms were highly disadvantageous to KHNP as Europe has far more ongoing nuclear projects than the Middle East. Whang defended the controversial settlement during the National Assembly audit.
KHNP is reportedly obliged to pay Westinghouse IP royalties of around 200 billion won ($143.64 million) per nuclear export project and guarantee contracts worth more than 1 trillion won. Allegations also emerged recently that KHNP agreed to issue a standby letter of credit (SBLC) for Westinghouse.
Industry observers believe that KHNP made excessive concessions in order to secure the Czech nuclear contract.
“I do not think the terms are fair from our perspective,” Whang said. “The total amount and percentages make it seem like Westinghouse gets a large portion, but since Westinghouse lacks its own supply chain, it will inevitably have to subcontract to those with supply chains like us even if it takes a share.”
His remarks suggest that KHNP could still secure profits from Westinghouse-led projects as the U.S. company lacks independent nuclear construction capacity.
On the same day, the Korean presidential office ordered the Ministry of Trade, Industry, and Energy to investigate the controversy surrounding the allegedly unfair contract between KHNP and Westinghouse.
Presidential spokesperson Kang Yoo-jung told a press briefing that “the Chief of Staff instructed the ministry to determine whether the negotiation and contract process between KHNP, Korea Electric Power Corp. (KEPCO), and Westinghouse were conducted in accordance with laws, regulations, principles, and procedures.”
The industry ministry is expected to examine the Czech project negotiations.
“We are compiling the situation in accordance with the presidential office’s directive and will report soon,” a senior ministry official said. “Once we report it, it will be possible to judge whether this contract indeed undermines our national interests.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power Co. (KHNP) withdrew from a Polish nuclear power project. The move comes amid the state-run nuclear power agency’s settlement of an intellectual property (IP) ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.2699a522df2f4ed38ed2cb29508972c4_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ KHNP President Whang Joo-ho. (News1)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397907]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
