<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11399029</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>596590</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-21 10:26:43</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KHNP eyes joint venture with Westinghouse for U.S. entry]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-21 10:26:43</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.4a2d8d81791e4deba864c9b428c42d98_P1.png' alt=' (KHNP)'>
The state-run Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power Co. (KHNP) is expected to raise discussions about forming a joint venture (JV) with Westinghouse Electric Co. during the South Korea–U.S. Summit next week, in an effort to enter the U.S. nuclear power market.
According to industry sources on Wednesday, KHNP and Westinghouse are negotiating a JV framework for U.S. market entry. KHNP Chief Executive Officer Whang Joo-ho is scheduled to visit Washington around the summit to discuss the plan.
KHNP has been barred from directly entering the North American market following a settlement reached in January with Westinghouse over an intellectual property dispute. Under the settlement, KHNP agreed not to pursue independent entry into the U.S. nuclear market. However, given Westinghouse lacking full-scale construction capacity, collaboration with KHNP, which offers complete project capabilities, is considered likely.
Appearing at the National Assembly on Tuesday, Whang pointed that the U.S. firm will have to rely on a partner with established supply chains given its limitations.
The U.S. nuclear market is expected to expand under President Donald Trump’s pro-nuclear policy. Trump has pledged to quadruple nuclear power capacity to 400 gigawatts by 2050, begin construction of ten 1,000-megawatt reactors by 2030, and shorten licensing periods for new plants to within 18 months.
Despite prospects for KHNP’s entry, controversy continues over the settlement with Westinghouse.
The ruling Democratic Party has denounced the agreement signed by KHNP and Korea Electric Power Corp. (KEPCO) as “traitorous” and criticized the previous Yoon Suk Yeol administration for pushing it.
The presidential office is cautious that heightened debate over the deal ahead of the summit could strain ties with Washington, given Westinghouse’s status as a key U.S. nuclear technology company. It has directed the Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy to investigate the matter, though a senior official said the probe will not conclude before the summit.
Meanwhile, nuclear-related stocks pared earlier losses on renewed optimism for KHNP’s U.S. entry.
Doosan Enerbility Co., which had fallen as much as 14.14 percent intraday, closed down 3.53 percent on Wednesday. Korea Electric Power Corp. reversed losses to finish 0.4 percent higher at 37,500 won ($26.83). KEPCO Engineering & Construction Co. and KEPCO Plant Service & Engineering Co. also narrowed declines, closing down 3.65 percent and 2.21 percent, respectively.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The state-run Korea Hydro & Nuclear Power Co. (KHNP) is expected to raise discussions about forming a joint venture (JV) with Westinghouse Electric Co. during the South Korea–U.S. Summit next week, in]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.4a2d8d81791e4deba864c9b428c42d98_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (KHNP)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11399029]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
