<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390342</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570890</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 10:35:48</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Aug. 1 to 10 exports fall 4.3% due to fewer working days]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 10:35:48</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.8d916e132bcb4e8b818793ad93b6792b_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korea’s exports fell in the first 10 days of August 2025 from a year ago due to fewer working days, data showed on Monday.
According to Korea Customs Service, the country’s exports from August 1st to 10th totaled $14.7 billion, down 4.3 percent from the same period during the previous year. Daily exports jumped 9.3 percent on year to $2.1 billion based on 7 working days, 1 day shorter than last year.
Outbound shipments rose 5.9 percent from a year ago in July 2025, staying robust after growing during the previous month. Demand for chips and automobiles remained strong. Outbound shipments of semiconductors climbed 12 percent from the same period a year ago in the first 10 days of August, while exports of vessels also gained 81.3 percent and automobiles rose 8.5 percent.
However, exports of petroleum products declined 19.4 percent and those of wireless telecommunications devices fell 4.5 percent during the cited period.
By country, shipments to China fell 10 percent, the United States 14.2 percent, and the European Union 34.8 percent, while exports to Vietnam rose 4.1 percent and Taiwan 47.4 percent.
Imports in the first 10 days of August stood at $15.9 billion, down 13.6 percent from a year ago and resulting in a trade deficit of $1.2 billion. Imports of wireless telecommunications devices rose 8 percent while those of crude oil fell 14.2 percent, chips 8.4 percent, and gas 29.5 percent.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s exports fell in the first 10 days of August 2025 from a year ago due to fewer working days, data showed on Monday. According to Korea Customs Service, the country’s exports from August 1]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.8d916e132bcb4e8b818793ad93b6792b_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390342]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
