<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405888</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>617677</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 10:37:21</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Seoul turns to Malaysia for new growth opportunities]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 10:37:21</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/my-p.v1.20250829.2592ddf6bff14e6a94178f5154ea49a8_P1.png' alt=' Members of South Korea’s special presidential delegation to Malaysia depart from Incheon International Airport on July 22. From left, lawmaker Youn Kun-young, delegation head and former Oceans and Fisheries Minister Kim Young-choon, and lawmaker Nam In-soon. (Newsis)'>
South Korea is looking to strengthen ties with Malaysia as Kuala Lumpur signals strong interest in expanding economic cooperation and elevating bilateral relations amid global trade tensions.
Former Oceans and Fisheries Minister Kim Young-choon, who visited Malaysia in July 2025 as head of a special presidential delegation, said the push for closer ties stems largely from Malaysia’s own push. “It was Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim who first raised the need to expand exchanges,” Kim said during a phone call with Maeil Business Newspaper, noting that a Korea-Malaysia free trade agreement (FTA) was “Malaysia’s greatest interest.”
According to Kim, Prime Minister Anwar and other senior officials pressed the delegation to conclude an FTA within the year, setting out a specific timeline. The urgency, he said, reflects Malaysia’s bid to reinvigorate stalled trade ties with Korea as part of its response to U.S.-led tariff measures. “The Korean government also holds a positive stance,” he added.
Malaysia is also eyeing Korea’s expertise in developing high-skilled talent in advanced industries. “Many Malaysian public officials and professionals receive training in Korea,” Kim said. “There is strong interest in Korea’s retraining programs for high-level talent. Most of the training is self-funded rather than aid-based, which indicates their high satisfaction.”
Representative Youn Kun-young, another delegation member, said Malaysian leaders consistently emphasized economic cooperation during the visit. “We met with the prime minister, deputy prime minister, and foreign minister, and they all expressed a strong preference for Korea,” Youn said. “Defense stood out in particular, while Korean culture and batteries were also highlighted as areas for collaboration.”
Representative Nam In-soon added that while the delegation’s mandate was to highlight Korea’s renewed emphasis on democratic governance, Malaysia placed greater weight on economic exchanges. “We conveyed the Korean government’s intention to advance ties with Malaysia under the New Southern Policy,” she said.
This year marks the sixty-fifth anniversary of diplomatic relations between the two countries, with Malaysia also serving as chair of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea is looking to strengthen ties with Malaysia as Kuala Lumpur signals strong interest in expanding economic cooperation and elevating bilateral relations amid global trade tensions. Former O]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/my-p.v1.20250829.2592ddf6bff14e6a94178f5154ea49a8_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Members of South Korea’s special presidential delegation to Malaysia depart from Incheon International Airport on July 22. From left, lawmaker Youn Kun-young, delegation head and former Oceans and Fisheries Minister Kim Young-choon, and lawmaker Nam In-soon. (Newsis)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405888]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
