<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393869</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>581928</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 15:14:16</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea to push ahead with pro-labor policy drive]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 15:14:16</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.944f631edbed437ebd21f5b37cf93795_P1.png' alt=' (Kim Ho-young)'>
South Korea is set to accelerate pro-labor policies as the Lee Jae-myung administration’s five-year policy agenda includes long-standing labor protection measures.
The five-year policy plan, drafted by the presidential policy committee and unveiled at a national briefing on Wednesday, outlines major labor law changes. The government plans to push ahead with amendments to restrict companies from seeking damages for illegal strikes and to strengthen the rights of temporary, subcontracted, and other non-regular workers in such disputes - measures labor groups have long sought. The bill is awaiting a plenary vote in the National Assembly.
The committee also announced plans to gradually extend labor laws to small workplaces with fewer than five employees, which are currently exempt from key provisions on working hours, overtime pay, and maternity protection. The government is reportedly considering beginning with measures that are easier to implement, such as banning workplace bullying and enhancing maternity protections.
The committee additionally said it would explicitly incorporate “equal pay for work of equal value” into law to address discrimination against contract workers performing similar duties to permanent employees. This could involve adding principles to labor law requiring comparable treatment regardless of employment type, gender, or career background.
The committee also pledged to prepare a cross-ministerial roadmap for reducing actual working hours, part of Lee’s pledge to introduce a 4.5-day workweek. The Ministry of Employment and Labor has proposed lowering statutory weekly working hours from 40 to 36 or reducing allowable overtime from 12 to 8 hours.
However, the business community has voiced concern that these measures could curb corporate activity. Employers are particularly alarmed by the planned limits on damage claims, warning that when combined with the recent expansion of directors’ fiduciary duties and the proposed corporate tax increase, they could hinder business operations. Critics say broader employer responsibility could lead to prolonged negotiations with subcontractor unions and prevent companies from recovering losses from illegal strikes, creating persistent industrial unrest.
Korea Enterprises Federation Chairman Sohn Kyung-shik sent letters to all 298 lawmakers on Tuesday urging them to stop the legislation. He warned that the changes could draw main contractors into subcontractor labor disputes and make corporate management decisions a target of labor action, potentially destabilizing key industries such as automobiles, shipbuilding, and construction.
Business leaders have also raised concerns over the “equal pay for equal value” proposal, arguing it could undermine wage systems based on job, performance, and experience, reduce pay flexibility, and stifle productivity and innovation. In sectors that have high proportions of contact workers, such as manufacturing and services, they fear labor costs could rise sharply in the short term. Shorter working hours are also controversial, with manufacturers already struggling under the 52-hour workweek warning that further cuts would require expanded shifts or more hiring, driving up costs.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea is set to accelerate pro-labor policies as the Lee Jae-myung administration’s five-year policy agenda includes long-standing labor protection measures. The five-year policy plan, drafted b]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.944f631edbed437ebd21f5b37cf93795_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Kim Ho-young)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393869]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
