<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11386183</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>559790</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-06 08:17:28</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[LG Electronics, LX Pantos to offer one-stop appliance service in the U.S.]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-06 08:17:28</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.fa98ae552872455699656a829f66ff17_P1.png' alt=' (MK DB)'>
South Korea’s LG Electronics Inc. and logistics company LX Pantos Co. have joined hands to launch a direct delivery and installation service for home appliances in the United States in the second half of 2025.
According to multiple sources from the logistics industry on Tuesday, LX Pantos and LG Electronics will fully implement a direct delivery and installation service for home appliances targeting the U.S. market in the second half of this year.
When American consumers purchase LG appliances through online channels such as the LG Electronics online shop, LX Pantos will provide one-stop service – from delivery to relocation and installation – directly to the customer’s home.
A pilot program was successfully conducted in 39 areas during the first half of the year.
The companies plan to gradually expand both the service areas across the U.S. and the range of products covered.
“In the U.S. logistics market, profitability depends on value-added services rather than simple delivery,” said an LX Pantos official. “We plan to extend our offerings to include services such as removal of used appliances and after-sales support.”
LX Pantos already provides delivery, installation, and relocation services for LG appliances in Korea and is leveraging this experience for its full-scale expansion into the U.S. market. The company continues to work closely with LG Electronics to bring the model overseas.
Some challenges remain for the service in the U.S., however, where the vast geographic area and a strong do-it-yourself culture make widespread adoption more difficult.
“Demand for Korean-style premium appliance installation and relocation services is steadily growing, particularly among the middle class in the U.S.,” an LX Pantos representative said. “We plan to offer a differentiated appliance delivery and installation service tailored to the U.S. market, drawing on our accumulated service experience and data-driven expertise from Korea.”
LX Pantos has identified the U.S. as a strategic growth market and is actively expanding its presence there.
This year, it acquired a large logistics center in Georgia and is reinforcing its North American infrastructure. The company is also developing a nationwide delivery network through direct contracts with U.S. rail operators.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s LG Electronics Inc. and logistics company LX Pantos Co. have joined hands to launch a direct delivery and installation service for home appliances in the United States in the second half]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.fa98ae552872455699656a829f66ff17_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11386183]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
