<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11399074</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>596692</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-21 10:45:56</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Gov’t unveils plans to accelerate petrochemical industry restructuring]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-21 10:45:56</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.2bf6022a8869473ca5caf5dbd6f7fced_P1.png' alt=' (Lee Chung-woo)'>
The South Korean government is preparing a comprehensive support policy package to accelerate the restructuring of the country’s petrochemical industry.
The plan was unveiled during a meeting of economy-related ministers on strengthening industrial competitiveness at the government complex in Seoul on Wednesday, where it finalized the restructuring direction and support principles for the petrochemical industry.
A cross-ministerial body for discussing industrial issues, the meeting was the first held under the new Lee Jae-myung administration. There, the government presented a target for reducing domestic petrochemical production capacity for the first time.
The government concluded that up to 3.7 million tons of naphtha cracking center (NCC) capacity should be cut going forward, based on the results of industry-led consulting. This accounts for 25.2 percent of the country’s total NCC capacity of 14.7 million tons.
To this end, the government will require the country’s top 10 petrochemical companies to submit their restructuring plans by the end of 2025. These plans are expected to include facility consolidations across the industry, mergers and acquisitions (M&As) to strengthen competitiveness, and strategies for transitioning to high value-added products.
After reviewing the validity of the restructuring plans and the companies’ self-help efforts, the government plans to put together a support package that includes financial assistance, tax benefits, research and development (R&D) support, and deregulation.
The government also made it clear that it will respond firmly to companies that attempt to survive solely via government aid and without taking responsible self-rescue measures or try to benefit only from other firms’ facility reductions.
“We cannot overcome the current crisis with a complacent mindset of ‘just wait it out’ or ‘just weather this storm.’ The industry must approach this situation with a ‘life-or-death’ mentality,” Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Economy and Finance Koo Yun-cheol said. “Petrochemical companies and their major shareholders must commit to painful self-help measures and swiftly present binding restructuring and competitiveness plans - not by the end of the year but as early as next month, with a sense of urgency.”
On the same day, the petrochemical industry held a voluntary restructuring agreement ceremony. The industry pledged to cut NCC capacity by 2.7 to 3.7 million tons, shift business operations toward high value-added and eco-friendly products, and minimize the impact on local economies at the event.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean government is preparing a comprehensive support policy package to accelerate the restructuring of the country’s petrochemical industry. The plan was unveiled during a meeting of econo]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.2bf6022a8869473ca5caf5dbd6f7fced_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Lee Chung-woo)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11399074]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
