<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390156</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570308</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 07:17:37</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Bodyfriend shifts to younger co-CEOs in leadership shake-up]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 07:17:37</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.c34b37f062484eb49e40d694410236e7_P1.jpg' alt=' (Bodyfriend)'>
Bodyfriend Inc., a leading healthcare robotics firm, has named two seasoned executives in their 40s and 50s as co-chief executives, marking a generational shift at the top.
The decision was made at a board meeting on Thursday and was disclosed on Friday.
Kwak Do-yeon, 50, joined the company in 2013 after a career in overseas business and sales at Lotte Chilsung Beverage.
Over the past ten years, he has led multiple divisions - including management, overseas business, and production - playing a key role in the company’s fast growth and expansion abroad.
Most recently, as chief sales officer, he focused on stabilizing the company’s performance. Kwak’s new mandate includes boosting Bodyfriend’s overseas sales share to 20 percent by 2027, with particular emphasis on markets like the United States.
The other new co-CEO, 43-year-old Kim Cheol-hwan, will take charge of internal operations and corporate management.
Since becoming head of the management support office in 2023, Kim has overseen companywide administration.
In his 13 years with Bodyfriend, he has worked in strategic finance, auditing, and other core departments, building a reputation as a leader committed to strengthening the company’s fundamentals.
Under the new structure, Kwak will be responsible for sales and research and development (R&D), while Kim will focus on management operations.
“These leaders have each been with Bodyfriend for more than a decade, accumulating extensive industry expertise and strong, hands-on management skills,” the company said in a statement.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Bodyfriend Inc., a leading healthcare robotics firm, has named two seasoned executives in their 40s and 50s as co-chief executives, marking a generational shift at the top. The decision was made at a ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.c34b37f062484eb49e40d694410236e7_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Bodyfriend)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390156]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
