<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384547</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554755</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 10:36:39</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai Rotem shares up thanks to second Poland K2 contract]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 10:36:39</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-04 16:12:18</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.229cf9b6be304631a1d9609c40d460b4_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Hyundai Rotem Co. shares rose in early Monday trading after the company confirmed the completion of the signing ceremony for the second implementation contract for K2 tank exports to Poland.
The stock was trading at 198,700 won ($143.28) As of 9:25 a.m., up 2.42 percent from the previous session.
The Ministry of National Defense said Minister Ahn Gyu-baek attended the signing ceremony on Friday in Gliwice, Poland, alongside Polish Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of National Defence Władysław Kosiniak-Kamysz.
The second-phase K2 tank export deal, finalized earlier in August 2024, is valued at about $6.5 billion, making it the largest single defense export contract in South Korea’s history.
On the same day, specialty aerospace alloy producer Sphere Co. saw its stock gain more than 14 percent in early trade.
The shares were at 16,210 won as of 9:28 a.m., up 14.40 percent from the prior day, according to the Korea Exchange.
The rally follows the previous week’s disclosure that Sphere signed a 10-year contract to supply specialty alloys to Space Exploration Technologies Corp. (SpaceX), led by Elon Musk. Under the deal, Sphere will deliver alloys annually through December 31st, 2035, with the first year’s estimated demand valued at around $110 million.
Sphere shares hit the daily upper price limit on Friday, the day after the contract announcement, and extended the gains on Monday.
Hyundai Rotem shares closed at 200,000 won, while Sphere shares closed at 14,170 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Rotem Co. shares rose in early Monday trading after the company confirmed the completion of the signing ceremony for the second implementation contract for K2 tank exports to Poland. The stock]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.229cf9b6be304631a1d9609c40d460b4_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384547]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
