<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385275</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>556995</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 08:46:28</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Instant noodle firms race to revamp work schedules]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 08:46:28</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.11ddf705cb114f609ed519430f532c0b_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
South Korea’s instant noodle industry is revamping its work schedules after President Lee Jae-myung emphasized “safety first” during his visit to SPC Samlip Co.’s plant in Sihwa, Gyeonggi Province, in July 2025.
According to sources from the food industry on Monday, Samyang Foods Co. decided to abolish its special extended work hours on the same day after facing criticism that its export demands had led to excessive night shifts for production workers.
Employees at Samyang’s second factory in Miryang, South Gyeongsang Province - where Buldak Ramen is produced - had been working a two-shift system, five days a week. This means night shift workers had to work through the night for five consecutive days.
Samyang has not sufficiently expanded its factory capacity or workforce despite its exports surging 45-fold over the past 15 years from 30 billion won ($21.67 million) to 1.34 trillion won in 2024.
“We will abolish special extended work hours at four factories, including two factories in Miryang and factories in Wonju and Iksan,” a company official said. “We have decided to cease all special extended work shifts starting Saturday, August 9th, thanks to our rapidly increasing automation line efficiency.”
The company is also reviewing changes to the current two-shift rotation system between day and night workers.
Nongshim Co., known for its flagship Shin Ramyun, is also exploring various options to revise its work system as it also operates on a two-shift schedule.
“We are currently reviewing changes from multiple angles while taking labor union feedback into account,” a Nongshim official said, while emphasizing that it strictly adheres to the 52-hour workweek and does not implement special extended hours.
For its part, Ottogi Corp., which produces Jin Ramen, is taking a different approach by distributing workloads more evenly.
“We are operating some production lines on a partial three-shift system to help reduce work intensity,” an Ottogi official said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s instant noodle industry is revamping its work schedules after President Lee Jae-myung emphasized “safety first” during his visit to SPC Samlip Co.’s plant in Sihwa, Gyeonggi Province, in]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.11ddf705cb114f609ed519430f532c0b_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385275]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
