<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11400184</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>600117</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-22 11:16:44</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[SK chief stresses importance of embracing AI]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-22 11:16:44</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.53fb429e52104175a18f372b045ed0d7_P1.png' alt=' (SK SUPEX Council)'>
SK Group Chairman Chey Tae-won emphasized the importance of embodying artificial intelligence (AI) on Wednesday.
The South Korean conglomerate disclosed on Thursday that Chey said “each and every member must be able to use AI comfortably in order to achieve innovation and success” during the closing session of the Icheon Forum 2025 in Seoul the day before.
He also noted that “we are in an era where we must rapidly internalize AI and digital transformation (DT) technologies to create differentiated competitiveness.”
Chey’s remarks outline the key capabilities that SK members should cultivate, given that he has personally designated AI as the group’s future growth engine and is pushing affiliates to expand AI investments as well as pursuing new businesses.
“Most of the tasks we currently perform will soon be replaced by AI agents, and people must focus on roles that create new and creative value,” he added.
The annual three-day Icheon Forum concluded with a closing session where Chey took part in real-time discussions with SK members, both on and offline, on topics including technological innovation, operational improvement, and sustainability.
Other forum attendees included Executive Senior Vice Chairman Chey Jae-won, SUPEX Council Chairman Chey Chang-won, other senior executives, and 170 SK members representing the workforce.
Chey also underlined the group’s Operation Improvement (O/I) initiative.
“Operational improvement is about strengthening the company’s fundamental capacity,” he noted. “To secure essential competitiveness in the AI era, it is necessary to thoroughly understand and reinforce daily work processes.”
During the forum’s “Skillful SK Life” session with employees on Tuesday, Chey had addressed the ongoing conflict over performance bonuses at SK hynix Inc.
“I heard that employees are not satisfied even with bonuses at 1,700 percent. But even if it rises to 3,000 percent or 5,000 percent, that will not necessarily bring happiness,” he said. “Although SK hynix has risen to become the top semiconductor company, there is still uncertainty. If we become fixated solely on compensation, we lose sight of the future. That is a shortsighted approach.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[SK Group Chairman Chey Tae-won emphasized the importance of embodying artificial intelligence (AI) on Wednesday. The South Korean conglomerate disclosed on Thursday that Chey said “each and every memb]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/22/news-p.v1.20250822.53fb429e52104175a18f372b045ed0d7_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (SK SUPEX Council)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11400184]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
