<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385446</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>557405</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 10:25:42</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean financial, securities stocks see second day of gains]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 10:25:42</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-05 16:12:31</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.9f5fcd2b1f4747308ceac72a045af1b5_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korean financial and securities stocks, which had plunged last week due to disappointment over the government’s announced tax reform plan, are continuing their rebound for the second consecutive day.
KB Financial Group shares were trading at 112,700 won ($81.4) as of 10:12 a.m., up 3.97 percent from the previous session. Shinhan Financial Group shares also soared 3.49 percent to 68,200 won, Hana Financial Group shares climbed 2.55 percent to 84,500 won, and Woori Financial Group shares gained 2.47 percent to 24,850 won.
Brokerage firms also saw notable gains. Samsung Securities Co. shares jumped 3.97 percent to 70,700 won, while Mirae Asset Securities Co. shares rose 2.32 percent to 18,540 won as of 10:14 a.m.
The rebound appears to be driven by expectations that the ruling party will respond to strong investor backlash over the government’s tax reform proposal to lower the threshold for large shareholders subject to capital gains from 5 billion won to 1 billion won.
There is also a growing expectation of a U.S. interest rate cut.
Separately, chip stocks gained on Tuesday, buoyed by Wall Street’s tech rally.
Samsung Electronics Co.’s shares traded at 70,300 won as of 10:16 a.m., up 0.86 percent from the previous session. SK hynix Inc. also increased 1.94 percent to 263,000 won.
The trend follows the previous day’s rally in U.S. chip stocks, including Nvidia Corp., which surged 3.62 percent to close at $180.
The PHLX Semiconductor Sector Index also gained 1.75 percent to finish at 5,624.41.
KB Financial Group shares closed at 112,400 won, while those for Shinhan Financial Group closed at 68,000 won, those for Hana Financial Group closed at 84,500 won, and those for Woori Financial Group closed at 24,900 won. Samsung Securities shares closed at 70,100 won and those for Mirae Asset Securities closed at 18,260 won.
Samsung Electronics shares closed at 69,900 won while those for SK hynix closed at 263,500 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean financial and securities stocks, which had plunged last week due to disappointment over the government’s announced tax reform plan, are continuing their rebound for the second consecutive]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.9f5fcd2b1f4747308ceac72a045af1b5_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385446]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
