<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11391271</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>573468</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-12 08:19:42</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[NCSoft targets mobile casual game market with new center]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-12 08:19:42</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.ec56de763aac46ae9828ebfc43803165_P1.jpg' alt=' (NCSoft)'>
NCSoft Corp. is expected to advance into the global casual gaming market with the creation of a new Mobile Casual Center, which will be led by a European industry veteran.
The South Korean game developer announced Monday that it has hired Anel Ceman as a new board member and head of the newly formed center.
The move aims to diversify NCSoft’s global game portfolio and strengthen its competitiveness through artificial intelligence (AI) and data-driven game development.
NCSoft plans to leverage its AI capabilities and data expertise to expand and enhance its presence in the mobile casual game sector, while actively seeking global investment opportunities to boost corporate value and competitiveness.
Ceman brings more than a decade of experience in Europe’s mobile casual game market, having held leadership roles at Tripledot Studios, a U.K.-based casual game developer, and Outfit7, the company behind the popular “Talking Tom” IP.
The launch of the Mobile Casual Center is the latest in a series of NCSoft initiatives to secure new growth engines.
The company has been strengthening both in-house IP development and publishing operations, diversifying its portfolio to include massively multiplayer online (MMO) games, shooting games, and subculture game clusters.
With the new center, NCSoft aims to secure a competitive edge in the mobile casual gaming sector.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[NCSoft Corp. is expected to advance into the global casual gaming market with the creation of a new Mobile Casual Center, which will be led by a European industry veteran. The South Korean game develo]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.ec56de763aac46ae9828ebfc43803165_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (NCSoft)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11391271]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
