<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11386387</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>560601</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-06 11:00:03</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Coupang posts record Q2 revenue on global business growth]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-06 11:00:03</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.27ace1e2cfb240b2a5d18e562fa841f7_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Coupang Inc. reported its highest-ever quarterly revenue in the second quarter of this year, nearing 12 trillion won ($8.52 billion), despite sluggish consumer spending.
The U.S.-listed South Korean e-commerce company said Wednesday that its operating profit for the April-June period reached 209.3 billion won, a reversal from the 34.2 billion won operating loss posted a year earlier.
Net income also swung to a profit of 43.5 billion won, compared to a loss of 143.8 billion won in the same period last year.
This quarter’s operating profit, however, marked a slight decline from the 233.7 billion won posted in the first quarter.
Revenue rose 19 percent on-year to 11.97 trillion won, surpassing the previous record of 11.48 trillion won set in the first quarter. It also marked the first time Coupang’s quarterly revenue topped $8 billion in dollar terms.
Founder and Board Chairman Bom Kim attributed the strong growth to increased spending across all customer cohorts, despite broader weakness in Korea’s consumer market.
“We added 500,000 new Rocket Delivery products this quarter alone, which led to more than a 40 percent year-on-year increase in same-day and dawn deliveries,” he said in a conference call.
The company’s global operations also played a key role. Coupang’s growth businesses, including Taiwan Rocket Delivery, posted a 33 percent increase in sales, helping to fuel the revenue surge.
The company’s core Product Commerce segment—which includes Rocket Delivery, Rocket Fresh, Marketplace, and Rocket Growth—generated 10.3 trillion won in sales, up 17 percent from a year earlier.
The number of active customers rose to 23.9 million, up about 10 percent from 21.7 million last year. Quarterly revenue per active customer climbed 6 percent to 431,340 won ($307).
Sales from the Growth segment—which includes Taiwan, Farfetch, and Coupang Eats—reached a quarterly record of 1.67 trillion won, up 33 percent year-over-year and 15 percent from the previous quarter in dollar terms.
CFO Gaurav Anand said the quarterly loss in adjusted EBITDA for the Growth segment widened 20 percent year-on-year to 330.1 billion won, primarily due to increased investment in Taiwan.
He noted that the company raised its full-year EBITDA loss forecast for growth businesses from $650–750 million to $900–950 million, calling the investment “very encouraging” given the pace of customer spending growth in Taiwan.
Kim expressed confidence in Taiwan’s long-term prospects, noting that its growth trajectory mirrors Coupang’s early expansion years in Korea.
He also pointed to untapped opportunities in verticals like Coupang Eats and Coupang Play, adding, “There’s still tremendous potential in our markets.”
On AI, Kim highlighted that Coupang has long used AI to enhance personalized recommendations, inventory forecasting, and delivery route optimization. “Up to 50 percent of new development code in the initial implementation phase is now written by AI,” he said. “AI will have a transformative impact across Coupang’s operations—including automation and humanoid robotics.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Coupang Inc. reported its highest-ever quarterly revenue in the second quarter of this year, nearing 12 trillion won ($8.52 billion), despite sluggish consumer spending. The U.S.-listed South Korean e]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.27ace1e2cfb240b2a5d18e562fa841f7_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11386387]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
