<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388470</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566207</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:51:53</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[[매경학생기자] How does watching youtube impact your brain?]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>09</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:51:53</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK100801</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[In today’s digital world, phone addiction is a serious problem to discuss, especially for young children whose brains are still in the process of developing. According to research conducted at California State University in 2024, teenagers spend an average of 3 hours per day on their phones, with 31% of them using their phone for 3-4 hours, and 24% surpassing 4 hours. Shockingly, children under 10 years old use their phone for 1 hour 15 minutes every day on average, which was an approximately 17% increase from the year before. People do lots of things using their phones: watch entertaining videos, play games, and educate themselves through helpful applications. Around 60-70% of people use their phones to access YouTube videos.
Many people enjoy watching videos online as they believe it helps to alleviate stress. However, this is not true. In fact, it increases stress, anxiety, and even depression. According to researchers from Griffith University, YouTube viewers, specifically those under 29 years old, expressed higher levels of depression and anxiety, as well as loneliness. Moreover, they also found out that people who spend two hours on YouTube daily are most likely to express these emotions, and those whose watching time exceeds five hours are even more likely.
<strong><div style="border-top: 4px solid #ed6d01;border-bottom: 1px solid #ed6d01;font-size: 18px;padding: 10px 0;margin:30px 0;">Effects of shorts on brain</div></strong>Many people would have experienced difficulties in stopping watching videos on YouTube once they start them. Watching videos, especially shorts, increases the release of dopamine, a neurotransmitter associated with the sensation of reward, which can lead to addiction. Shorts, which are typically under a minute, deliver fast-paced entertainment and can reduce your ability to focus for extended periods. Shorts train your brain to get accustomed to switching focus quickly, making it harder to concentrate on one task for a long time. In addition, the effect on your memory depends on the type of video you are watching. Educational videos make viewers focus and think about many ideas for up to 15 minutes, helping them make connections. In contrast, non-educational videos show shocking or provocative content that grabs attention but doesn‘t encourage viewers to think deeper.
<strong><div style="border-top: 4px solid #ed6d01;border-bottom: 1px solid #ed6d01;font-size: 18px;padding: 10px 0;margin:30px 0;">Impact on younger children</div></strong>The effects listed above are effects on the brain of a fully grown adult. The impact on young children whose brains are still developing will be even greater. Unlike adults’ brains, children’s brains adapt and change very quickly. When they watch educational videos, the brain quickly forms new connections that develop their learning. On the other hand, when they watch non-educational videos, they will have an opposite effect such as reduced concentration level and increased phone addiction. If their brain gets used to constant changes, their brain will crave constant novelty and therefore they will find it hard to adapt to activities that do not have constant change. Also, youngsters find it hard to control their emotions and are likely to imitate the behaviour of their favourite characters or creators they see in videos. Videos with intense emotional content and that expose children to negative behaviour will hinder them from developing proper emotional regulation skills. To add more, as children consume more videos, they are likely to gain skills to access information easily, rather than remember the specific details of a particular situation or information.
<strong><div style="border-top: 4px solid #ed6d01;border-bottom: 1px solid #ed6d01;font-size: 18px;padding: 10px 0;margin:30px 0;">Solutions to this problem</div></strong>Some solutions are to prevent harmful effects caused by video addiction by setting limits on screen time and encouraging children to watch educational videos such as science experiments rather than inappropriate videos that include offensive language and actions. Watching educational videos will help children think more deeply and decrease the risk of diminishing their attention level. It is important to use technology as a tool, not as a babysitter. Parents should also have prior knowledge of how digital activities including social media influences the cognitive development of children’s brains.
<strong><div style="border-top: 4px solid #ed6d01;border-bottom: 1px solid #ed6d01;font-size: 18px;padding: 10px 0;margin:30px 0;">Parents’ Responsibility</div></strong>In conclusion, the level of harmfulness highly depends on what kinds of videos people watch. Parents have a big responsibility in maintaining their child’s mental health and controlling their screen usage, as they are too young to manage themselves.
<b><i>※ External contributions may not be consistent with our editorial direction.</i></b>
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[In today’s digital world, phone addiction is a serious problem to discuss, especially for young children whose brains are still in the process of developing. According to research conducted at Califor]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK100801</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[사회일반]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00504</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[사회]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK100801</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[사회일반]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388470]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
