<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385495</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>557723</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 11:04:15</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hanwha tops market cap growth among Korea’s 10 major conglomerates]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 11:04:15</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.107cf2e9af4d49d6ae10177006c8dd1a_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Hanwha Group has recorded the fastest increase in corporate value this year among South Korea’s top 10 business groups, with gains fueled by its booming defense and shipbuilding units and growing investor optimism following the Korea-U.S. tariff agreement.
The combined market capitalization of Hanwha Group’s 13 listed affiliates reached 120.7 trillion won ($88.1 billion) as of Friday’s close, up 77.2 trillion won from 43.5 trillion won at the end of 2024.
During the same period, the Kospi rose 30.6 percent, and the average growth in market cap among the other top 10 groups, excluding Hanwha, was 30.3 percent, making Hanwha’s growth more than five times higher.
Hanwha’s listed firms accounted for just 2.3 percent of the Kospi’s total market cap of 2,662.7 trillion won at the end of last year. This year, they have contributed 12.9 percent of the Kospi’s total increase of 600.2 trillion won, highlighting their outsized influence on the market.
The group’s rising corporate value is mainly attributed to soaring stock prices in its defense and shipbuilding affiliates—Hanwha Aerospace, Hanwha Ocean, and Hanwha Systems—whose combined market cap stood at 97 trillion won (about $70.8 billion) as of July 31.
Hanwha Aerospace shares surged 245.1 percent, from 326,000 won at the end of last year to 996,000 won at the end of July.
The company posted record-high earnings in the first half of this year, with revenue of 11.86 trillion won and operating profit of 1.43 trillion won. It also completed a 4.2 trillion won capital raise in July through a rights offering.
On March 20, the day Hanwha Aerospace announced the capital increase, its share price stood at 722,000 won, later peaking at 1.035 million won in intraday trading by the end of July, a record high.
Meanwhile, Hanwha Ocean’s stock jumped 200.1 percent, from 37,350 won to 112,300 won, thanks to successful early-stage restructuring and investor enthusiasm over the Korea–U.S. tariff deal.
On Friday, shares closed at 117,400 won, bringing its market cap to 35.97 trillion won, making it the 13th-largest company on the Kospi by market value, overtaking Naver.
Hanwha Ocean’s corporate value has soared more than tenfold in just over two years since its acquisition in mid-2023, when it was valued at around 3 trillion won.
The stock’s sharp rise last week followed reports that Korean shipbuilders, particularly Hanwha Ocean, played a pivotal role in the recent Korea–U.S. tariff negotiations.
As the only Korean shipbuilder with a U.S.-based shipyard—Philly Shipyard, acquired last year—Hanwha Ocean has been advancing local investments, job creation, and technology transfers. Its U.S. operations have served as strategic leverage in the bilateral tariff talks.
Meanwhile, the PLUS Hanwha Group Stocks ETF, launched by Hanwha Asset Management at the end of last year, recently surpassed 180 billion won in net assets.
The fund has returned 151.57 percent year-to-date, making it the best-performing ETF among those tracking major Korean conglomerates.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hanwha Group has recorded the fastest increase in corporate value this year among South Korea’s top 10 business groups, with gains fueled by its booming defense and shipbuilding units and growing inve]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.107cf2e9af4d49d6ae10177006c8dd1a_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385495]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
