<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11404926</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>615068</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-28 12:39:40</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea’s electric bus exports to China fall far behind imports: Data]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-28 12:39:40</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.7fd0bf259dd64e728ee593496ca7bfe7_P1.png' alt=' (MK DB)'>
South Korea’s imports of Chinese electric buses have reached nearly 3,000 times its exports to China, reflecting Beijing’s long-standing subsidy support for domestic companies.
Data from the Korea Customs Service released Wednesday showed that Korea exported just 20 tons of electric buses to China from 2017, when electric bus trade began, through June this year.
Over the same period, imports from China totaled 63,121 tons. With one electric bus weighing about 12 tons, the figures translate to Korea exporting the equivalent of only 1.7 buses over nine years while importing about 5,260.
Analysts noted that until 2023, Beijing published a monthly list of recommended new energy vehicles, which assessed criteria such as driving range, battery type, and motor technology to determine subsidy eligibility. Korean-made electric vehicles (EVs) without Chinese batteries were often excluded.
“Although central government subsidies have since ended, provincial governments continue to grant local subsidies that primarily favor domestic firms,” said Kim Pil-soo, professor of automotive studies at Daelim University. “By contrast, Korea has offered subsidies equally to domestic and imported vehicles, making it easier for Chinese manufacturers to enter the market.”
Kim added that some Korean-made buses also use Chinese modules for core parts, estimating that Chinese electric buses already account for 60 to 70 percent of the Korean market.
Korea has become China’s largest export destination for electric buses.
A study commissioned by the Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy and conducted by INI R&C Co. found that China exported $1.7 billion worth of electric buses worldwide in 2023, with Korea making up 13.3 percent, the highest share. Japan, which has a comparable market environment, accounted for only 3.2 percent.
The domestic electric bus market is expanding rapidly. The share of electric buses in operation jumped from 4.3 percent in 2020 to 21.4 percent as of July last year, according to the study.
Price competitiveness is another factor behind the influx of Chinese buses.
While Korean buses generally use nickel-cobalt-manganese (NCM) batteries, Chinese models rely on cheaper lithium iron phosphate (LFP) batteries, giving them an estimated cost advantage of about 100 million won ($72,000) per unit. Because buses are commercial vehicles, industry officials note that price, rather than brand preference, is the key purchase driver.
Industry representatives argue that private-sector efforts alone will not be enough to narrow the gap. They are calling for tighter purchase subsidy guidelines, improvements in product testing and certification, and policies to encourage domestic manufacturers to lower prices.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s imports of Chinese electric buses have reached nearly 3,000 times its exports to China, reflecting Beijing’s long-standing subsidy support for domestic companies. Data from the Korea Cus]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.7fd0bf259dd64e728ee593496ca7bfe7_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11404926]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
