<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390228</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570461</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 08:59:18</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai’s Avante sedan stages comeback]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 08:59:18</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.580ade901c364838b8dd48a0ca3d6dd4_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
Hyundai Motor Co.’s compact sedan Avante is making a strong comeback, breaking into the top three in sales in a new car market dominated by sport utility vehicles (SUVs).
According to an analysis by Maeil Business Newspaper based on data from car market tracker Car Is You and used car platform Encar.com, the Avante has outsold popular SUV models such as Kia Corp.’s Sportage and Seltos. It has even surpassed Hyundai’s Grandeur, the country’s best-selling sedan.
Car Is You data shows that 39,675 units of the Avante were sold in the new car market during the first half of this year, up 41.5 percent from a year earlier. It ranked third after the Sorento (52,262 units) and Carnival (43,160 units), climbing four places from seventh a year ago. The Grandeur sold 34,798 units and the Seltos 29,488 units during the period.
In July alone, the Avante sold 7,711 units, a 55.1 percent increase from a year earlier, placing it second behind the Sorento (8,127 units).
The model is also performing well in the used car market, which is led by compact cars and SUVs.
The Avante MD sold 11,385 units, ranking eighth overall. Along with the Grandeur and Genesis G80, it remains among the best-selling sedans.
The Avante has become a favored choice among drivers in their 20s.
.com’s analysis of used car transactions from January to July this year showed the Avante CN7 was the most purchased model through its online used car sales service, followed by The New Ray and Casper. The Avante AD ranked fourth, and The New Grandeur IG ranked fifth.
A separate Encar.com survey of domestic used car purchase inquiries by gender and age last year showed similar trends. Among men in their 20s, the Avante CN7 was the most desired model. Among women in their 20s, the Avante CN7 ranked first and the Avante AD fourth. The Avante CN7 also placed sixth among women in their 30s and fourth among women in their 50s.
Industry officials say the Avante appeals to consumers seeking reasonably priced vehicles with a comfortable ride. While it attracts buyers across all age groups, its primary market is drivers in their 20s and 30s.
Current Avante models available in the market offer digital convenience features and safety standards beyond their class, along with a price advantage over compact SUVs.
In the used car market, it is viewed as a high-value first car, typically priced under 20 million won ($14,400).
It is especially popular among younger buyers who find small, cramped compact cars unappealing and large, expensive SUVs burdensome.
“SUVs may be the mainstream these days, but there is still demand for sedans that are comfortable and easy to drive. In the sub-midsize category, the Avante essentially has no real competitors, and its enhanced digital features are driving demand,” an industry insider said. “The model is also gaining popularity as a second car for women over 50.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Co.’s compact sedan Avante is making a strong comeback, breaking into the top three in sales in a new car market dominated by sport utility vehicles (SUVs). According to an analysis by M]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.580ade901c364838b8dd48a0ca3d6dd4_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390228]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
