<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11396858</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>590194</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-19 10:42:51</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Gov’t loan support for overseas resource development stalled for 5 yrs]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-19 10:42:51</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.e2736f668f874e909b911be3f7f70a50_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
The South Korean government’s loan support program for private companies seeking to develop overseas mineral resources has effectively stopped, data showed on Monday.
According to data obtained by the office of Representative Lee Jong-bae of the main opposition People Power Party from the Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy on Monday, budget for the government’s overseas mineral resource development loan program was not executed over the past five years from 2020 to 2024.
The program is designed to provide loans - up to 50 percent of the investment amount - to companies developing overseas mineral resources in order to ensure stable supply.
The issue at hand lies in the government’s extremely insufficient budget compared with corporate investment needs.
The government allocated 1.65 billion won ($1.19 million) to the program in 2024.
The average annual budget over the past five years was only about 1.7 billion won.
Given that a single company typically invests at least 50 to 100 billion won in overseas mineral development, the program’s budget is entirely misaligned with actual demand.
Meanwhile, the country’s lead agency for resource development, Korea Mine Rehabilitation and Mineral Resources Corp. (KOMIR), is effectively barred by law from making its own overseas investments, and government budget support is limited to offering long-term, low-interest loans to cover part of private-sector investments.
In this situation, companies have found little incentive to use the program, leaving it virtually idle.
The Korean resource development industry points to Japan as a model for resource-poor Korea.
Japan, also resource-poor, operates under a structure where the Japan Organization for Metals and Energy Security (JOGMEC) leads overseas resource development.
According to KOMIR, Korea’s domestic resource development rate for six strategic minerals (bituminous coal, uranium, iron, copper, zinc, and nickel) stood at 34.4 percent as of 2023, barely half of Japan’s 69.9 percent.
“Our country has practically abandoned resource development even as resource security grows increasingly important,” Rep. Lee said. “The government must design more tailored policies to match corporate demand and ensure that there are no setbacks in securing essential resources.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean government’s loan support program for private companies seeking to develop overseas mineral resources has effectively stopped, data showed on Monday. According to data obtained by the]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.e2736f668f874e909b911be3f7f70a50_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11396858]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
