<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388469</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566204</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:50:51</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[SK Rent-a-Car, A Rental partner to launch motorcycle fleet monitoring era]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:50:51</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.6204579964ca4a2fae3d56a991ed2151_P1.jpg' alt=' (SK Rent-a-Car)'>
SK Rent-a-Car will develop a motorcycle fleet management system based on its proprietary monitoring solution and supply it exclusively to A Rental & Service, a specialist in motorcycle rentals.
The company said Thursday it had signed a business agreement with A Rental & Service to collaborate on monitoring solutions. The signing ceremony, held Wednesday at A Rental’s headquarters in Gangseo District, Seoul, was attended by SK Rent-a-Car CEO Lee Jeong-hwan, A Rental CEO Lee Sang-yoon, and about a dozen executives from both companies.
Founded in 2004, A Rental is South Korea’s first motorcycle rental specialist and a leader in the domestic two-wheeler leasing market, backed by one of the industry’s largest partner networks. It offers specialized operational services such as insurance, accident response, emergency repairs, and maintenance, serving not only major delivery platforms like Baedal Minjok, Coupang Eats, and Yogiyo, but also security, postal, and food-and-beverage businesses.
Under the agreement, SK Rent-a-Car will exclusively supply A Rental with “A-Link,” a motorcycle-specific monitoring platform developed from its all-in-one vehicle management solution, Smartlink. This marks the first time Smartlink has been applied to motorcycle rentals. A Rental plans to use A-Link’s GPS-based location tracking, driving history logs, and anomaly detection features to build an intelligent motorcycle management framework.
The company expects the adoption of A-Link to improve service quality and operational efficiency. The platform will allow A Rental to calculate driver safety scores, enabling benefits such as lower insurance premiums and preferential rental reviews, ultimately reducing customer costs.
Precision GPS capabilities will also make it possible to respond quickly to accidents, automatically record vehicle check-in and check-out histories, and streamline administrative processes. In addition, real-time vehicle health monitoring will help optimize maintenance schedules, such as replacing parts or scheduling repairs, further enhancing operational stability.
“This collaboration is an important step in expanding SK Rent-a-Car’s vehicle data technology into new areas,” an SK Rent-a-Car official said. “By combining our technology with A Rental’s operational know-how, we aim to set new standards in the motorcycle rental market and deliver differentiated, customer-centric value.”
Smartlink, developed in-house by SK Rent-a-Car in 2016, collects and analyzes real-time driving data from onboard devices, covering over 10,000 vehicle operation metrics. It supports fleet monitoring, car sharing, and other large-scale corporate vehicle operations, with cumulative deployments now surpassing 100,000 vehicles.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[SK Rent-a-Car will develop a motorcycle fleet management system based on its proprietary monitoring solution and supply it exclusively to A Rental & Service, a specialist in motorcycle rentals. The co]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.6204579964ca4a2fae3d56a991ed2151_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (SK Rent-a-Car)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388469]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
