<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393877</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>581929</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 15:14:45</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean budget airline stocks lose altitude as summer demand fizzles]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 15:14:45</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.79235a66875d43e6b457ffbebd0ad17e_P1.png' alt=' (Image generated by DALL·E)'>
South Korean airline stocks are struggling to take off even as the summer travel season hits its peak, weighed down by a slowdown in passenger demand and fading investor sentiment. Smaller budget carriers have been hit hardest.
According to the Korea Exchange on Wednesday, T’way Air shares fell 7.16 percent over the past month, followed by Air Busan, Jeju Air, and Jin Air. Korean Air was the sole gainer, with its stocks rising 2.86 percent.
Industry data suggests the rally in international passenger traffic is losing steam. Ministry of Land, Infrastructure and Transport figures show a mere 4 percent year-on-year increase in July 2025. T’way Air, which launched European routes after the merger between Korean Air and Asiana Airlines, Inc., saw its international passengers drop 8 percent.
Travel to China remains a bright spot, with routes growing more than 20 percent for five consecutive months. But much of that growth has gone to full-service carriers (FSCs).
“China’s recovery has mainly benefited large airlines with secured flight rights,” Korea Investment & Securities Co. analyst Choi Go-woon said, noting that international passenger traffic rose 5 percent for Korean Air and 9 percent for foreign carriers but only 1 percent for budget carriers.
Analysts warn the gap between large FSCs and smaller carriers could widen further. “Budget airliners are locked in a price war as demand weakens on core routes,” NH Investment & Securities Co. analyst Jeong Yeon-seung said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean airline stocks are struggling to take off even as the summer travel season hits its peak, weighed down by a slowdown in passenger demand and fading investor sentiment. Smaller budget carr]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.79235a66875d43e6b457ffbebd0ad17e_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Image generated by DALL·E)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393877]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
