<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402173</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>606302</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-25 14:27:13</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[LG Uplus, Korean police team up to combat voice phishing]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-25 14:27:13</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.83d2219f3ce3484cb9c238ac3623325e_P1.png' alt=' (LG Uplus)'>
LG Uplus said Sunday it has signed a memorandum of understanding with the Korean National Police Agency to help eradicate voice phishing. Reached on August 22nd, 2025, the agreement focuses not only on technical cooperation and information sharing but on building a systematic response to block voice phishing as well.
Under the partnership, LG Uplus will provide data related to voice phishing, including abnormal patterns detected in its telecom infrastructure, logs of malicious app control servers, suspicious text forwarding numbers, and relay device information. The police agency will integrate this data with its crime database and investigative information to strengthen real-time response systems. LG Uplus will also share phishing-related data collected via the voice phishing detection feature of its AI app “ixi-O,” enabling a framework that spans from early detection to immediate action and post-crime investigation. While public-private cooperation to prevent voice phishing existed before, this is the first collaboration by a Korean telecom operator leveraging AI technology, according to the company.
The two sides will also cooperate to protect victims of voice and smishing scams. LG Uplus stores will serve as initial “safe shelters” for victims, providing emergency response and first-line support before the handover to the police that will prevent further losses.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[LG Uplus said Sunday it has signed a memorandum of understanding with the Korean National Police Agency to help eradicate voice phishing. Reached on August 22nd, 2025, the agreement focuses not only o]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.83d2219f3ce3484cb9c238ac3623325e_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (LG Uplus)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402173]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
