<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402008</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>605628</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-25 11:28:34</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hanwha Ocean to invest $70 mn for Philly Shipyard expansion]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-25 11:28:34</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.8607dab096ac40bfbe80799cc27cc847_P1.png' alt=' (Hanwha Ocean)'>
Hanwha Ocean Co. will invest at least $70 million to expand its Philadelphia shipyard, with plans to raise annual dock productivity to about 10 vessels by 2035 as well as accelerating the adoption of automation and smart systems.
According to shipbuilding industry sources on Sunday, the White House recently disclosed major foreign investment plans in the United States, including Hanwha Ocean’s $70 million commitment to the Philly Shipyard expansion.
Although questions about the value of the deal lingered When Hanwha acquired the yard, sentiment shifted after U.S. President Donald Trump signaled interest in closer shipbuilding cooperation with South Korea. The facility is now emerging as the symbol of a Korea-U.S. partnership project referred to as Make American Shipbuilding Great Again (MASGA).
The Philly Shipyard currently only builds only 1 to 1.5 vessels a year, highlighting the urgent need for expansion. “The yard’s productivity and construction capacity reflect the lag in U.S. shipbuilding,” an industry official said. “There is significant room to improve efficiency via new investment.”
If Hanwha Ocean raises capacity to 10 ships annually, the yard could operate as a mid-sized shipbuilder with projected annual revenue of $4 billion. It is also gaining importance as a hub for the maintenance, repair, and overhaul of U.S. Navy vessels, drawing on Korean shipbuilding expertise. Korean President Lee Jae-myung also plans to visit the yard on Tuesday local time to underscore its role as a symbol of bilateral shipbuilding cooperation.
“The fact that the additional investment, long mentioned only as a possibility, was announced by the White House with a concrete figure is significant,” another industry official said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hanwha Ocean Co. will invest at least $70 million to expand its Philadelphia shipyard, with plans to raise annual dock productivity to about 10 vessels by 2035 as well as accelerating the adoption of ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/25/news-p.v1.20250825.8607dab096ac40bfbe80799cc27cc847_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hanwha Ocean)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402008]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
