<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11404919</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>615063</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-28 12:39:07</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[OpenAI to launch its third Asian office in Seoul]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-28 12:39:07</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.f609e2eb52364c99813009ac9780e18f_P1.png' alt=' (Reuters/Yonhap)'>
OpenAI Korea is set to officially enter the South Korean market with a launch event next month.
According to ICT industry sources on Thursday, OpenAI Korea will hold a press briefing on September 10, serving as its official opening ceremony.
The Seoul office, located on Teheran-ro in Gangnam, will be housed in a shared office space, with the press briefing substituting for a formal opening event.
Jason Kwon, OpenAI’s Chief Strategy Officer (CSO), will attend the briefing to present the company’s vision for its operations in Korea.
The head of OpenAI Korea, whose recruitment is currently underway, is also expected to be announced during the event.
Since May, OpenAI Korea has been hiring about 10 staff across six different roles.
In addition, OpenAI announced the launch of Creative Lab Seoul, a domestic program supporting local creators.
The Creative Lab is a global initiative by OpenAI to support creators, and Creative Lab Seoul marks the first iteration of the program in South Korea.
The program will feature 21 participants, who will use OpenAI’s video generation tool Sora and ChatGPT ImageGen for creative projects.
Participants will gain access to creative tools, hands-on learning, networking with the global creative community, and opportunities to showcase their works.
OpenAI identified the core values of the Creative Lab as creator-centric focus, transparency and trust, community orientation, and tangible support.
Furthermore, OpenAI will continue its local engagement by collaborating with the Seoul Design Foundation, including participation in the Seoul Light Dongdaemun Design Plaza (DDP) 2025 Autumn media façade festival.
Headquartered in San Francisco, OpenAI maintains offices in the UK, France, and Germany, with Asian offices in Japan and Singapore.
The Seoul office will be OpenAI’s 12th globally and the third in Asia.
South Korea ranks second globally in ChatGPT paid subscribers after the United States, and in May, domestic ChatGPT monthly active users (MAU) surpassed 10 million. Seoul also has the highest number of users for OpenAI’s video generation tools.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[OpenAI Korea is set to officially enter the South Korean market with a launch event next month. According to ICT industry sources on Thursday, OpenAI Korea will hold a press briefing on September 10, ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.f609e2eb52364c99813009ac9780e18f_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Reuters/Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11404919]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
