<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388468</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566194</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:48:13</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KIET encourages development of customized strategies for key industries]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:48:13</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.a7311326fd3844599afeedd6e00eb685_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korea should craft tailored upgrading strategies for its core industries while actively nurturing new growth engines such as white biotechnology, a state-run think tank said on Thursday.
The Korea Institute for Industrial Economics & Trade (KIET) published a four-part series of reports under the theme, “Strategies and Challenges for the Leap Forward of Korean Industries” on Thursday.
The reports cover an assessment of the current status of Korean industries and the challenges they face, 10 key policy tasks across four major areas, advancement strategies for the country’s 10 key industries, and strategies for eight new growth engines.
KIET identified semiconductors, secondary batteries, automobiles, steel, and chemicals among the 10 key industries. For each sector, it proposed tailored advancement strategies.
For the semiconductor industry, it stressed the need to seize opportunities arising from changes in the U.S.-led division of labor and the growing demand for data centers.
It noted that the U.S.’s push to attract advanced manufacturing facilities to its own soil under the banner of “de-risking from China” could be an opportunity.
For shipbuilding, the report pointed to the need for the development and commercialization of eco-friendly autonomous ships, as well as the formulation of global expansion strategies through smart shipyards.
The institute identified eight new industries with potential to become Korea’s future growth drivers: advanced biopharmaceuticals, white biotechnology, future mobility, advanced robotics, digital healthcare, defense and space, and offshore wind power.
White biotechnology refers to industries that replace traditional fossil fuel-based chemical and energy sectors with biomass-based alternatives.
KIET advised focusing technology development on product groups where a shift of biomass offers advantages.
For offshore wind power, it suggested stimulating initial demand and providing financial support to grow the domestic offshore wind supply chain. It also emphasized the need to overcome the structural stagnation in offshore wind deployment through policy shifts.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea should craft tailored upgrading strategies for its core industries while actively nurturing new growth engines such as white biotechnology, a state-run think tank said on Thursday. The Kor]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.a7311326fd3844599afeedd6e00eb685_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388468]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
