<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11391237</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>573399</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-12 07:02:58</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea to introduce credit pardon policy for 3.24mn people]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-12 07:02:58</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.8eb4e23694624143b2d3afb3a1f40f80_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
The South Korean government will implement a credit pardon policy that deletes the delinquency records of 3.24 million people who have faithfully repaid debts of 50 million won ($35,950) or less incurred after the Covid-19 outbreak.
The Financial Services Commission announced on Monday that it will help small business owners with debt, who were hit by Covid-19 and economic slowdown caused by high interest rates, “to return to normal economic activity.”
“We will temporarily implement a credit recovery support measure, restricting the sharing and use of delinquency history information from September 30th, 2025, onwards,” it said.
The credit pardon applies to individuals with arrears of 50 million won or less from personal or sole-proprietor loans incurred between January 2020 and August 2025, provided they fully repay their debts by the end of this year.
If they settle their debts within the year, their delinquency history will be erased from credit records and thus allow them to resume normal financial activities such as taking out loans and using credit cards.
A total of 3.24 million people are eligible for this credit recovery support measure. Of these, 2.72 million have already repaid their debts and are confirmed for support. The remaining 520,000 will also qualify for the credit pardon if they clear their debts by year-end.
The delinquency amount is based on the outstanding loan principal registered by financial institutions with the Korea Credit Information Services.
The government also carried out credit pardons in 2021 and 2024. At that time, the eligibility limit was 20 million won or less, but the ceiling was expanded to 50 million won this year.
“We considered the prolonged impact of Covid-19 and the ongoing high-interest rate environment, as well as the fact that the debt adjustment standard for long-term small-scale delinquent debts is set at 50 million won or less,” the FSC said.
However, critics warn that combining debt write-offs through bad banks with credit pardons could heighten moral hazard as it may foster the perception among well-intentioned borrowers that they do not need to repay their debts.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean government will implement a credit pardon policy that deletes the delinquency records of 3.24 million people who have faithfully repaid debts of 50 million won ($35,950) or less incur]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.8eb4e23694624143b2d3afb3a1f40f80_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11391237]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
