<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11391465</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>574182</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-12 11:07:14</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[CJ CheilJedang’s Q2 OP down 11.3% on weak domestic consumption]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-12 11:07:14</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.498b8c0ad0c24b4483b63dc33b9f18eb_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
South Korean food giant CJ CheilJedang Corp. saw its second-quarter 2025 operating profit fall 11.3 percent, excluding its subsidiary CJ Logistics Corp.
CJ CheilJedang said on Tuesday that its preliminary operating profit for the second quarter of the year stood at 235.1 billion won ($168.91 million), excluding CJ Logistics, which was down 11.3 percent from the same period a year ago.
This is the second consecutive quarter of decline following the first quarter. Sales came to 4.32 trillion won in the April to June 2025 period, a 0.2 percent drop year-on-year.
Including CJ Logistics, sales were 7.24 trillion won, down 1.5 billion won, while operating profit fell 7.9 percent to 353.1 billion won. Net profit rose 41.5 percent to 209.1 billion won.
In the food business segment, sales fell 1 percent to 2.69 trillion won, and operating profit plunged 34 percent to 90.1 billion won. Domestic food sales dropped 5 percent to 1.32 trillion won due to sluggish offline channels amid weak domestic consumption, while online processed food sales grew 24 percent.
Overseas food sales increased 3 percent to 1.37 trillion won, driven by higher brand recognition for Bibigo and expanded entry into major retail channels in countries such as the United States, Europe, Oceania, and Japan.
In North America, which accounts for the largest share of overseas sales, the company posted 1.11 trillion won in revenue on the back of solid growth in frozen rice (up 19 percent), chicken (up 12 percent), rolls (up 18 percent), and pizza (up 6 percent).
In Japan, a key market for K-food expansion, sales surged 37 percent thanks to strong demand for fruit vinegar “Micho” and dumplings.
Bibigo also secured dedicated brand shelves in Japanese discount store chain Don Quijote’s nationwide stores - adding to placements in Aeon, Costco, Amazon, and Rakuten – while also accelerating local expansion by building a new production base in Chiba Prefecture.
The company also saw steady growth in Europe, with sales rising 25 percent after Bibigo entered major U.K. retailers such as Morrisons in the first quarter of 2025, following earlier placements in France’s Leclerc and Carrefour.
The bio business segment posted 1.08 trillion won in sales, up 2 percent year-on-year, and 102.4 billion won in operating profit, up 8 percent.
Despite high base effects from the previous year’s strong performance in high-value-added products such as tryptophan and specialty amino acids, revenue and profit grew thanks to higher lysine prices and expanded sales of soy protein concentrate (SPC).
In particular, histidine for animal feed, one of the specialty products, recorded an 88 percent growth rate thanks to rising demand in the salmon feed market and expanded global market share.
The feed & care segment posted 555.3 billion won in sales, down 3 percent, and 42.6 billion won in operating profit, up 25 percent.
Although sales declined due to falling feed prices, profitability improved significantly thanks to strong performance in Vietnam’s livestock business and structural reforms focusing on margins.
CJ CheilJedang plans to accelerate the global expansion of K-food in the second half of this year by establishing a production base in Japan and scaling up its Global Strategic Products (GSP).
The domestic food business will seek sales growth by speeding up digital transformation and launching products that reflect consumer trends in health and convenience.
The bio business will continue its growth through its 10 global production bases, including in the United States, and its cost competitiveness, while diversifying its portfolio of specialty products such as arginine, histidine, valine, and TasteNrich.
In the case of lysine, a favorable business environment is expected to continue due to the European Union and the United States imposing tariffs on Chinese products.
“With our OnlyOne spirit of being the first, the best, and differentiated, we will strengthen our structural competitiveness, accelerate innovative growth, and secure future growth engines to leap forward as a global leading company,” a CJ CheilJedang official said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean food giant CJ CheilJedang Corp. saw its second-quarter 2025 operating profit fall 11.3 percent, excluding its subsidiary CJ Logistics Corp. CJ CheilJedang said on Tuesday that its prelimi]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.498b8c0ad0c24b4483b63dc33b9f18eb_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11391465]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
