<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390344</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570897</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 10:38:21</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea’s grocery prices see steepest rise in a year in July]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 10:38:21</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.3e54fefca154484086fa43c179e8863c_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Food prices in South Korea posted their steepest rise in a year in July, underscoring growing cost pressures on low-income households.
According to data from Statistics Korea on Monday, the food and non-alcoholic beverage price index reached 125.75 in July, up 3.5 percent from a year earlier.
The increase far outpaced the overall consumer price growth of 2.1 percent and marked the sharpest gain since July 2024, when prices rose 3.6 percent.
After hovering between 2 percent and 3 percent from late last year to May, food inflation has now hit 3 percent for two straight months, driven by extreme weather conditions, including heatwaves and heavy rain, as well as sustained increases in wholesale prices of processed foods.
Fish and seafood prices jumped 7.2 percent in July, staying above 7 percent for the second consecutive month and hitting their highest level in two years.
Dried squid surged 42.9 percent, anchovies rose 13.4 percent, and mackerel gained 12 percent. Bread and grains climbed 6.6 percent, the fastest pace in nearly two years, while rice rose 7.6 percent—its first increase above 7 percent since March 2024.
Instant noodle prices gained 6.5 percent, extending a streak of three months above that level.
Other notable increases included snacks, ice cream, sugar, and eggs.
Among non-alcoholic beverages, coffee, tea, and cocoa prices jumped 13.5 percent, while bottled water, soft drinks, and juices rose 3.4 percent.
Rising public service prices are also adding to household strain.
After staying below 1 percent last year, the public service price index rose 1.4 percent in July following a subway fare hike in Seoul.
Concerns grow that households could face even greater financial pressure if the government pushes for potential hikes in electricity, gas, and railway fares later this year.
The Lee Jae-myung administration pledged earlier to keep public utility rates frozen in the first half of 2025.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Food prices in South Korea posted their steepest rise in a year in July, underscoring growing cost pressures on low-income households. According to data from Statistics Korea on Monday, the food and n]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.3e54fefca154484086fa43c179e8863c_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390344]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
