<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11396922</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>590405</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-19 11:22:51</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hankook Tire supplies high-performance EV tires for BMW iX]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-19 11:22:51</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.55dd95a9145b43979d01640715293705_P1.png' alt=' (Hankook Tire &amp; Technology)'>
Hankook Tire & Technology Co. said Tuesday it will supply its high-performance EV tire and its all-season variant as original equipment for BMW’s electric SUV iX.
To support the iX’s performance of over 500 horsepower, Hankook applied its proprietary iON Innovative Technology to both tires.
The iON evo SUV reduces in-cabin noise by up to 18 percent and enhances cornering stiffness by 10 percent.
It also significantly reduces rolling resistance, boosting energy efficiency by up to 6 percent. The use of eco-friendly compound materials cuts down on wear, extending mileage by up to 15 percent.
The iON evo AS SUV, designed for all-season performance, features a low-noise tread pattern, an EV-specific compound and cold-temperature vulcanization technology to reduce noise and rolling resistance while improving drive performance and energy efficiency.
This is Hankook’s second OE supply for a BMW electric vehicle, following its first in 2022 for the BMW i4 electric coupe.
The company has also been supplying tires exclusively for BMW’s seventh-generation M5 high-performance sedan since last year.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hankook Tire & Technology Co. said Tuesday it will supply its high-performance EV tire and its all-season variant as original equipment for BMW’s electric SUV iX. To support the iX’s performance of ov]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/19/news-p.v1.20250819.55dd95a9145b43979d01640715293705_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hankook Tire &amp; Technology)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11396922]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
