<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11399030</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>596589</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-21 10:26:44</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[FSS chief stresses ‘consumer protection,’ financial sector on edge]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-21 10:26:44</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.641b6d0b94ff4462bd22d50ed04f5aa6_P1.png' alt=' FSS governor Lee Chan-jin. (Yonhap)'>
Lee Chan-jin, the new Financial Supervisory Service (FSS) governor, stressed “consumer protection” at his first internal meeting after taking office, suggesting stronger oversight ahead. Given Lee’s long career with the civic group People’s Solidarity for Participatory Democracy, many in the financial sector believe he will put strong emphasis on safeguarding consumer rights.
At his inaugural executive meeting on Wednesday, Lee told participants, “Consumer protection must always be kept in mind when carrying out all tasks going forward.” Officials noted that he generally remained attentive during other reports and primarily spoke up in matters related to consumer protection. “He has consistently highlighted this as part of his philosophy, and since the new administration is pursuing the same direction, it appears natural that this was his first request,” an FSS official explained.
Lee had already declared at his inauguration ceremony on August 14th, 2025, that he would “work to innovate the organizational system of the Consumer Protection Bureau and enhance professionalism and efficiency.” He also pledged to “significantly strengthen monitoring of consumer protection practices in the financial sector and actively employ supervisory and inspection powers when necessary.”
Observers view Lee’s remarks as a call to shift the FSS’s traditional focus on mainly inspecting and regulating financial institutions and capital markets toward ensuring consumer rights.
Discussions are also ongoing regarding potential changes to financial regulatory structures, including proposals to separate the FSS Consumer Protection Bureau and establish it as an independent Financial Consumer Protection Agency. If given inspection authority, such an agency would place additional regulatory burdens on financial firms.
President Lee Jae-myung previously vowed during his presidential campaign to significantly expand consumer protection, including introducing the “one-sided binding effect.” Under this system, when disputes arise between financial firms and consumers, the companies are legally bound to comply with dispute settlement proposals from regulators once the consumer accepts them. The Presidential Committee on Policy Planning has also suggested lowering the monetary threshold for eligible cases from the current 30 million won ($22,060) under the Small Claims Act.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Lee Chan-jin, the new Financial Supervisory Service (FSS) governor, stressed “consumer protection” at his first internal meeting after taking office, suggesting stronger oversight ahead. Given Lee’s l]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.641b6d0b94ff4462bd22d50ed04f5aa6_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ FSS governor Lee Chan-jin. (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11399030]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
