<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387332</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>562938</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 09:42:00</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[HD Hyundai wins first U.S. Navy ship maintenance deal]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 09:42:00</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.193c8c1a37ac41d79dd3ac68a8c926cd_P1.png' alt=' (HD Hyundai Heavy Industries)'>
HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. has secured its first contract for maintenance, repair, and overhaul (MRO) services for a non-combat U.S. Navy vessel.
The company announced Wednesday that it recently won a contract to carry out scheduled maintenance on the USNS Alan Shepard, a 41,000-ton supply ship operated under the U.S. Navy‘s Seventh Fleet.
Work will begin in September at a dock near HD Hyundai Mipo in Ulsan on Korea’s east coast and will include propeller cleaning, tank servicing, and equipment inspections.
The vessel is scheduled to be delivered back to the U.S. Navy in November.
Commissioned in 2007, the USNS Alan Shepard is 210 meters long, 32 meters wide, and 9.4 meters high. It is named after Alan Shepard, the first American astronaut in space and a former U.S. Navy officer.
“This is the first MRO contract awarded since the launch of the Make American Shipbuilding Great Again (MASGA) initiative, a U.S.-Korea effort to revive American shipbuilding and modernize the U.S. Navy using Korean expertise,” said Joo Won-ho, head of HD Hyundai Heavy Industries’ special ship division.
HD Hyundai Heavy Industries has been actively pursuing cooperation with the U.S. shipbuilding sector.
In April, the company signed a memorandum of understanding with Huntington Ingalls Industries Inc., the largest U.S. naval shipbuilder.
In July, the two sides discussed ways to enhance shipbuilding productivity. The collaboration is expected to transfer Korea’s shipbuilding expertise and experience to the United States.
HD Hyundai is also participating in workforce training programs as part of the Korea-U.S. shipbuilding partnership to help rebuild the American shipbuilding industry.
In June, it hosted the Korea-U.S. shipbuilding cooperation expert forum, which included participants from major Korean universities and six U.S. universities, focusing on naval and ocean engineering.
In addition, HD Hyundai has partnered with U.S. shipbuilding group Edison Chouest Offshore (ECO) for joint construction and technical collaboration in both naval and commercial ship sectors.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. has secured its first contract for maintenance, repair, and overhaul (MRO) services for a non-combat U.S. Navy vessel. The company announced Wednesday that it recently ]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.193c8c1a37ac41d79dd3ac68a8c926cd_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (HD Hyundai Heavy Industries)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387332]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
