<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402924</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>608675</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-26 11:18:33</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[LocknLock sets up Indian subsidiary]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-26 11:18:33</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[LocknLock, a global household goods company, announced on Monday it has established a subsidiary in India as part of its plan to accelerate market expansion with products tailored to local consumer preferences.
The Mumbai-based office is the company’s seventh overseas subsidiary, following those in China, Vietnam, and the United States, and will serve as a hub to boost exports.
<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.32905d67e40c4ef78224dca58df7956e_P1.png' alt=' LocknLock booth at the ‘HGH India’ home and lifestyle exhibition held in Mumbai, India, in July. (LocknLock)'>
As part of its push, LocknLock participated in the HGH India home and lifestyle exhibition in Mumbai in July, where it received positive reviews from consumers and industry officials. It also won the Innovation Product Award in recognition of product excellence.
In India, LocknLock’s Classic and Euro food storage containers and tumblers account for a significant portion of sales. To strengthen its premium positioning, the company is preparing to launch its Metro premium tumbler series, redesigned with features and styles suited to Indian consumers.
“India is a high-potential market with a young demographic and rapid growth outlook,” said Jeoung Jae-won, head of LocknLock India. “We aim to position ourselves as a premium lifestyle brand by leveraging differentiated product competitiveness and expanding our presence across both online and offline channels.”
LocknLock currently exports to over 120 countries worldwide. The company plans to expand into new markets such as India, Europe, and Latin America, while also diversifying products in its existing key markets to increase its global market share.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[LocknLock, a global household goods company, announced on Monday it has established a subsidiary in India as part of its plan to accelerate market expansion with products tailored to local consumer pr]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.32905d67e40c4ef78224dca58df7956e_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ LocknLock booth at the ‘HGH India’ home and lifestyle exhibition held in Mumbai, India, in July. (LocknLock)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402924]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
