<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390171</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570346</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 07:59:20</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Demand for luxury watches, jewelry rises in Korea]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 07:59:20</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.dcf29c0f7c47468f9993ddf209c24eed_P1.jpg' alt=' (AFPYonhap News)'>
Demand for luxury watches and jewelry is on the rise in South Korea, recent data showed.
Maeil Business Newspaper asked Korea’s three major department store chains to compare watch and jewelry sales from January to July 2025 with the same period during the previous year.
The results showed that Lotte Department Store sales jumped 33 percent, Shinsegae Department Store sales increased 35 percent, and Hyundai Department Store sales climbed 34 percent.
Industry insiders in the retail and luxury sectors cite three main factors driving this growth: scarcity, stronger value retention, and a preference for authentic goods.
“Young adult women in Korea love designer bags – maybe not always Hermes or Chanel, but most own at least one from well-known brands like Louis Vuitton, Gucci, Celine, or Saint Laurent. But since everyone is carrying luxury bags these days, luxury watches and jewelry are getting more attention.”
A department store representative also noted that “before Covid-19, luxury watches and jewelry were mostly seen as wedding gifts, so engaged couples were the main big spenders.”
“But now, more people see watches and jewelry as a way to express their personality and identity in everyday life, so demand has risen,” the representative said.
Another factor driving the trend is that, after wearing them for a while, people can resell high-end watches and jewelry at prices close to – or even higher than – what they originally paid.
The rise in luxury watch buyers has also boosted the resale market. Viver, a platform dealing in brands including Rolex, Breguet, and Patek Philippe, handled around 15 billion won ($10 million) in watch deals last month alone.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Demand for luxury watches and jewelry is on the rise in South Korea, recent data showed. Maeil Business Newspaper asked Korea’s three major department store chains to compare watch and jewelry sales f]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.dcf29c0f7c47468f9993ddf209c24eed_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (AFPYonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390171]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
