<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11404925</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>615059</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-28 12:39:29</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[LG H&H moves to sell beverage unit Haitai htb]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-28 12:39:29</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.1bbc20483f16429797715d05c88281fa_P1.png' alt=' (LG Household &amp; Health Care)'>
LG Household & Health Care is considering the sale of its beverage subsidiary Haitai htb as part of its portfolio restructuring to focus more on its core cosmetics business.
According to investment banking industry sources on Wednesday, LG Household & Health Care has engaged Samjong KPMG to pursue the sale of Haitai htb, with the deal value estimated at around 250 billion won ($179.36 million).
LG H&H’s beverage division, which includes Haitai htb and Coca-Cola under its umbrella, posted 1.82 trillion won in revenue and 168.1 billion won in operating profit last year. While revenue edged up 1 percent from a year earlier, operating profit declined 21.9 percent.
Haitai htb, formerly Haitai Beverage, was acquired by LG Household & Health Care in 2010 from Asahi Breweries and other shareholders, with LG taking full ownership. The company was renamed Haitai htb in 2016. The acquisition was initially intended to broaden LG’s beverage portfolio beyond Coca-Cola alongside its cosmetics and household goods businesses.
Since then, Haitai htb has expanded its product line with brands such as Sunkist and Coco Palm. However, the company reported revenue of 414 billion won and an operating profit of 3.6 billion won in 2024, down 1.3 percent and 74 percent, respectively, from the previous year.
An LG H&H spokesperson said the company is “reviewing various options, including business restructuring, but nothing has been decided yet.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[LG Household & Health Care is considering the sale of its beverage subsidiary Haitai htb as part of its portfolio restructuring to focus more on its core cosmetics business. According to investment ba]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.1bbc20483f16429797715d05c88281fa_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (LG Household &amp; Health Care)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11404925]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
