<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402921</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>608659</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-26 11:18:22</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[SK innovation to sell petrochemical units in U.S., France]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-26 11:18:22</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.e90c3dfd4c964fb09283451cb76a9bfe_P1.png' alt=' SK innovation CI'>
SK innovation Co., an integrated energy and materials company under South Korea’s SK Group, has decided to sell its petrochemical subsidiaries in the United States and France, which it acquired to strengthen its high-value materials business.
According to sources from the investment banking (IB) industry on Monday, SK geo centric Co., a chemical subsidiary of SK innovation, is working with overseas advisors to approach foreign buyers to sell its packaging materials businesses acquired from Dow Chemical in the U.S. and Arkema in France.
The assets up for sale include the ethylene acrylic acid (EAA) and polyvinylidene chloride (PVDC) businesses acquired from Dow Chemical in 2017, and the functional polyolefin business purchased from Arkema in 2019.
At the time, SK innovation designated packaging materials as a next-generation growth engine, with an aim to elevate SK geo centric into one of the world’s top 10 chemical companies.
EAA and PVDC are widely used in food and beverage, cosmetics, and pharmaceutical packaging, while polyolefin is applied to food packaging and wire insulation.
The business segments performed well during the Covid-19 pandemic due to rising demand for packaging, but have since struggled as oversupply from Chinese and other competitors weighed on results.
Market watchers are also paying attention to whether SK geo centric will accelerate its merger with Korea Petrochemical Ind. Co. (KPIC), which involves its Ulsan naphtha cracker (NCC) operations.
SK innovation did not confirm details related to the asset sale but it noted that “various options are under discussion.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[SK innovation Co., an integrated energy and materials company under South Korea’s SK Group, has decided to sell its petrochemical subsidiaries in the United States and France, which it acquired to str]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.e90c3dfd4c964fb09283451cb76a9bfe_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ SK innovation CI]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402921]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
