<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11399028</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>596591</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-21 10:26:43</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Mirae Asset’s AUM nears $741 bn on strong overseas business]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-21 10:26:43</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.8b76a919412140278044d4ed2b3f23d1_P1.png' alt=' (Mirae Asset)'>
South Korea’s Mirae Asset Financial Group is seeing its assets under management (AUM) near 1,000 trillion won ($740.74 billion) as its overseas business begins to gain full momentum.
According to Mirae Asset on Wednesday, its total client assets managed across domestic and overseas markets amounted to 987 trillion won. Of the amount, Mirae Asset Securities Co.’s overseas subsidiaries managed 79.4 trillion won, while Mirae Asset Global Investments Co.’s overseas affiliates managed 185.3 trillion won.
The numbers show that 27 percent of the group’s client assets come from overseas subsidiaries and affiliates.
Mirae Asset has invested more than 800 billion won in innovative companies such as SpaceX, X (formerly Twitter), and xAI since 2022.
It has positioned its global strategy as a central growth axis by actively sourcing major deals through its global network.
Chairman Park Hyeon-joo has also stressed the importance of entering global markets through bold overseas expansion and mergers and acquisitions (M&A).
Reflecting this vision, the group has been executing strategic M&A and investments.
In November 2024, Mirae Asset completed the acquisition of Mirae Asset Sharekhan in India, aiming to gain an early foothold in the country’s fast-growing securities industry and create group-wide business synergies.
The group’s overseas business performance has also strengthened. Its U.S. subsidiary achieved its highest-ever quarterly results in the fourth quarter of 2024.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s Mirae Asset Financial Group is seeing its assets under management (AUM) near 1,000 trillion won ($740.74 billion) as its overseas business begins to gain full momentum. According to Mira]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.8b76a919412140278044d4ed2b3f23d1_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Mirae Asset)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11399028]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
