<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11395752</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>587270</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-18 10:47:46</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean donut brand wins over U.S. customers with unique treats]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-18 10:47:46</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.7990b66b923b4ed4a1ed33d7e17eaa08_P1.png' alt=' CEO Lee Joon-beum. (Lee Seung-hwan)'>
Korean donut brand Knotted, which first gained fame in Seoul for its cream-filled pastries, is now making a splash in the United States. The brand has quickly won over American consumers with its signature Milk Cream Donut, which has garnered praised for its soft, fluffy texture and unique cream filling.
“Americans call Knotted donuts ‘ice cream-like donuts.’ Our signature Milk Cream Donut is filled with fresh cream. It may look very sweet from the outside, but when you take a bite, it is not overly sugary but is soft, fluffy, and creamy. That unique texture is what Americans really love,” Lee Joon-beum, CEO of Knotted’s operator GFFG said.
Debuting in Korea in 2018, Knotted once earned nicknames such as “life-changing donut” and “sell-out frenzy,” particularly among young female consumers, and is making waves in the United States, the birthplace of donuts. Despite steady growth for about five years in Korea’s highly competitive food and beverage market, the brand eventually plateaued. Its parent company GFFG decided to shift focus from offline store expansion in Korea toward online channels while pursuing overseas markets for new growth. The group streamlined its portfolio from more than 10 dining brands down to a few core names – Knotted, Hojokban, and Clap Pizza - with Knotted accounting for most of its revenue.
After more than a year of preparation, Lee opened Knotted’s first directly operated store in Los Angeles in April 2025. The company’s first overseas venture drew 30,000 visitors in its first month alone.
Lee added that Knotted plans to open a second U.S. location in downtown Los Angeles’ Arts District that will be a combined venue featuring both Knotted and Hojokban, a Korean fusion dining brand, within the year.
The company is also targeting the Australian market and preparing to launch its first store in Sydney under a master franchise agreement by the end of 2025. Thanks to the strong overseas reception, GFFG has set its revenue target at 70 billion won for the year, or up 11 percent from the previous year’s 63 billion won.
In addition to overseas expansion, GFFG is strengthening its intellectual property (IP) business, which has been a key driver of Knotted’s rapid growth. Character-based merchandise such as Knotted’s “Sugar Bear” line has fueled the brand’s popularity, and Lee said the company is also exploring offline events alongside other initiatives that leverages its IP.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Korean donut brand Knotted, which first gained fame in Seoul for its cream-filled pastries, is now making a splash in the United States. The brand has quickly won over American consumers with its sign]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.7990b66b923b4ed4a1ed33d7e17eaa08_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ CEO Lee Joon-beum. (Lee Seung-hwan)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11395752]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
