<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384349</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554069</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 06:55:15</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[CU convenience stores thrive aboard Korea-China ferries]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 06:55:15</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-04 06:56:18</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.3350e996c7ba4ded9d4d1bf62453fe00_P1.jpg' alt=' (CU)'>
CU, the convenience store chain operated by BGF Retail Co., is seeing strong sales growth at its ferry-based outlets serving Korea–China routes.
According to industry sources on Sunday, CU operates two ferry stores, CU Weidong Ferry Weihai and CU Weidong Ferry Qingdao, aboard the New Golden Bridge ferry.
The vessel runs three times a week between Incheon and the Chinese cities of Weihai and Qingdao. Since their launch in October last year, the stores have gained steady popularity.
Although located on a ship, the ferry outlets closely resemble regular CU stores in both layout and product selection. Occupying about 33 square meters, each outlet stocks more than 1,500 items, including beverages, alcohol, instant noodles, ready-to-eat meals, and ice cream.
Korean souvenirs such as keyrings, fans, and mugs are also available for travelers.
Passenger response has been positive.
Previously, travelers had to purchase essentials before boarding, but now they can shop onboard for a wide range of food, beverages, and necessities, boosting satisfaction and sales alike.
“Sales are more than five times higher than domestic ferry stores and above forecast,” said an official from BGF Retail.
Average sales are currently about 26 percent higher than at opening last year. Top-selling categories include alcohol, ice cream, instant noodles, side dishes, and snacks.
Recently, Peaceminusone Highball, an alcoholic beverage created in collaboration with Korean pop star G‑Dragon’s fashion brand of the same name, has performed particularly well.
Roughly 70 percent of customers are Chinese. The visa-free entry to China, implemented late last year, has sharply increased ferry passenger traffic, fueling CU’s optimism.
The company expects further growth if Korea introduces a temporary visa-free program for Chinese group tourists in the third quarter.
Opening ferry-based stores presented operational challenges. The most pressing was the tight construction schedule, as the ferry docks in the morning and departs in the afternoon. CU said it met its opening deadline by coordinating closely with related departments and working every other day during the limited docking period.
Internet installation was another hurdle. Conventional landline connections were not viable at sea, but after consulting Korea’s three major telecom operators, CU adopted a Code Division Multiple Access (CDMA) system, enabling multiple simultaneous wireless connections between the ship’s onboard base station and land-based stations, according to CU.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[CU, the convenience store chain operated by BGF Retail Co., is seeing strong sales growth at its ferry-based outlets serving Korea–China routes. According to industry sources on Sunday, CU operates tw]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.3350e996c7ba4ded9d4d1bf62453fe00_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (CU)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384349]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
