<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387321</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>562905</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 09:35:05</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea to temporarily allow visa-free entry for Chinese tour groups from Sept. 29]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 09:35:05</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.777fba9367b2480cbf36e455d34a14b3_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
The South Korean government will temporarily allow visa-free entry for Chinese group tourists starting in late September.
The visa waiver was announced on Wednesday following a tourism task force meeting chaired by Prime Minister Kim Min-seok.
The decision serves as a reciprocal measure in response to China’s visa-free entry policy for Korean nationals, which has been in effect since November last year.
The waiver for Chinese tour groups will run from September 29 through June 30, 2026.
With the recovering tourism industry, the government expects the new policy to boost the number of Chinese visitors and help stimulate domestic demand, particularly in regional areas.
During the meeting, the government also introduced regulatory changes aimed at attracting more foreign tourists to Korea.
Fast-track immigration benefits for attendees of international conferences will be expanded by lowering the eligibility threshold from 500 participants to 300. A simplified immigration screening system, currently in pilot testing, will be formally adopted starting next year.
The government also plans to revise the criteria for designating outstanding medical tourism institutions by including their performance in attracting foreign patients.
These institutions will gain expanded privileges, including the authority to issue e-visas, exemption from financial documentation requirements, and broader rights to invite caregivers, including collateral relatives within the fourth degree.
At the upcoming national tourism strategy meeting, the government plans to discuss additional measures to boost inbound tourism in connection with the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit, scheduled to take place in Gyeongju at the end of October.
Prime Minister Kim described the 2025 APEC summit as a critical opportunity to revitalize tourism and instructed the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism and other related agencies to develop a structured promotional strategy and detailed action plan.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean government will temporarily allow visa-free entry for Chinese group tourists starting in late September. The visa waiver was announced on Wednesday following a tourism task force meet]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.777fba9367b2480cbf36e455d34a14b3_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387321]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
