<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11387328</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>562923</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-07 09:39:16</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[SK sells entire stake in Vietnam’s Vingroup]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-07 09:39:16</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.01e77f96d1e343e786e68329da515bd8_P1.png' alt=' (MK DB)'>
South Korea’s SK Group has sold its entire stake in Vingroup, Vietnam’s largest private conglomerate, securing over 1 trillion won ($710 million) in fresh capital. The move is part of the group’s broader business rebalancing strategy, aimed at strengthening its financial structure and investing in future growth areas.
According to local investment banking sources and foreign media reports on Wednesday, SK Group completed the sale of its 6.05 percent stake in Vingroup through its Vietnamese investment arm, SK Investment Vina II.
The sale was executed via block trades on the local stock market, using a pre-designated institutional buyer, and took place gradually from January to early August.
Back in January, SK Group offloaded a 2.2 percent stake in Vingroup, raising approximately 120 billion won. The group is believed to have closely monitored Vingroup’s stock performance and currency fluctuations before finalizing the timing of the remaining sale.
Vingroup shares surged from 39,000 Vietnamese dong at the start of the year to 104,000 dong in early August—an increase of about 2.6 times. When factoring in foreign exchange gains, the total proceeds from the stake sale are estimated to exceed 1.3 trillion won.
This marks the end of a six-year investment relationship between SK and Vingroup. SK originally invested 1.1 trillion won in 2019 to become the Vietnamese firm’s fourth-largest shareholder. With this exit, the group has successfully recovered more than its initial investment.
SK Group is expected to use the newly secured funds to bolster its financial soundness and reinvest in future-oriented sectors such as artificial intelligence, semiconductors, and energy solutions.
Since last year, the group has been aggressively pursuing a rebalancing strategy to restructure its portfolio and ensure long-term competitiveness.
An SK official noted, “Separate from the share sale, SK Group plans to maintain its strategic partnership with Vingroup in future growth sectors.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s SK Group has sold its entire stake in Vingroup, Vietnam’s largest private conglomerate, securing over 1 trillion won ($710 million) in fresh capital. The move is part of the group’s broa]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/07/news-p.v1.20250807.01e77f96d1e343e786e68329da515bd8_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11387328]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
