<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388487</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566234</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 09:57:41</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Upcoming Korea-U.S. Summit to test trade strategy]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 09:57:41</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400105</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[The United States began full enforcement of its reciprocal tariff policy on Thursday, imposing duties ranging from 10 to 50 percent on imports from about 70 countries.
South Korea was assigned a 15 percent rate, matching the level applied to Japan and the European Union.
However, tensions have escalated following President Donald Trump’s unexpected announcement of a potential 100 percent tariff on semiconductors, casting uncertainty over the broader trade framework.
These sweeping measures mark the onset of a new trade order rooted in protectionist policy. While several countries have negotiated tariff rates with the U.S., confusion remains over how these agreements will be implemented in practice.
The semiconductor sector, in particular, faces heightened uncertainty. During Apple Inc.’s announcement on Wednesday of its expanded U.S. investment, President Trump said that semiconductors not manufactured in the U.S. would be subject to a 100 percent tariff.
Semiconductors are Korea’s second-largest export to the U.S., following automobiles, with exports from Samsung Electronics Co. and SK hynix Inc. totaling $10.6 billion last year.
Although the Korean presidential office emphasized that the domestic semiconductor industry has secured most-favored-nation status, the absence of a final written agreement leaves the sector exposed to potential policy shifts, especially given President Trump’s volatile rhetoric.
Japan, which similarly agreed to a 15 percent tariff rate, is navigating ambiguity over tariff enforcement. Japanese Economic Revitalization Minister Ryosei Akazawa made an urgent trip to Washington to address the issue but returned without a definitive resolution.
The tariff shock is intensifying competition among companies, prompting a wave of strategic responses.
On Thursday, Samsung Electronics and Hyundai Motor Co. announced expanded partnerships with Apple and General Motors Co., respectively, as part of localization efforts aimed at mitigating trade risks.
In addition to corporate efforts, the Korean government should also take active measures such as financial assistance, tax relief, and facility investments to help cushion the impact.
The upcoming Korea-U.S. summit, scheduled for later this month, may serve as a critical point.
As President Trump continues to apply pressure even on allied nations, the scope of potential economic demands remains uncertain.
The Korean government must approach the summit with thorough planning to navigate a complex and shifting landscape.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The United States began full enforcement of its reciprocal tariff policy on Thursday, imposing duties ranging from 10 to 50 percent on imports from about 70 countries. South Korea was assigned a 15 pe]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400105</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400105</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Opinion Editorial]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388487]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
