<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384357</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554096</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 07:39:55</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[VIG Partners weighs stake in pharma distributor PICO Innovation]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 07:39:55</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.0c84a9ce18164ad3983cdf5c10de8803_P1.png' alt=' (MK DB)'>
South Korean private equity firm VIG Partners is exploring an investment in PICO Innovation, a fast-growing pharmaceutical retail platform founded by a consortium of small and mid-sized drugmakers.
The move comes as traditional pharmaceutical supply chains undergo digital transformation, potentially reshaping a domestic industry long dominated by large offline wholesalers.
According to sources familiar with the investment banking industry on Sunday, VIG Partners is in talks to acquire a minority stake in PICO Innovation, which is valued at around 250 billion won ($179 million).
The proposed investment, estimated at around 100 billion won, could grant the equity firm effective control of the company, despite falling short of a majority stake, given the platform‘s fragmented shareholder base.
Established in July 2020 by over 20 smaller pharmaceutical companies—including DONGKOO Bio&Pharma, HLB Pharmaceutical Co., and Ilsung IS Co.—PICO Innovation was born out of a desire to bypass traditional intermediaries and reduce costly distribution fees, which can run up to 12 percent when using large wholesalers.
The major players in the domestic pharmaceutical distribution sector, including Geoyoung and Baekje Pharmaceutical Co., have built scale through dominance in offline channels.
Geoyoung alone posted sales of more than 5 trillion won last year. For smaller companies with annual sales in the tens of billions of won, such distribution costs have had a sizable impact on margins.
PICO Innovation launched its own logistics center in Pyeongtaek, Gyeonggi Province, in March 2024 and rolled out PICO Mall, an online wholesale marketplace aimed at pharmacies.
The platform allows direct sales, bypassing traditional intermediaries and cutting distribution costs.
Since the launch, PICO Innovation has seen explosive sales growth—from 36 million won in 2022 to 5.1 billion won in 2023 and 11.9 billion won in 2024.
However, it reported an operating loss of roughly 5.4 billion won last year due to upfront investment in logistics and technology infrastructure.
Should VIG Partners proceed with the investment, it would mark another turning point in the pharmaceutical distribution sector.
MBK Partners’ 1.19 trillion acquisition of Geoyoung last year reinforced the dominance of traditional offline logistics players. VIG Partners, in contrast, is betting on a disruptive online-first model.
Still, VIG Partners is approaching the opportunity with caution.
“We’ve only had preliminary discussions, and due to the complexity of the business, talks haven’t advanced further,” said a company official.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean private equity firm VIG Partners is exploring an investment in PICO Innovation, a fast-growing pharmaceutical retail platform founded by a consortium of small and mid-sized drugmakers. Th]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.0c84a9ce18164ad3983cdf5c10de8803_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384357]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
