<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11397981</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>593363</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-20 10:44:49</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai E&C drops out of BEXCO’s third exhibition hall bid]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-20 10:44:49</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.3925d420433b4853bfecb5a97d43f567_P1.png' alt=' (BEXCO)'>
Hyundai Engineering & Construction Co. has withdrawn from bidding on the construction of BEXCO’s third exhibition hall in Busan, a decision seen as influenced by mounting public criticism following its unilateral pullout from a government-backed contract to develop land for the new Gaduk Airport.
According to the Busan Metropolitan Government on Wednesday, Hyundai E&C recently notified city officials via an official letter that it would not participate in the bidding. This was in response to a March request for intent sent to 16 construction companies that had attended the project’s briefing session.
While Hyundai initially expressed interest at the session, it later reversed its position after internal review.
Hyundai Group holds more than a 30 percent stake in BEXCO, the city’s flagship convention facility. Hyundai E&C had previously built the first and second exhibition halls in 1998 and 2009, respectively, and was considered a strong candidate for the third hall.
However, intense criticism from the local community appears to have forced the company to step back.
After Hyundai abandoned the Gaduk Airport land development contract, public anger grew, with some calling for penalties barring the company from participating in national or public construction projects. The company’s subsequent move to pursue the 290 billion won ($213.2 million) BEXCO contract further fueled local backlash.
On July 24, Busan Metropolitan City councilor Jeon Won-seok of the Democratic Party criticized the administration, saying, “It is irresponsible not to consider even minimal restrictions on bidding for a company that has betrayed citizens’ trust.”
Councilor Seo Ji-yeon also issued a statement on Wednesday urging institutional safeguards such as fines, bid restrictions, and compensation requirements for companies that withdraw from large-scale public projects with major social impact.
Busan city will finalize its administrative procedures through a technical review committee before asking the Public Procurement Service to issue the bid for the third exhibition hall.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Engineering & Construction Co. has withdrawn from bidding on the construction of BEXCO’s third exhibition hall in Busan, a decision seen as influenced by mounting public criticism following it]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/20/news-p.v1.20250820.3925d420433b4853bfecb5a97d43f567_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (BEXCO)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11397981]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
