<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385247</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>556898</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 07:46:25</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Foreign net buying in Korean stocks surges in July]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 07:46:25</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.f44795c73d3c4a3faebed35abe22ff98_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
The South Korean stock market saw a sharp rise in foreign capital inflows in July 2025, with foreign investors posting their largest monthly net purchases in one year and five months.
Data from the Korea Exchange showed foreign investors were net buyers of 6.28 trillion won ($4.53 billion) in July, the highest monthly total since February 2024, when net purchases totaled 7.86 trillion won. The figure was also 2.3 times greater than June’s 2.7 trillion won.
Foreign net buying last peaked at 7.8 trillion won in February 2023 before turning into nine consecutive months of net selling from August 2024 through April this year. The trend reversed in May, when foreigners bought roughly 1 trillion won worth of shares, and investment volumes have since continued to expand.
Analysts attribute the renewed buying interest to expectations for stock market stimulus measures under the Lee Jae-myung administration, along with optimism following the conclusion of Korea-U.S. trade negotiations.
Samsung Electronics Co. was the clear focus of foreign investment in July 2025. The company attracted strong interest after announcing a large-scale supply agreement to provide artificial intelligence (AI) chips to Tesla Inc. Foreigners purchased a net 3.5 trillion won worth of Samsung shares that month, or 56 percent of their total net buying. The investment was supported by expectations that the company’s long-weak foundry business will see a recovery.
Hanwha Ocean Co. was in second place with net foreign purchases of 858 billion won, reflecting continued investor interest in the shipbuilding and defense sectors. Other stocks favored by foreign investors included SK Square Co., Isu Petasys Co., and Hanwha Aerospace Co.
While July’s foreign inflows helped give the Kospi a boost, foreign investors turned to net selling on August 1st, unloading 650 billion won in the cash market and 750 billion won in Kospi 200 futures. The Kospi fell 3.88 percent in a single session.
Investor sentiment was weighed down by the government’s tax reform plan that was announced on the previous day. The reform, which centers on tax increases, disappointed markets and triggered selling pressure. Although Korea-U.S. trade negotiations have now been concluded, concerns remain that resulting U.S. tariffs could weigh on domestic corporate earnings. The recent sharp rise in the won-dollar exchange rate poses another challenge, with expectations of continued dollar strength potentially limiting further foreign inflows. The rate briefly climbed above 1,400 won per U.S. dollar in regular trading on August 1st, 2025.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean stock market saw a sharp rise in foreign capital inflows in July 2025, with foreign investors posting their largest monthly net purchases in one year and five months. Data from the Ko]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.f44795c73d3c4a3faebed35abe22ff98_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385247]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
