<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11388602</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>566546</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-08 11:11:57</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Naver Q2 OP up more than 10% on solid growth in all segments]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-08 11:11:57</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-08 15:10:59</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.537045c5dbc14b4e82fefe1634ba203f_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Naver reported an operating profit of 521.6 billion won ($385.96 million) for the second quarter, up 10.3 percent from a year earlier, according to its preliminary earnings announcement Friday.
Revenue rose 11.7 percent on-year to 2.91 trillion won, while net profit came in at 497.4 billion won. The results were in line with market expectations compiled by Yonhap Infomax, which had forecast 2.9 trillion won in revenue and 529.5 billion won in operating profit.
The company said it maintained solid growth across all major business segments. By division, revenue came to 1.03 trillion won from search platform services, 861.1 billion won from commerce, 411.7 billion won from fintech, 474 billion won from content, and 131.7 billion won from enterprise solutions.
Search platform revenue rose 5.9 percent from a year earlier, driven by longer user engagement through AI-powered services and feeds, as well as enhanced advertising capabilities. Overall advertising revenue across Naver’s platforms climbed 8.7 percent on-year and 5.6 percent from the previous quarter.
Commerce revenue jumped 19.8 percent on-year and 9.3 percent quarter-on-quarter, supported by steady growth following the launch of the Naver Plus Store app. On-platform transaction volume for Naver’s commerce business grew 9.0 percent year-on-year, backed by increases in sales through Smart Store and related services.
Fintech revenue increased 11.7 percent from a year earlier, with Naver Pay transaction volume soaring 18.7 percent on-year to 20.8 trillion won in the second quarter, helped by the expansion of its Smart Store operations and external ecosystem. Naver plans to expand Naver Pay into an integrated on-offline financial platform, including the launch of payment terminals that support features such as facial recognition.
Content revenue rose 12.8 percent on-year and 3.2 percent quarter-on-quarter, buoyed by a rebound in webtoon growth and an increase in paid subscribers to its camera app.
“Naver will continue to strengthen platform competitiveness and business capabilities based on AI, while securing new business references for mid- to long-term growth and laying the foundation for global expansion,” CEO Choi Soo-yeon said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Naver reported an operating profit of 521.6 billion won ($385.96 million) for the second quarter, up 10.3 percent from a year earlier, according to its preliminary earnings announcement Friday. Revenu]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/08/news-p.v1.20250808.537045c5dbc14b4e82fefe1634ba203f_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11388602]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
