<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11403904</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>611570</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-27 11:05:21</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean shipbuilding stocks rally as Canada shortlists submarine suppliers]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-27 11:05:21</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-27 16:04:20</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.087b1af9543546c29c98314f40db3711_P1.png' alt=' (Hanwha Ocean)'>
South Korean shipbuilders Hanwha Ocean Co. and HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. saw their shares rise on early Wednesday following reports that they have been shortlisted alongside a German firm for the final round of bidding in Canada’s submarine procurement program.
The two companies are jointly bidding for Canada’s Canadian Patrol Submarine Project (CPSP) worth about 20 trillion won ($14.34 billion). The Canadian government expected to select the final contractor as early as next year.
Hanwha Ocean shares were trading at 111,200 won as of 9:08 a.m. on Wednesday, up 3.15 percent from the previous session, while those of HD Hyundai Heavy Industries were trading 1.6 percent higher at 475,500 won.
The project aims to replace Canada’s four Victoria-class submarines, which are slated for decommissioning in the mid-2030s, with up to 12 diesel-powered submarines.
The acquisition contract alone is valued at up to 20 trillion won, and when operating and maintenance costs over the next 30 years are included, the total project size could expand to as much as 60 trillion won.
If secured, it would also mark the largest single defense export contract in Korea’s history.
Meanwhile, Bumhan Fuel Cell Co. also saw its shares surge to the daily upper limit on Wednesday morning after its client companies, Hanwha Ocean and HD Hyundai Heavy Industries, were confirmed to have made it to the final shortlist in the Canadian submarine project.
Bumhan Fuel Cell shares were trading at 23,750 won as of 9:26 a.m., up 29.92 percent from the previous session, hitting the daily upper price limit right after the market opened.
The company manufactures fuel cell modules, a core component of air-independent propulsion (AIP) systems for submarines.
Shares of Hanwha Ocean finished 2.88 percent higher at 110,900 won while those of HD Hyundai Heavy Industries ended 11.32 percent higher at 521,000 won. Bumhan Fuel Cell ended at 20,400 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean shipbuilders Hanwha Ocean Co. and HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. saw their shares rise on early Wednesday following reports that they have been shortlisted alongside a German firm for th]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.087b1af9543546c29c98314f40db3711_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hanwha Ocean)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11403904]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
