<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405886</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>617673</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 10:37:10</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Securities posts earnings surprise]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 10:37:10</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.ca160bdc1e2945119b8bcd77683ebd13_P1.png' alt=' CEO Bae Hyung-keun'>
South Korea’s Hyundai Motor Securities Co. delivered an earnings surprise in the first half of 2025, with net profit surpassing the company’s total profit for all of 2024 thanks to revenue diversification.
According to Hyundai Motor Securities on Wednesday, its consolidated net profit for the first half of 2025 was approximately 40 billion won ($28.87 million), up 59.1 percent from 25.2 billion won in the same period in 2024.
The figure also exceeded the full-year net profit of 36.2 billion won recorded in 2024. Operating profit for the first half came to 54.1 billion won, a 66.1 percent increase from 32.6 billion won a year earlier. Net profit was 20.7 billion won in the second quarter alone, up 38.5 percent year-on-year, while operating profit rose 39 percent to 27 billion won.
The strong results were driven by the company’s diversification of revenue sources. Since taking office early 2024, Chief Executive Officer Bae Hyung-keun has strengthened the company’s retirement pension business by setting up a dedicated unit under the retail division to bolster defined contribution (DC) and individual retirement pension (IRP) offerings. He also established a new Sales & Trading (S&T) division to consolidate trading and investment operations, including derivatives and principal investment (PI).
In the investment banking (IB) division, the company reorganized its structure to expand its non-real-estate portfolio, focusing on corporate bond underwriting, asset-backed loan (ABL) financing, and general corporate credit financing.
The company’s financial soundness also improved. Its contingent liabilities stood at about 709 billion won as of the end of June 2025, with the contingent liability ratio to equity down about 4 percentage points from 54 percent at the end of 2024.
The net capital ratio (NCR) improved from 478 percent to 605 percent following a rights issue in March. The company also strengthened its fundamentals by setting aside 29.11 billion won in provisions last year.
Hyundai Motor Securities maintained its “AA- (stable)” credit rating from Korea’s three major credit rating agencies earlier this year.
Moreover, Bae purchased 200 million won worth of company shares in a show of commitment to responsible management. He subscribed to 8,747 shares during the March rights offering for existing shareholders and purchased an additional 6,950 shares in June 2025 after initially acquiring 11,130 shares upon taking office.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s Hyundai Motor Securities Co. delivered an earnings surprise in the first half of 2025, with net profit surpassing the company’s total profit for all of 2024 thanks to revenue diversifica]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.ca160bdc1e2945119b8bcd77683ebd13_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ CEO Bae Hyung-keun]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405886]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
