<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384575</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554872</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 10:52:43</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[TMON to resume operations on Aug. 11 with next-day payment system]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 10:52:43</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.2eb76ebb045c4b5bb6d4e49cd50a674d_P1.jpg' alt=' (TMON Inc.)'>
South Korean e-commerce platform TMON Inc. will resume operations on August 11, nearly one year after it suspended services.
The company announced the reopening on Monday, marking its return just under two months after receiving court approval for its rehabilitation plan on June 23.
TMON is currently notifying its partner sellers of the reopening and related procedures.
To regain trust and attract sellers, TMON plans to offer contract terms with some of the lowest commission rates in the industry—between 3 to 5 percent—and will implement a next-day payment settlement system.
The company aims to reposition itself as a sustainable and mutually beneficial platform by rebuilding trust with sellers.
TMON filed for court receivership last year following a large-scale crisis involving unpaid settlements and refunds. In June, it was acquired by Oasis, a company specializing in early-morning grocery delivery.
Meanwhile, fellow e-commerce platform WeMakePrice has yet to find a buyer.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean e-commerce platform TMON Inc. will resume operations on August 11, nearly one year after it suspended services. The company announced the reopening on Monday, marking its return just unde]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.2eb76ebb045c4b5bb6d4e49cd50a674d_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (TMON Inc.)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384575]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
