<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11386180</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>559782</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-06 08:12:49</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean fast-food restaurants struggle as consumers tighten their belts]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-06 08:12:49</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.8cfab9a60f1b466a8c2ce9d65f711f4b_P1.png' alt=' (MK DB )'>
South Korea’s fast-food industry is struggling to stay afloat due to weak demand, intensified competition, and rising costs.
According to data from the National Tax Service on Tuesday, the total number of fast-food outlets in Korea stood at 47,632 as of the end of June 2025, down from 47,907 at the end of last year.
This is the first decline since 2017, when relevant data became available on a semi-annual basis.
If the current trend continues, a year-on-year decline would also be inevitable for the first time on record.
The number of fast-food outlets had steadily increased, nearing the 50,000 mark by the end of last year.
However, the figure began to decline as consumer sentiment weakened in the first half of this year.
The primary reason is reduced consumer spending.
Private consumption in the first quarter of this year fell by 1.4 percent compared to the previous quarter, and although it rebounded by 0.5 percent in the second quarter, analysts attribute this to base effects.
Small business sales are also on the decline.
According to Korea Credit Data (KCD), the average revenue per small business establishment in the first quarter was 41.79 million won ($30,155), down 0.72 percent year-on-year and 12.9 percent quarter-on-quarter.
Overheated competition, particularly among chicken franchises, also contributed.
As major brands intensify their expansion efforts, smaller brands with less capital are being squeezed out of the market.
Major franchises such as BHC, BBQ, and Kyochon Chicken continue to maintain a high number of locations.
Kyochon, for example, operated 1,359 stores as of the end of the first quarter, with only three closures during the same period.
Amid worsening market conditions, more than half of fast-food franchise owners are shutting down within three years.
According to data from the National Tax Service, the three-year survival rate for fast-food outlets from 2019 to 2023 was 46.8 percent, the third lowest after online retail (45.7 percent) and snack bars (46.6 percent).
This indicates that over half of new fast-food businesses close within three years of opening.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s fast-food industry is struggling to stay afloat due to weak demand, intensified competition, and rising costs. According to data from the National Tax Service on Tuesday, the total numbe]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/06/news-p.v1.20250806.8cfab9a60f1b466a8c2ce9d65f711f4b_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB )]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11386180]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
