<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11391254</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>573435</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-12 07:57:14</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Tomoro Robotics eyes physical AI lead with natural language training]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-12 07:57:14</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400103</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.a988cc0d99244687acf9f72495d91644_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
Tomoro Robotics, an artificial intelligence (AI) firm specializing in robot training, has set its goal to become a global leader in physical AI with its natural language–driven training technology.
When Maeil Business Newspaper visited Tomoro Robotics’ humanoid AI research lab in Seoul last week, humanoid robots from leading Korean robotics companies, including Rainbow Robotics Co.’s RB-Y1 and Robotis Co.’s AI Walker, were connected to computers.
“To realize physical AI, we assign tasks to various humanoid robot models and collect the resulting data to train them using our proprietary robot foundation model, CLIP-RT,” said Zhang Byoung-tak, chief executive officer of Tomoro Robotics and director at the Artificial Intelligence Institute of Seoul National University (AIIS).
Tomoro Robotics develops robot foundation models, essentially the “brains” of humanoid robots.
The company was founded in April 2022 by Zhang under the guiding concept of “embodied AI,” or AI with a physical body.
“For AI to fully understand the world, it must directly sense and experience the physical environment,” Zhang said. “Understanding only text or images does not mean AI truly understands the world. Its capabilities improve when it can operate, learn, and adapt in the physical world.”
Initially, Tomoro Robotics focused on logistics automation solutions. Currently, it is conducting a humanoid-based logistics automation proof-of-concept with CJ Logistics Corp.
Robots deployed at CJ’s logistics centers assist with parcel sorting, collecting data in the process to train AI models.
The company’s most notable innovation is CLIP-RT, an advanced robot foundation model based on OpenAI’s CLIP. The system enables robots to process and learn from vision and language as well as physical trajectories.
It gained attention when a related paper was accepted this year by a major international robotics conference.
Zhang also serves as chair of the K-Humanoid Alliance, which was launched this year under the leadership of the Ministry of Trade, Industry and Energy.
The alliance aims to develop a general-purpose humanoid ecosystem leveraging Korea’s manufacturing base and information and communication technology (ICT) infrastructure. “Korea has a diverse manufacturing portfolio, world-class ICT capabilities, and abundant talent,” Zhang said. “By combining these strengths, we have a real opportunity to lead the global humanoid industry.”
Following the alliance’s launch, Tomoro Robotics began building partnerships with major domestic robotics companies.
Last month, Robotis and Tomoro Robotics signed a memorandum of understanding under which Robotis will develop high-precision, high-efficiency robot hardware and navigation systems, while Tomoro Robotics will focus on control software and applications using voice, vision, and natural language processing technologies.
Zhang emphasized that physical AI is an area in which Korea can assume global leadership.
“In physical AI, no country or company has yet secured an unassailable advantage. Korea, with an ecosystem well suited to this field, is in a strong position to lead,” he said.
He also highlighted the need to address regulatory challenges in parallel with technological progress. “Regulatory issues in physical AI are inevitable, and the public and private sectors must work together to craft balanced policies that protect privacy and safety without stifling innovation,” Zhang said. “Our objective is to develop robots capable of perceiving, acting, and working like humans.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Tomoro Robotics, an artificial intelligence (AI) firm specializing in robot training, has set its goal to become a global leader in physical AI with its natural language–driven training technology. Wh]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400103</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400103</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Companies]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/12/news-p.v1.20250812.a988cc0d99244687acf9f72495d91644_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11391254]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
