<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11403783</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>611169</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-27 09:51:25</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korea’s One Team makes it to final round in CPSP]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-27 09:51:25</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-27 11:08:11</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.c1295f2dc5484e5a92959a2af0875309_P1.png' alt=' (Hanwha Ocean)'>
South Korea’s “One Team” defense partnership between Hanwha Ocean Co. and HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. was shortlisted as one of the final two contenders in Canada’s Canadian Patrol Submarine Project (CPSP).
This development is particularly noteworthy as the Korean consortium has outpaced strong European rivals in a project valued at up to 60 trillion won ($43.01 billion), just as Korea-U.S. shipbuilding cooperation is gaining momentum.
Hanwha Ocean, which leads the Korea One Team’s participation in CPSP, announced on Tuesday: “We were shortlisted in the Canadian Navy’s project to procure 12 submarines of around 3,000 tons, and our final competitor is Germany’s thyssenkrupp Marine Systems (TKMS).”
In Canada’s evaluation, long-established European players – France’s state-owned Naval Group, Spain’s Navantia, and Sweden’s Saab - were eliminated, leaving only the Korea One Team and Germany’s TKMS in contention.
The Korea One Team proposed the 3,000-ton-class “Jangbogo-III Batch II” submarine to Canada.
Equipped with an air-independent propulsion (AIP) system and lithium-ion batteries, the vessel can conduct submerged operations for more than three weeks and has a maximum range of 7,000 nautical miles (about 12,900 kilometers).
“In addition to the submarine’s capabilities, we believe factors such as rapid delivery timelines and our localization strategy earned us strong evaluations from the Canadian Navy,” Hanwha Ocean said. “While submarine contracts typically require about nine years from signing to delivery, we are confident we can shorten that to six years.”
“The submarine is capable of operations across vast areas spanning the Pacific, Atlantic, and Arctic Oceans, which meets the Canadian Navy’s strategic requirements,” a Hanwha Ocean official added.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korea’s “One Team” defense partnership between Hanwha Ocean Co. and HD Hyundai Heavy Industries Co. was shortlisted as one of the final two contenders in Canada’s Canadian Patrol Submarine Proje]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/27/news-p.v1.20250827.c1295f2dc5484e5a92959a2af0875309_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hanwha Ocean)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11403783]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
