<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385256</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>556924</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 08:06:30</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean SMEs’ H1 exports surge led by cosmetics, used cars]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 08:06:30</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.60306632b13a445f9a17a5e4d2b7be69_P1.png' alt=' (CJ Olive Young)'>
Exports by South Korea's small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) continued to grow in the first half of 2025 as demand for Korean cosmetics and used cars surged amid changing U.S. tariff policies.
According to data released by the Ministry of SMEs and Startups on Monday, the country’s SME exports stood at $56.7 billion in the first half of this year, up 3 percent from the same period a year ago.
This is the seventh consecutive quarter of growth since SME exports turned upward in the fourth quarter of 2023.
The number of exporting SMEs also rose to 78,655 companies during the cited period, a 2.2 percent increase year-on-year and the highest figure ever recorded for the first half of any year.
Cosmetics and automobiles were the top-performing export categories, boosted by the global K-beauty trend.
Cosmetics exports totaled $3.94 billion in the first half, a new record high and ranking first among SME export items. The figure marked a 19.7 percent year-on-year increase.
While exports to major markets such as the United States ($720 million) and China ($570 million) remained strong, demand in emerging markets such as the United Arab Emirates (up 63.6 percent) and Poland (up 160 percent) also grew significantly.
Automobile exports saw a particularly sharp increase, rising 73.7 percent year-on-year to $3.92 billion.
Analysts attribute this growth to the UAE’s role as a re-export hub, where Korean used cars are imported for use as rental vehicles for tourists and then sold to other countries.
“The demand for tourist rental cars is not a short-term phenomenon, so we expect the upward trend in exports to continue for the time being,” an official from the SMEs ministry said.
Exports of general machinery, on the other hand, declined 31.2 percent year-on-year due to weakened demand for electric vehicle (EV)-related equipment amid a decline in EV demand.
The impact of U.S. tariff hikes in the first half had a mixed effect by product category, data showed.
While U.S.-bound exports of steel and aluminum fell by 16.3 percent and 3.4 percent, respectively, auto parts exports to the U.S. rose by 10.3 percent.
By country, exports to Taiwan and Kyrgyzstan showed strong growth, while those to Vietnam struggled.
Exports to Taiwan rose 23 percent year-on-year, thanks to a boom in the global semiconductor industry, driving up shipments of semiconductor manufacturing equipment (82.5 percent), semiconductors (25.5 percent), and precision chemical materials (173.7 percent).
Exports to Kyrgyzstan, which ranked 8th among top export destinations, saw a 95.7 percent surge in used car shipments, reaching a record high of $1.35 billion in the first half.
In contrast, exports to Vietnam - Korea’s third-largest export market - saw a 5 percent decline as nine out of the country’s top 10 export items, including semiconductors and synthetic resins, posted negative growth.
This marks the second consecutive quarter of decline since the first quarter.
Meanwhile, online exports topped $500 million for the first time in a half-year period.
Emerging markets, rather than the traditional top 10 export destinations, accounted for a growing share.
The growth is particularly high in the United Kingdom (180 percent) and the Netherlands (104 percent), indicating that rising interest in K-culture is expanding into broader global demand for Korean products.
“K-beauty is currently driving the overall increase in SME exports,” said Lee Soon-bae, director general for global growth policy at the SMEs ministry. “We will continue to identify and foster other promising K-content-based sectors, such as fashion, food, and software.”
Lee also noted that online exports are cost-effective and especially suitable for beginner exporters.
“We plan to guide these businesses to start with online exports as a first step into the global market.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Exports by South Korea's small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) continued to grow in the first half of 2025 as demand for Korean cosmetics and used cars surged amid changing U.S. tariff policies. A]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.60306632b13a445f9a17a5e4d2b7be69_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (CJ Olive Young)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385256]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
