<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390361</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570972</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 10:56:32</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Samyang Foods shares soar on Buldak sauce deal with Panda Express]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 10:56:32</reg_dt>
<mod_dt>2025-08-11 16:19:37</mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.ad8c6021501646b8aaaf7864b3b3e8e0_P1.jpg' alt=' (Yonhap News)'>
Samyang Foods Inc. shares climbed on Monday following an announcement of a partnership between its Buldak Sauce brand and Panda Express, the United States’ largest Asian dining brand.
The stock was trading at 1.489 million won ($1,072) as of 10:39 a.m., up 2.34 percent from the previous session. S&D, the exclusive supplier of ingredients for the Buldak sauce, also saw its shares jump 6.5 percent to 126,200 won.
Samyang Foods said it has entered into an official partnership with Panda Express for its Buldak-branded sauce. The two companies have collaborated on the Dynamite Sweet & Sour Chicken, which will be sold for a limited time until October 7th, 2025, at select Panda Express locations in ten U.S. cities.
Meanwhile, Seohee Construction shares tumbled by more than 7 percent after a special counsel investigating allegations involving former First Lady Kim Keon-hee raided the company over a necklace scandal.
The shares were trading at 1,622 won as of 10:41 a.m., down 7.37 percent from the previous session.
The special counsel’s team said in a press release that it launched a search and seizure of Seohee Construction in connection with the case under investigation.
Investigators suspect the company may have gifted Kim an expensive necklace in exchange for personnel favors. Kim wore the necklace, a Van Cleef & Arpels piece, during her overseas trip to the NATO summit in June 2022, but it was allegedly omitted from her asset disclosure.
Samyang Foods shares closed at 1,502 million won while those of S&D finished at 125,900 won. Seohee Construction shares closed at 1,623 won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Samyang Foods Inc. shares climbed on Monday following an announcement of a partnership between its Buldak Sauce brand and Panda Express, the United States’ largest Asian dining brand. The stock was tr]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.ad8c6021501646b8aaaf7864b3b3e8e0_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap News)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390361]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
