<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11393611</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>580968</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-14 11:27:06</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Gov’t to create $72 bn fund to foster high-tech industries]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-14 11:27:06</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.c9ca20faeca54dc1bfe1eae0471e005b_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
The South Korean government will create a 100 trillion won ($72.5 billion) national growth fund to foster new growth high-tech industries such as artificial intelligence (AI), biotechnology, and semiconductors.
The State Affairs Planning Committee under the Lee Jae-myung administration on Wednesday unveiled its economic growth strategy to achieve a 3 percent potential growth rate, which includes nurturing new AI industries, energy transition, and expanding the venture ecosystem.
The committee announced national policy tasks aimed at propelling Korea into the ranks of the world’s top three AI powerhouses, which include the construction of an AI superhighway to drive a full-scale AI transformation, building an energy superhighway, expanding renewable energy, and creating RE100 industrial complexes.
Also, inspired by the massive success of “KPop Demon Hunters,” which showcased the global power of K-content, the committee set goals to expand the K-culture market to 300 trillion won and increase inbound tourism from 16 million visitors in 2024 to 30 million by 2030.
In particular, the committee plans to establish a 100 trillion won Advanced Strategic Industry Fund jointly funded by the public and private sectors to support the country’s economic growth strategy.
The plan is to make large-scale investments in future strategic industries to raise the nation’s potential growth rate.
The state-owned Korea Development Bank (KDB), as the operating entity, will provide 50 trillion won, while the remaining 50 trillion won will be raised through contributions from the financial sector and private investment.
KDB will focus on providing a growth catalyst for advanced strategic technology sectors such as AI, future mobility, secondary batteries, semiconductors, and defense.
It will also invest in infrastructure such as AI data centers and the energy superhighway, as well as support the growth of innovative companies, including venture firms and startups.
Support methods under consideration include loans, joint investments, subordinated financing, and debt guarantees.
Separately, the committee presented a blueprint to expand annual venture investment from the current 12 trillion won to 40 trillion won by 2030.
The goal is to invigorate the economy and create a growth ladder that will help small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) grow into global companies by expanding the venture capital market and fostering startups.
For national key industries such as AI, biohealth, and renewable energy, the committee will push for “zero regulation” and a shift toward a negative regulatory framework, and implement mega-special zones to drive innovation.
To accelerate the arrival of the KOSPI 5000 era, it will also implement measures such as the introduction of a one-strike-out rule to strictly punish capital market manipulation.
The committee also pledged to turn inter-Korean relations - long regarded as a “Korea discount” factor - into a Korean Peninsula premium.
The committee also included a wide range of measures to support local and rural areas in its policy agenda.
It aims to raise the share of gross regional domestic product (GRDP) outside the Seoul capital area from the current upper-40 percent range to over 50 percent, by expediting the completion of the administrative capital and immediately moving forward with the second phase of public institution relocations.
It also plans to transfer authority from the central government to local governments and adjust the current national-to-local tax revenue ratio from 7.5:2.5 to 7:3 during the administration’s term, thereby establishing a solid framework for local autonomy.
It is also noteworthy that the committee included in its agenda a rural basic income program, which would place a substantial burden on fiscal resources.
This is one of President Lee’s campaign pledges, aiming to provide a monthly stipend to rural residents.
A bill on the Rural Basic Income Act has already been proposed to grant 150,000 won per month (1.8 million won annually) to rural residents.
According to the National Assembly Budget Office, providing 1.8 million won annually to 9.6 million residents living in towns and villages would require 17.4 trillion won per year.
The government is reportedly planning to launch a pilot program next year, offering 150,000 won per month in local currency to residents in five to six depopulated rural areas, jointly funded by the central and local governments.
“Our country is mired in structural low growth, as the flow of capital concentrated in real estate is stifling economic growth,” said Jung Tae-ho, head of the committee’s Economic Division 1. “We must rebuild the framework for growth to adapt to the changed environment.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[The South Korean government will create a 100 trillion won ($72.5 billion) national growth fund to foster new growth high-tech industries such as artificial intelligence (AI), biotechnology, and semic]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/14/news-p.v1.20250814.c9ca20faeca54dc1bfe1eae0471e005b_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11393611]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
