<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405889</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>617675</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-29 10:37:24</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Musinsa posts record earnings in Q2]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-29 10:37:24</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.b839c94724cc459099fb72c49c10b0fe_P1.png' alt=' Musinsa CI'>
South Korean online fashion platform Musinsa reported its highest-ever second-quarter 2025 results, with both sales and operating profit reaching record levels. Expectations for further growth are rising, with the company set to launch its biggest annual discount event and open overseas stores in the second half of the year.
Musinsa said on Thursday that its consolidated revenue rose 30.7 percent to 377.7 billion won ($272.6 million) in the April to June period, while operating profit increased 22.6 percent to 41.3 billion won. Net profit surged 5.6 times year-on-year to 40.8 billion won, marking the best second-quarter performance in the company’s history.
For the first half of the year, sales totaled 670.5 billion won, up 22.1 percent from a year earlier, while operating profit rose 23.1 percent to 58.9 billion won. Net profit reached 37.2 billion won, reflecting the impact of an accounting policy change that classified redeemable convertible preferred shares (RCPS) as liabilities.
Musinsa’s performance contrasts sharply with many domestic fashion companies that have struggled amid an economic slowdown and abnormal weather conditions. The company attributes its growth to its extensive selection of brands and products, development of an omni-channel presence across online and offline platforms, and targeted marketing toward foreign tourists. Musinsa hosts about 10,000 fashion brands ranging from streetwear to sports and casual labels.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean online fashion platform Musinsa reported its highest-ever second-quarter 2025 results, with both sales and operating profit reaching record levels. Expectations for further growth are ris]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/29/news-p.v1.20250829.b839c94724cc459099fb72c49c10b0fe_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Musinsa CI]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405889]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
