<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11385305</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>557062</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-05 09:06:41</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Samsung forms AI–humanoid unit to secure future tech lead]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-05 09:06:41</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.245cf0a12ea14a1d8b619b8f504f5324_P1.png' alt=' (MK DB)'>
Samsung Electronics Co. has launched a dedicated task force to fast-track innovation in artificial intelligence (AI) and humanoid robotics, as part of its broader strategy to expand its AI ecosystem and strengthen its leadership in next-generation technologies.
The company announced on Monday the formation of Inno X Lab, a new organization within its Device eXperience (DX) division that will oversee major strategic projects.
This marks the first time the DX division—which is responsible for Samsung’s consumer electronics businesses—has established a unit solely dedicated to exploring new business areas.
The name Inno X Lab is a combination of “Innovation” and “Transformation,” and reflects the group’s mission to drive disruptive change.
The lab is guided by two core principles: speed and efficiency.
To accelerate execution, the lab is designed to select necessary talent across different business units based on the needs of each project, allowing for flexible workforce deployment and seamless cross-divisional collaboration.
In its initial phase, Inno X Lab will work on expanding the application of digital twin solutions, innovating logistics operations through AI-powered systems, automating manufacturing processes using physical AI, and developing core technologies for humanoid robots.
The lab will continuously add new projects over time and retire completed ones, operating under a dynamic project management model.
The initiative is believed to have been strongly championed by Roh Tae-moon, President and Acting Head of the DX division.
In May, Samsung also launched an AI Productivity Innovation Group within the DX division and established AI task forces within individual business units to reinforce AI adoption.
Inno X Lab, however, goes a step further by serving as a dedicated execution body aimed at delivering measurable results.
Industry observers expect the new lab to function as a powerful catalyst in Samsung’s push to commercialize AI-based new businesses.
Areas such as humanoid robotics, smart manufacturing, and logistics innovation are viewed as convergence points for AI, robotics, sensors, and semiconductor technologies. Digital twin technology, in particular, is expected to play a key role in enhancing operational efficiency company-wide.
“Inno X Lab will be the central pillar for identifying and executing new businesses in the AI era,” said a Samsung official. “We will actively pursue company-wide strategic challenges to bolster our future technological and business competitiveness.”
The new unit is also expected to play an important role in accelerating the spread of Samsung’s AI ecosystem, a long-term initiative pursued by the DX division.
The DX division encompasses Samsung’s consumer product lines, including mobile (MX), video display (VD), and digital appliances (DA). The company has been increasingly embedding AI across its product range.
Galaxy smartphones, both premium S series and more affordable A series, now feature real-time translation and call summarization functions—capabilities that have been well-received and are seen as outpacing rival offerings from Apple. This has contributed to a simultaneous rise in Samsung’s domestic and global market share.
Samsung’s TVs also leverage AI to optimize picture and sound quality, with some models supporting real-time subtitle translation.
Its appliances incorporate Bespoke AI, which automatically adjusts laundry, refrigeration, and cooking settings for optimal results. The AI Home platform further enhances connectivity and centralized control among devices.
According to one industry insider, “Samsung’s DX division aims to integrate AI into all its products to keep consumers engaged within the Samsung ecosystem, which includes One UI, SmartThings, and AI Home.”
“Inno X Lab will likely focus on reinforcing links between different AI technologies and delivering a unified user experience across devices,” the insider said.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics Co. has launched a dedicated task force to fast-track innovation in artificial intelligence (AI) and humanoid robotics, as part of its broader strategy to expand its AI ecosystem a]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/05/news-p.v1.20250805.245cf0a12ea14a1d8b619b8f504f5324_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11385305]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
