<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11392849</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>578580</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-13 14:55:38</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hanwha, DL clash over Yeocheon NCC rescue plan]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-13 14:55:38</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.5ab2046f339344b5a62ee7a69c56c215_P1.png' alt=' Yeocheon NCC'>
Hanwha Group and DL Group, who each hold a 50 percent stake in Yeocheon NCC Co., are locked in a dispute over who bears responsibility for the company’s losses and how best to steer it back to stability. Yeocheon NCC, which was formed as a joint venture between the two conglomerates, is South Korea’s third-largest ethylene producer.
DL Chemical Co., a DL Group affiliate and one of the two shareholders in Yeocheon NCC, has moved to raise 200 billion won ($144 million) via a capital increase to shore up Yeocheon NCC’s finances. The funding is expected to ease the company’s immediate liquidity crunch, but no agreement has been reached with fellow shareholder Hanwha Solutions Corp. on concrete support measures. Analysts say the shareholder rift could slow efforts to normalize operations.
Hanwha Group escalated the feud on Tuesday, issuing a statement that accused DL Group of inflicting heavy losses on Yeocheon NCC through low-priced transactions. The group urged its co-shareholder to take “active and responsible” steps to avert the ethylene producer’s bankruptcy.
The statement came a day after DL Group announced its fundraising plan without specifying how much of the money would be injected directly into Yeocheon NCC.
The statement also highlighted issues in DL Group’s raw material supply contract and raised concerns over a recent tax dispute. According to Hanwha Group, Yeocheon NCC was hit with a 100.6 billion won corporate tax bill following an audit by the National Tax Service, which found that the company had sold ethylene and other products below market value.
Hanwha Group added 96 percent of the underpricing - worth 96.2 billion won - was linked to transactions with DL Group, compared with just 4 percent related to Hanwha Group.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hanwha Group and DL Group, who each hold a 50 percent stake in Yeocheon NCC Co., are locked in a dispute over who bears responsibility for the company’s losses and how best to steer it back to stabili]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/13/news-p.v1.20250813.5ab2046f339344b5a62ee7a69c56c215_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Yeocheon NCC]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11392849]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
