<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11390163</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>570325</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-11 07:39:29</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Samsung’s Smart Monitor M9 dubbed ‘best monitor’ by U.S. media]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-11 07:39:29</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400109</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.909ecfc4552a44adbabc0a93dd1671ab_P1.jpg' alt=' (Samsung Electronics)'>
Samsung Electronics’ Smart Monitor M9 (model M90SF) is earning glowing reviews from leading U.S. tech publications, with some calling it the best monitor currently on the market.
Launched in June 2025, the Smart Monitor M9 is the first in Samsung’s Smart Monitor lineup to feature an OLED panel. The 32-inch display offers 4K resolution, a 165Hz refresh rate, and an ultra-fast 0.03ms (GTG) response time. AI-powered features such as 4K AI Upscaling Pro, AI Picture Optimizer, and Active Voice Pro enhance the viewing experience for movies, games, and other content.
Tech outlet Tom’s Guide praised the M9 as “a massive upgrade over its predecessor,” highlighting its 32-inch 4K QD-OLED panel for delivering outstanding contrast and color accuracy that “elevates the movie-watching experience.” The publication added that the M9 offers “top-tier performance among Samsung’s OLED 4K monitors.”
IT media Techaeris awarded the monitor a 9.7 out of 10 and named it a “Top Pick for 2025,” noting its “vivid and punchy colors” and “remarkable brightness that resists color washout thanks to its quantum-dot backlight.” The site described the QD-OLED-equipped M9 as “the best monitor you can buy today, no matter the competition.”
Home entertainment publication Home Theater Review also ranked the M9 among “the most impressive displays available for purchase,” lauding its fast response times and color accuracy as features that “creative professionals will love.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics’ Smart Monitor M9 (model M90SF) is earning glowing reviews from leading U.S. tech publications, with some calling it the best monitor currently on the market. Launched in June 2025]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400109</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400109</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Bio&Tech]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/11/news-p.v1.20250811.909ecfc4552a44adbabc0a93dd1671ab_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Samsung Electronics)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11390163]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
