<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11402920</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>608667</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-26 11:18:21</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Group to invest $26 bn in U.S. over 4 yrs]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-26 11:18:21</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.6007bb97c2a84b1ba9e2d9cb7c5aa48d_P1.jpg' alt=' (Hyundai Motor/Kia)'>
Hyundai Motor Group announced Tuesday that it will invest $26 billion over four years in the United States, an increase of $5 billion from the $21 billion announced in March. The investment will focus on future industries such as steel, automobiles, and robotics.
The move is aimed at strengthening competitiveness in mobility and other future businesses, expanding business opportunities in line with U.S. government policy, and boosting economic cooperation between Korea and the U.S.
Hyundai Motor Group plans to build a 2.7 million-ton electric arc furnace steel plant in Louisiana, producing low-carbon, high-quality steel plates to be supplied to key U.S. industries such as automotive. Once completed, the plant will create a full value chain in the U.S., from steel to parts to finished cars.
The group will also expand its local auto production capacity.
In March, it pledged to increase annual production from 700,000 to 1.2 million units, but now plans to expand beyond that, with a lineup spanning EVs, hybrids, and internal combustion vehicles.
Parts and logistics affiliates will also expand facilities to boost localization, secure EV battery pack supply chains, and strengthen ties between automakers and suppliers.
For the first time, Hyundai unveiled plans to establish a robot plant in the U.S. capable of producing 30,000 units annually. The facility, to be led by robotics subsidiary Boston Dynamics, will produce key products such as Atlas and Spot, though details on timing and location have not been finalized.
The conglomerate will also expand collaboration with U.S. companies in autonomous driving, artificial intelligence, and software-defined vehicles (SDVs), while accelerating commercialization of Boston Dynamics and Motional operations in the U.S.
Domestically, Hyundai Motor Group is investing a record 24.3 trillion won ($17.87 billion) this year, up more than 19 percent from 20.4 trillion won last year. This includes 11.5 trillion won in R&D, 12 trillion won in ongoing investments, and 800 billion won in strategic investments.
The group will complete Kia’s EV plant in Hwaseong, Gyeonggi Province, in the second half of this year and begin operations at Hyundai’s EV-dedicated plant in Ulsan in the first half of next year.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Hyundai Motor Group announced Tuesday that it will invest $26 billion over four years in the United States, an increase of $5 billion from the $21 billion announced in March. The investment will focus]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/26/news-p.v1.20250826.6007bb97c2a84b1ba9e2d9cb7c5aa48d_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Hyundai Motor/Kia)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11402920]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
