<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11396039</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>588184</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-18 14:43:53</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[KLEANNARA unveils humidifying mask]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-18 14:43:53</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400111</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.ad4dbad001e84af48445dcd26f3da4c9_P1.png' alt=' (KLEANNARA)'>
South Korean specialized paper and hygienic products manufacturer KLEANNARA Co. said on Monday that it released a “Watershot Humidifying Mask,” which helps maintain moist breathing even on airplanes or in strongly air-conditioned indoor environments.
KLEANNARA explained that it analyzed the mask’s moisture retention and user satisfaction in real-life environments via internal wear tests and found that its humidifying function lasts for up to 10 hours. It also incorporates antibacterial nonwoven fabric that provides 99.9 percent effectiveness against E. coli and Staphylococcus aureus.
The mask is additionally designed with a two-layer structure and a 3D ergonomic fit that conforms to facial contours, ensuring comfortable breathing even during extended wear. Its wide ear bands also help reduce pressure on the ears, allowing for comfortable use during sleep or long flights, the company said.
“This is a new product that helps keep our respiratory system healthy even in dry environments,” a company official said. “It can be used in a variety of everyday situations such as air travel, sleep, and air-conditioned indoor spaces.”
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[South Korean specialized paper and hygienic products manufacturer KLEANNARA Co. said on Monday that it released a “Watershot Humidifying Mask,” which helps maintain moist breathing even on airplanes o]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400111</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400111</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Biz]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/18/news-p.v1.20250818.ad4dbad001e84af48445dcd26f3da4c9_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (KLEANNARA)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11396039]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
