<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11405042</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>615399</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-28 14:22:41</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[BNK Asset Management named preferred bidder for Emart Tower]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-28 14:22:41</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400110</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.240cf29d1f71462e86a77694e1500688_P1.png' alt=' Emart Tower (GenstarMate)'>
BNK Asset Management has been selected as the preferred bidder to acquire Emart Tower, a prime office property near Seoul Station in central Seoul.
According to investment banking sources Wednesday, NH-Amundi Asset Management chose BNK Asset Management as the preferred buyer for the sale of Emart Tower. GenstarMate and Cushman & Wakefield Korea served as advisors for the transaction.
The bidding attracted interest from BNK Asset Management, NH REITs Management, Kiwoom Asset Management, and KB Real Estate Trust. BNK Asset Management, an affiliate of BNK Financial Group, has been actively seeking to secure prime office assets in Seoul this year with strong backing from its parent group.
Earlier this year, BNK Asset Management was designated the preferred bidder for the Hyundai Motor Securities Building in Yeouido but failed to complete the deal due to Hyundai Motor Securities exercising its preemptive purchase right.
For the Emart Tower auction, BNK Asset Management reportedly offered more than 360 billion won ($258.29 million), or in the mid-30 million won range per 3.3 square meters, securing the negotiation rights.
Completed in 2007, Emart Tower is a large office building located at 37 Sejong-daero 7-gil, Jung District, Seoul. The building spans six basement levels and 19 above-ground floors with a total floor area of about 34,173 square meters. Emart, a major Korean retailer, leases about 98 percent of the property, with the lease running until February 2033.
The tower is considered a highly favorable asset due to its proximity to new financial headquarters and ongoing development projects around Seoul Station.
NH-Amundi Asset Management, the seller, acquired the property from ARA Korea Asset Management in 2020 for 252 billion won.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[BNK Asset Management has been selected as the preferred bidder to acquire Emart Tower, a prime office property near Seoul Station in central Seoul. According to investment banking sources Wednesday, N]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400110</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400110</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Market]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/28/news-p.v1.20250828.240cf29d1f71462e86a77694e1500688_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ Emart Tower (GenstarMate)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11405042]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
