<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11384351</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>554073</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-04 06:59:13</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Trudeau to attend WKF in Korea in September]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-04 06:59:13</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.c9845c0edfb34d1cb8543b795847e9b6_P1.jpg' alt=' (MK DB)'>
Former Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau will attend as a speaker at the 26th World Knowledge Forum (WKF), the largest business forum in Asia hosted by South Korea’s Maekyung Media Group.
This will be his first visit to South Korea since stepping down from his post in March 2025 after leading Canada for the past decade.
WKF’s 2025 edition will take place from September 9th to 11th at the Jangchung Arena and Shilla Hotel in central Seoul under the theme “New Odyssey: Navigating the Great Transition.”
Trudeau is scheduled to deliver the opening keynote speech on September 9th, tentatively titled “Leadership, Solidarity, and Humanity’s New Challenges in the Era of Great Transition,” aligning with the forum’s main theme.
That afternoon, Trudeau will also take part in a special session at the Shilla Hotel commemorating the 32nd Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit.
In a one-on-one discussion, Trudeau will meet with Lee Cheol-woo, Governor of North Gyeongsang Province, where the upcoming APEC summit will be held. The session will focus on “The Global Order led by APEC,” exploring APEC’s significance and geopolitical implications.
Canada has been a founding member of APEC since 1989, and Trudeau actively participated in the annual summits during his time in office. At the 2024 APEC meeting in Lima, Peru, he highlighted the potential synergy between Korea and Canada, noting that the two countries would chair APEC and the G7 respectively in the following year.
Meanwhile, paid registration for the WKF (3.6 million won or $2,592) is open until August 28th, 2025. Inquiries should be directed to the forum’s secretariat.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Former Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau will attend as a speaker at the 26th World Knowledge Forum (WKF), the largest business forum in Asia hosted by South Korea’s Maekyung Media Group. This wi]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/04/news-p.v1.20250804.c9845c0edfb34d1cb8543b795847e9b6_P1.jpg]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (MK DB)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11384351]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
