<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<saltlux>
<article>
<action>T</action>
<wms_article>
<art_id>11399069</art_id>
<art_year>2025</art_year>
<art_no>596685</art_no>
<gubun>S</gubun>
<service_daytime>2025-08-21 10:45:37</service_daytime>
<title><![CDATA[Korean exports up 7.6% from Aug. 1 to 20, shipments to U.S. down]]></title>
<sub_title><![CDATA[]]></sub_title>
<media_code>01</media_code>
<writers><![CDATA[]]></writers>
<free_type>F</free_type>
<pub_div>W</pub_div>
<pub_date></pub_date>
<pub_edition></pub_edition>
<pub_section></pub_section>
<pub_page></pub_page>
<reg_dt>2025-08-21 10:45:37</reg_dt>
<mod_dt></mod_dt>
<art_org_class>MK400102</art_org_class>
</wms_article>
<wms_article_body>
<body><![CDATA[<img src='https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.4f0b331c6b6c4bb19e5e2ea3513cdaf4_P1.png' alt=' (Yonhap)'>
Korea’s exports rose in the first 20 days of August 2025 on the back of semiconductors and passenger cars, although shipments to the United States fell in a reflection of the growing impact of U.S. tariff policies.
According to the Korea Customs Service on Thursday, exports for August 1st to 20th totaled $35.5 billion, up 7.6 percent from a year earlier. Average daily exports came to $2.45 billion, with 14.5 working days during the period, the same number as 2024.
Monthly exports rose 5.9 percent in July from a year earlier, the second consecutive month of gains. While semiconductors and automobiles fueled the growth, some analysts said exporters also front-loaded shipments ahead of anticipated U.S. tariff measures.
By item, exports of semiconductors jumped 29.5 percent, passenger cars 21.7 percent, and ships 28.9 percent. In contrast, petroleum products fell 3.9 percent and wireless communication devices dropped 11.6 percent.
By country, exports to the United States slipped 2.7 percent, affected by steel and auto tariffs already in place. Exports increased to China (2.7 percent), the European Union (0.1 percent), Vietnam (9.6 percent), and Taiwan (59.1 percent).
Imports for the same period came to $34.7 billion, up 0.4 percent year-on-year. Imports of semiconductors (9.4 percent), gas (4.3 percent), and machinery (3.2 percent) rose, while those of crude oil (-8.8 percent) and petroleum products (-15.7 percent) fell.
With exports outpacing imports, the trade balance posted a surplus of $800 million.
]]></body>
</wms_article_body>
<wms_article_summary>
<summary><![CDATA[Korea’s exports rose in the first 20 days of August 2025 on the back of semiconductors and passenger cars, although shipments to the United States fell in a reflection of the growing impact of U.S. ta]]></summary>
</wms_article_summary>
<stock_codes>
</stock_codes>
<wms_article_keywords>
</wms_article_keywords>
<wms_code_classes>
<wms_code_class>
<code_id>MK400102</code_id>
<code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></code_nm>
<large_code_id>0</large_code_id>
<large_code_nm><![CDATA[뉴스]]></large_code_nm>
<middle_code_id>00308</middle_code_id>
<middle_code_nm><![CDATA[English]]></middle_code_nm>
<small_code_id>MK400102</small_code_id>
<small_code_nm><![CDATA[Economy]]></small_code_nm>
</wms_code_class>
</wms_code_classes>
<wms_article_images>
<wms_article_image>
<image_url><![CDATA[https://wimg.mk.co.kr/news/cms/202508/21/news-p.v1.20250821.4f0b331c6b6c4bb19e5e2ea3513cdaf4_P1.png]]></image_url>
<image_caption><![CDATA[ (Yonhap)]]></image_caption>
</wms_article_image>
</wms_article_images>
<article_url><![CDATA[https://www.mk.co.kr/article/11399069]]></article_url>
</article>
</saltlux>
